[{"question":"<p>Transactions are recorded or posted to the ledger in line with<\/p>","options":["Accounting Concept","Source document","Double Entry Principle","Data collection"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Show how the following transaction will be recorded applying the double entry principle:<br \/>\r\nRent \u20a650,000 was paid by Mr. Roi to his landlord on 1st July, 20 &times; 7 by cheque.<\/p>","options":["Dr Rent A\/c; Dr Bank A\/c","Dr Bank A\/c; Cr Rent A\/c","Dr Rent A\/c; Cr Bank A\/c","Dr Rent A\/c; Cr Mr. Roi"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>A statement in a double entry system in which are recorded all the transactions of one specific class, which takes place during the period is called<\/p>","options":["Double entry system","Ledger","Cash Book","Petty Cash Book"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The advantage of double entry is that<\/p>","options":["it is easy to prepare the final account","it increase assets","has cash and bank column","It disburses cash"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Accounts can be classified into<\/p>","options":["cash and credit transactions","cash and credit accounts","personal and private account","personal and impersonal account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Goods were purchased for resale on credit costing \u20a6150,000 on 30th September 20X8 from Tosanwumi International. The entry to record these transaction is debit<\/p>","options":["Tosanwumi International, credit purchase Account","Purchase Account \u20a6150,000, credit Tosanwumi International Account \u20a6150,000","Credit Account \u20a6150,000, Credit Tosanwumi International \u20a6150,000","Tosanwumi International \u20a6150,000, credit credit Account \u20a6150,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>If only wages is shown on the trial balance, it should be charged to the<\/p>","options":["profit and loss account","trading account","balance sheet","wages account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What is the Gross Profit on percentage of sale?<\/p>","options":["2.7%","0.27%","27.0%","29.8%"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Calculate the net profit on percentage of expenses.<\/p>","options":["60%","25%","13%","65.7%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Mr Ojo gives you the following information on 31st July 2017<br \/>\r\nOpening Stock &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 7,000<br \/>\r\nClosing Stock &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 12,000<br \/>\r\nPurchases &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 60,000<br \/>\r\nExpenses &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 4,500<br \/>\r\nUniform margin of 33 \\(\\frac{1}{3}\\) %<br \/>\r\nYou are required to calculate the sales<\/p>","options":["#55,000","#82,500","#27,500","#50,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The company&#39;s paid-up capital is<\/p>","options":["#70,000","\u20a680,000","\u20a6220,000","\u20a6120,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The Unissued capital of the company is<\/p>","options":["\u20a6310,000","\u20a6200,000","\u20a6210,000","\u20a6100,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Given:<br \/>\r\nOrdinary share dividend \u20a6100,000, General reserve \u20a64,100, Net profit b\/d \u20a627,370, corporation tax \u20a62,500, Profit and loss \u20a628,200, Interim ordinary dividend \u20a64,050, Goodwill 20,50 provide for preference Dividend \u20a62100 and Final ordinary Dividend of 5% and also write off Goodwill at \u20a61500.<br \/>\r\nThe retained profit in the Appropriation account is<\/p>","options":["\u20a655,570","\u20a636,320","\u20a650,000","\u20a630,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Retained profits is an example of<\/p>","options":["Revenue reserve","Capital reserves","General reserves","Loan capital"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Ojo&#39;s share of profit is<\/p>","options":["2475","1322.5","4950","6000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Sam&#39;s share of profit is<\/p>","options":["7000","4921","3000","991.8"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The rate of interest on capital for Ade is<\/p>","options":["250","200","300","400"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Calculate the subscriptions in the Income and expenditure account<\/p>","options":["8400","7400","6400","7200"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The figure \u20a61000 represent what in the balance sheet.<\/p>","options":["Assets","Liability","capital","Subscription"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What is the opening cash balance<\/p>","options":["\u20a620,600","\u20a68,050","\u20a63,650","\u20a68,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Which of these will not appear in the preparation of control account.<br \/>\r\nI. Bad debts<br \/>\r\nII. Discounts<br \/>\r\nIII. Returns<br \/>\r\nIV. Provision for bad debts<\/p>","options":["I only","II and III","I and III only","IV only"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Use the following Information to answer this question.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table cellpadding=\"4\" cellspacing=\"0\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td><br \/>\r\n\t\t\tStock of finished goods: Jan 1st<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tDec 31st<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tStock of Raw materials: Jan 1st<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tDec 31st<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tPurchase of Raw Materials<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tManufacturing Wages<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tDepreciation: Factory equipment<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tDirect expenses<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tFactory Fuel<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tCarriage inwards on Raw Materials<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t50,640<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t71,380<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t32,160<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t29,640<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t145,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t52,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t16,500<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t12,500<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t7,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t7,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>Cost of raw materials consumed is<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["\u20a653,000","\u20a6150,000","\u20a6152,120","\u20a6148,120"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Use the following Information to answer this question.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table cellpadding=\"4\" cellspacing=\"0\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td><br \/>\r\n\t\t\tStock of finished goods: Jan 1st<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tDec 31st<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tStock of Raw materials: Jan 1st<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tDec 31st<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tPurchase of Raw Materials<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tManufacturing Wages<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tDepreciation: Factory equipment<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tDirect expenses<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tFactory Fuel<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tCarriage inwards on Raw Materials<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t50,640<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t71,380<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t32,160<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t29,640<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t145,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t52,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t16,500<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t12,500<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t7,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t7,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>","options":["220,480","213,480","200,480","190,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>A fall or decrease in the economic service potential of an asset as a result of wear, tear and obsolescence is referred to as<\/p>","options":["Estimate","Depreciation","Asset","Useful Life"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The cost of a machine is \u20a610,000. The residual value is \u20a64,000. It is expected to last for 4 years. Using the straight line method, what is the amount of depreciation charged per annum?<\/p>","options":["6000","1000","1500","2500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Recurrent expenditure is<\/p>","options":["\u20a6345,000","\u20a63,245,000","\u20a6421,000","\u20a64,245,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Capital expenditure is<\/p>","options":["\u20a6345,000","\u20a63,245,000","\u20a6421,000","\u20a64,245,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Goods can be charged to branches using any of these pricing methods except<\/p>","options":["cost price","cost plus percentage","selling price","selling plus percentage"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Abelawo ltd operates a retail branch at Aba. All purchases are made by the head office in Onitsha and goods are charged to the branch at cost plus 50%. During the year ended. Goods sent to branch at invoiced price is \u20a630,870, cash sales \u20a613,020 and Bad debt amounted to 129. From the following, what is the profit?<\/p>","options":["20,580","10,290","7980","30,870"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The cost of goods for department B is<\/p>","options":["4,120","3400","3000","2800"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The net profit for departmental A is<\/p>","options":["1880","1600","880","425"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Every economic unit, regardless of its legal form of existence, is treated as a separate entity from parties having economic interest is<\/p>","options":["realisation concept","entity concept","going concern concept","matching concept"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The two recognised accounting bases are<\/p>","options":["cash and credit","personal and impersonal","Accrual and Cash","Drawings and Private"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Given:<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table cellpadding=\"4\" cellspacing=\"0\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td><br \/>\r\n\t\t\tAdditional capital<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tCapital<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tClosing capital<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tNet profit<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t4000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t8000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t12000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t1500<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>The drawings for the period stand at<\/p>","options":["1500","3000","12,000","10,500"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The importance of bank statement is all except<\/p>","options":["verifies the accuracy of balances of cash book and cheque book","helps to detect and rectify any error","helps to debit an account","helps to update the cash book"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Accounting standards are issued at the International level by the<\/p>","options":["Standards Advisory Council","International Accounting Standards Board","Nigerian Accounting Standards Board","Standing Interpretations Committee"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The method of stock valuation in which the issue price is obtained by dividing the value of stock in hand by unit of stock in hand is<\/p>","options":["FIFO","LIFO","SAP","WAP"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>One of these is not a similarity between Joint Venture and Partnership.<\/p>","options":["AIM is profit making","It is for a specific venture","Involves two people","have rights and duties"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Majority of commercial transactions are termed credit transactions, which means<\/p>","options":["The buyers pay immediately for goods bought","Settlement is deferred to a future date","No account will be opened","Item of expenditure increases"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Bought motor vehicle \u20a660 paying by cheque. The effect of the transaction will be<\/p>","options":["Increase in assets of motor vehicle account","Decrease in assets of motor vehicle account","Increase in assets of bank account","Increase in liabilities of bank account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>A proprietor withdraws cash from the business for private use, he<\/p>","options":["credits cash account and debits bank account","credits cash account and debits drawing A\/C","debits cash account and credits drawings account","debits bank account and credits drawings account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The rules of double entry states that<\/p>","options":["for every debit entry, there must be a corresponding debit entry","for every credit entry, there must be a corresponding credit entry","all transactions must be recorded in two accounts, one account is debited and another is credited","all transaction must be credited"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The difference between double entry and single entry is<\/p>","options":["double entry is based on the dual concept while single entry is not based on dual concept","double entry is an account while single entry is not an account","double entry keeps personal account while single does not","double entry is useful for business enterprise while single entry is not"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>A rent of \u20a650,000 was paid by samson to his landlady by cheque. The double entry in Samson&#39;s book is<\/p>","options":["Debit rent account, Credit bank account","Debit Rent account, Credit Samson's account","Debit Bank account, Credit Rent account","Debit Samson's account, Credit Rent account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The purpose of profit and loss account is to ascertain<\/p>","options":["Gross profit","Capital","Expenses","Net profit"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Discount received is charge to<\/p>","options":["current account","profit and loss","trading account","balance sheet"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What was the cost of goods sold?<\/p>","options":["\u20a625,000","\u20a635,000","\u20a650,000","\u20a675,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What was the gross profit?<\/p>","options":["\u20a635,000","\u20a675,000","\u20a650,000","\u20a625,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>An ordinary share of \u20a6100 was issued at \u20a680. The share was issued at<\/p>","options":["premium","par","discount","loss"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Shares that are offered to existing shareholders at a price is called<\/p>","options":["par","premium","right issue","bonus issue"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Use the following information to answer this question<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table cellpadding=\"4\" cellspacing=\"0\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Year<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>1991<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t1992<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t1993<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t1994<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>14,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t24,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t10,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t16,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>It has been decided to value goodwill at 2 years purchase of average profit for the past 4 years. The value of goodwill is<\/p>","options":["32,000","16000","30000","64,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Where there is no agreement made by the partners, the following provisions takes place except<\/p>","options":["No salary for partners acting in the business","There is interest on capital","No interest to be charged on drawings","Profit and loss are to be shared equally"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In the absence of partnership agreement, a loan by a partner attracts interest at<\/p>","options":["20%","5%","10%","15%"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In a non-profit making organisation, the excess of Assets over liabilities equals<\/p>","options":["capital","capital employed","capital owned","accumulated funds"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The similarities between Receipts and payments and income and expenditure account is<\/p>","options":["Both accounts follows the principle of double entry","They are summaries of financial statements","Both include capital items","Both are prepared by non-profit making concern"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Given:<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table cellpadding=\"4\" cellspacing=\"0\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td><br \/>\r\n\t\t\tEquipment<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tMotor Vehicle<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tLoan<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tCreditors<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tSub in advance<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tSub in arrears<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t10,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t15,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t4,500<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t3,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t150<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t3500<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>What is the accumulated fund?<\/p>","options":["\u20a614,150","\u20a620,850","\u20a621,850","\u20a614,200"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Use the information to answer this question<br \/>\r\n<br \/>\r\nPayment to creditors \u20a612,250<br \/>\r\nCreditors at start \u20a6550<br \/>\r\nCreditors at end \u20a6830<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>What us the amount of purchase<\/p>","options":["\u20a611,970","\u20a611,000","\u20a61,250","\u20a612,053"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Use the information to answer this question<br \/>\r\n<br \/>\r\nPayment to creditors \u20a612,250<br \/>\r\nCreditors at start \u20a6550<br \/>\r\nCreditors at end \u20a6830<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>What is the creditors amount in the balance sheet?<\/p>","options":["\u20a6550","\u20a612,250","\u20a612,530","\u20a6830"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In the preparation of statement of profit, if the opening capital is greater than closing capital, there will be<\/p>","options":["profit","capital","loss","cash"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The manufacturing account is prepared to ascertain<\/p>","options":["cost of goods sold","cost of production","Gross profit","Finished goods"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Which of the following is not charged to manufacturing account?<\/p>","options":["Direct expenses","Factory wages","Distribution expenses","Raw materials"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Which of the following cannot depreciate?<\/p>","options":["plant and machinery","motor van","premises","land"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>A machine cost \u20a612,500 it will be kept for 4 years and then sold at a scrap value of \u20a65,120. Using the diminishing balance method, what is the amount of depreciation for second year?<\/p>","options":["\u20a65,120","\u20a66,400","\u20a68,000","\u20a612,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>An officer that is charged with the responsibility of carrying out investigations on the book of accounts to show the true and fair view is<\/p>","options":["Ministry of Finance","Accountant General","Revenue office","Auditor General"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The instrument isued by the Minister who authorized an officer to incure expenditure is a\/an<\/p>","options":["warrant","budget","imprest","consolidated fund"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>One of the objective of maintaining the account of a branch at the head office is to<\/p>","options":["to access the performance of the branches","check the excesses of customers","record charges in shareholdings","record charges in liabilities"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>A company goods sent to branch at invoiced price is \u20a630,870 at cost plus 25%. The mark-up is<\/p>","options":["\u20a620,000","\u20a66,000","\u20a66,174","\u20a610,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The objective of departmentalization is to<\/p>","options":["ensure that departmental managers are adequately monitored","record transactions for each department for better documentation","tackle any recording problem as a result of expansion","evaluate the profit of different departments"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Discount received is apportioned to each department on the basis of<\/p>","options":["Floor area","Turnover","Purchases","Horse power"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Given:<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table cellpadding=\"4\" cellspacing=\"0\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td><br \/>\r\n\t\t\tFixed assets<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tLiabilities<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tCurrent assets<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t55,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t20,000<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t13,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>What is the capital?<\/p>","options":["\u20a688,000","\u20a648,000","\u20a662,000","\u20a655,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>One of the limitations of accounting is that<\/p>","options":["it ascertain financial position","it prevent fraud","transactions are recorded in monetary terms","it monitor the progress of the enterprise"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Capital at start was \u20a6250,000, while capital at the end of the year was \u20a6400,000. Drawings during the year amounted to \u20a615,000. What is the profit?<\/p>","options":["\u20a6165,000","\u20a6635,000","\u20a6600,000","\u20a6156,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In the preparation of account, the owners of the business and the business concerned are treated as:<\/p>","options":["partners","joint venture","the same person","separate legal entities"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>From the following, determine the value of closing stock using:<br \/>\r\nFeb 1 purchased 200 units @ \u20a62.00 each<br \/>\r\nFeb 3 purchased 100 units @ \u20a61.00 each<br \/>\r\nFeb 4 issued 120 units @ \u20a65.00 each<br \/>\r\nFeb 5 purchased 50 units @ \u20a63.00 each<br \/>\r\nFeb 6 issued 100 units @ \u20a64.00 each<\/p>","options":["330","420","230","320"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>A sent B a cheque for \u20a62000 to provide him with friends. They agreed to share profits in ratio 3 : 2 and settlement is by cheque.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table cellpadding=\"4\" cellspacing=\"0\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td><br \/>\r\n\t\t\t<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tSales<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tAdvert<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tWages<br \/>\r\n\t\t\tPurchases<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>A<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t\u20a6<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t3200<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t327<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t85<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t1600<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>B<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t\u20a6<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t2100<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t463<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t70<br \/>\r\n\t\t\t1100<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>The profit and loss in joint venture with B account in the ledger of A.<\/p>","options":["\u20a61000","\u20a6900","\u20a6993","\u20a6883"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What is the amount of capital employed?<\/p>","options":["\u20a67000","\u20a610000","\u20a622000","\u20a615000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Advertising expenses incurred on a product in a business organization should be charged to<\/p>","options":["Sales department","Production department","Purchase department","Administration department"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<table border=\"1\" cellpadding=\"1\" cellspacing=\"1\" style=\"width:500px\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; N<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;N<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Capital&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 39,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;Land&nbsp; 20,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Long Term Loan&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 15, 000&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Building 30,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Creditors&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;9,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Stock&nbsp; 40,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Debtors&nbsp; 6,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Accrued wages&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;5,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Cash&nbsp; 8, 000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;68,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp; &nbsp;68,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Use the information above to answer the question<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;: The acid test ratio in the company is___________<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["1:1","2:3","1:2","3:2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>When goods are sent to branch at cost plus mark up, it means that the branch should sell at_____________<\/p>","options":["Price above or below the stipulated price","Any price but not below the transfer price","Cost price","A price that is equal to the mark up"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The office responsible for ascertaining whether all public expenditures and appropriations are in line with approved guidelines is the________<\/p>","options":["Accountant general","Finance minister","Auditor general","Permanent secretory."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Use the information below to answer question<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<br \/>\r\nTrading account for the year ended 31st December 2009<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table border=\"1\" cellpadding=\"1\" cellspacing=\"1\" style=\"width:500px\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Opening Stock&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;32,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Sales&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 48,000&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Purchases&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;40,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Less Return&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;2,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Carriage inwards&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;1,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<strong> 41,000<\/strong><\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Less Return&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 2,000&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;39,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Cost of goods available&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;??<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Less closing stock&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <strong>&nbsp; 9,000<\/strong><\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Cost of goods sold&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; ??<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["#20,500","#23,000","#28,000","#27,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Use the information below to answer question<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<br \/>\r\nTrading account for the year ended 31st December 2009<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table border=\"1\" cellpadding=\"1\" cellspacing=\"1\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Opening Stock&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;32,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Sales&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 48,000&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Purchases&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;40,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Less Return&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;2,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Carriage inwards&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;1,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<strong> 41,000<\/strong><\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Less Return&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 2,000&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;39,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Cost of goods available&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;??<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Less closing stock&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <strong>&nbsp; 9,000<\/strong><\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Cost of goods sold&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; ??<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Calculate the cost of goods sold<\/p>","options":["#61,000","#62,000","#58,000","#57,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The amount called in respect of a share but not paid before or on the date fixed for payment is referred to as:<\/p>","options":["Call in advance","call in arrears","forfeiture","shares"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>When goodwill is not retained in the business, the entries in the new partners books will be to debit______________<\/p>","options":["Goodwill account and credit partners capital account","Cash account and credit goodwill account","Goodwill account and credit cash account","Partners capital account and credit goodwill account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Use the information below to answer the question<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table border=\"1\" cellpadding=\"1\" cellspacing=\"1\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td><strong>Liabilities&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;\u20a6<\/strong><\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td><strong>Assets&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;\u20a6<\/strong><\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Capital&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 40,000&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Furnishing&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;10,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Ceiling Fan&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;1,500<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Cash in Hand&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;28,500<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 40,000<\/strong><\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<strong>40,000<\/strong><\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>If at 31\/1\/95 the following information was ascertained<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (i). rent for shop #12,000 paid for the year<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (ii). Total purchases #15,000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (iii). Total sales #8,200<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (iv). Stock of goods left #10,000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (v). paid sales boy #500<\/p>","options":["#40,000","#41,500","#41,700","48,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>In the head office ledger, the value of goods sent to the branch are____________<\/p>","options":["Debited to the branch current account","Debited to the head office current account","Credited to the head office current account","Credited to the branch current account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>If the purchase price exceeds the net assets of a company, the excess amount is debited to________________<\/p>","options":["Cash account","purchase account","goodwill account","sales account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Gross profit in the branch adjustment account is transferred to the branch____________<\/p>","options":["Income and expenditure account","profit and loss account","receipt and payment account","trading account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Ade, Tony, Rose share profit and losses in the ratio of 3 : 2 : 1 respectively. Ade retires and the remaining partners decide to take Ade&rsquo;s share in the existing ratio. What is the new ratio?<\/p>","options":["1 : 1","3 : 6","2 : 1","2 : 6"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Calls in advance are treated in the balance sheet as_______<\/p>","options":["Current asset","Fixed asset","Current liability","Fixed liability"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Why are adjustments in the profit and loss account necessary?<\/p>","options":["To cover some expenses of the following year","To show the provisions made during the year","To show the total expenses paid and income received during the year","To ascertain the actual expenses incurred and income earned during the year"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Which of the following is not a type of branch?<\/p>","options":["Dependent branch","foreign branch","independent branch","single branch"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>In reconciling the branch and head office accounts, remittance in transit in the branch books is treated as a_____________<\/p>","options":["Debit entry","Contra entry","Credit entry","Reversal entry"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Profit or loss in a partnership is usually arrived at after deducting from gross profit all expenses including____________<\/p>","options":["Partners salaries","Interest on capital","Interest on loans","Partners drawings"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Use the information below to answer the question<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table border=\"1\" cellpadding=\"1\" cellspacing=\"1\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td><strong>Liabilities&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;\u20a6<\/strong><\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td><strong>Assets&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;\u20a6<\/strong><\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Capital&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 40,000&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Furnishing&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;10,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Ceiling Fan&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;1,500<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Cash in Hand&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;28,500<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 40,000<\/strong><\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<strong>40,000<\/strong><\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>If at 31\/1\/95 the following information was ascertained;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (i). rent for shop #12,000 paid for the year<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (ii). Total purchases #15,000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (iii). Total sales #8,200<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (iv). Stock of goods left #10,000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (v). paid sales boy #500<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>If at 31\/1\/95 the following information was ascertained;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (i). rent for shop #12,000 paid for the year<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (ii). Total purchases #15,000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (iii). Total sales #8,200<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (iv). Stock of goods left #10,000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; (v). paid sales boy #500<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; What is the balance on its cash account as at 31\/1\/95<\/p>","options":["#22,800","#9,200","#800","#21,200"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The amount paid by the new partner on admission as a compensation for the reputation built up by old partners is a<\/p>","options":["Bonus","Good will","Premium","Commission"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<table border=\"1\" cellpadding=\"1\" cellspacing=\"1\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<s>N<\/s><\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Stock at branch 1st January at cost&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>400<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Goods sent to branch at cost<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;8000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Returns to head office<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 340&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Cash sales<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>9160<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Stock at branch 31st December at cost<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>720<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Use the information below to answer the question.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; Adex Ltd. Issues stock to its retail branches at cost price. The following particulars relate to Ede branch.<\/p>","options":["#1870","#1530","#1640","#1820"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Which of the following methods of invoicing goods to branches facilitate easy checks on the activities of branches?<\/p>","options":["Selling price","Fixed percentage on cost","Cost price","Invoice price"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>When goods are sent to branch at cost plus mark up, it means that the branch should sell at_____________<\/p>","options":["Price above or below the stipulated price","Any price but not below the transfer price","Cost price","A price that is equal to the mark up"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>In departmental accounting, which is not a transfer pricing_________<\/p>","options":["cost based transfer price","market based transfer pricing","Dual pricing system","peak pricing"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>What act generally includes completing unfinished partnership business, collecting and paying debts, collecting partnership assets to be turned into cash and taking inventory?<\/p>","options":["Formation","dissolution","winding up","termination"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Using the following:<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; Balance as par overdraft of the cashbook is \u20a64000 ,uncredited cheque is \u20a62300, bank charges \u20a6300, unpresented cheque \u20a65000.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; what is the adjusted cashbook balance?<\/p>","options":["4000","300","4300","5000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Branch stock adjustment account is prepared at?<\/p>","options":["Cost price","new price","invoice price","normal price"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>A partnership deed is used to____________<\/p>","options":["Promote mutual understanding","Enhance mistrust","Encourage discrepancy","Control funds"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The cost price method is applicable when_____<\/p>","options":["Goods are sold at specific prices","goods are perishable","goods attract different gross profit percentage","to disclose gross profit or loss"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<table border=\"1\" cellpadding=\"1\" cellspacing=\"1\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<s>N<\/s><\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Stock at branch 1st January at cost&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>400<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Goods sent to branch at cost<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>8000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Returns to head office<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>340<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Cash sales<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>9160<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Stock at branch 31st December at cost<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>720<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Use the information below to answer the question.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; Adex Ltd. Issues stock to its retail branches at cost price.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;Calculate the cost of goods credited to the head office trading account<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["#7200","#7460","#7500","#7660"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>In dealing with incomplete record, fixed assets are posted to___________-<\/p>","options":["Profit and loss account as brought forward figure","Closing balance sheet as carried forward figure","Closing balance sheet as brought forward figure","Profit and loss as carried forward figure"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Tea and Cup are into a partnership business. Interests on drawings made by partners are at 10% per annum. Tea&rsquo;s capital is \u20a670000 and current balance is \u20a650000. He withdrew the following amounts during the year : 3000 on 31st January ,2000 on 31st March, 4000 on 1st July, 1500 on the 30th September, 2500 on 1st November. Cup&rsquo;s capital is \u20a6100000 and current balance is \u20a640000. He made no drawings during the period. What is the interest on the drawings of Tea?<\/p>","options":["\u20a6705","\u20a6500","\u20a61000","\u20a610000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Which of the following should not be adjusted for in the profit and loss account?<\/p>","options":["Accruals","inventory","subscription","depreciation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Use the information below to answer the question .<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table border=\"1\" cellpadding=\"1\" cellspacing=\"1\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Total<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>P<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Q<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Total<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>P<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Q<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Stock<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>3,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>2,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>1,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Sales<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>10,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>6,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>4,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Purchase<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>4,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>2,500<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>1,500<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>Closing Stock<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp; 2,000<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>1,500<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp; &nbsp;500<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Goods worth #300 was transferred from department Q to P. Similarly, P&rsquo;s total expenses for the period was #200.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; Department P&rsquo;s net profit was<\/p>","options":["#2,500","#2,800","#3,000","#5,200"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>In the absence of a partnership deed, the act stipulates that____________<\/p>","options":["An amount should be fixed as salaries for partners","Profits and losses should not be shared equally","Interest on partner\u2019s loan should be 25%","Interest should not be allowed on partners drawings"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>A partnership&rsquo;s internal regulation are set out by________---<\/p>","options":["A constitution","A law","A deed","An article"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Sule and Ahmed are in partnership sharing profit and losses equally. If Khadija is admitted as a new partner to take 1\/5 th as her share. What is the new profit or loss sharing?<\/p>","options":["Sule1\/3, Ahmed1\/3, Khadija 1\/3","Sule1\/3, Ahmed1\/3, Khadija 1\/3","Sule1\/5, Ahmed1\/5, Khadija3\/5","Sule2\/5, Ahmed1\/5, Khadija2\/5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Transfers from the head office to branches are best carried out at__________<\/p>","options":["Cost price","Cost plus mark up","Selling price","Market price"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Which of the following is a common cause of a discrepancy between head office and branch trial office________<\/p>","options":["Stock and repayment","Creditors and cash in transit","Stock and cash in transit","Debtors and cash in transit"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Departmentalization of accounts is useful because it shows the____________<\/p>","options":["Over all performance of a division","Cost per unit of a profit","Price per unit of a product","Over all performance of a firm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Why should a new partner contribute towards goodwill on his admission?<\/p>","options":["It is a norm","to ensure new partner also have a stake in the business","the firm into which he is entering already has some goodwill in the market","to purchase the business"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The rent expense for Trendy store is \u20a63500. Trendy store has three departments; jewelry, hair dressing, and clothing. The floor spaces occupied by the departments are 3:2:5 respectively. What is the rent allocated to clothing department?<\/p>","options":["\u20a6700","\u20a61050","\u20a61750","\u20a63500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Cost of rent as an expense can be apportioned to all department on the basis of:<\/p>","options":["No of employees","stock value","space occupied","wages"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Use the information to answer the questions<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; Rakiya and joy are in a partnership and agreed that 5% interest per annum is to be charged on drawings. The drawing made by both partners in one year were:<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; Rakiya, #200 on March 31 and #300 on September 30.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; Joy, #100 on April 1 and #240 on July 1.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; The interest on Joy&rsquo;s drawing is___________<\/p>","options":["#511.25 debit","#500.00 credit","#349.75 debit","#340.00 credit"],"answerIndex":"0","examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Which of the following is a conversion cost?<\/p>","options":["Factory overhead","purchases","material cost","wages"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Tea and Cup are into a partnership business. Interests on drawings made by partners are at 10% per annum. Tea&rsquo;s capital is \u20a670000 and current balance is \u20a650000. He withdrew the following amounts during the year : 3000 on 31st January , 2000 on 31st March, 4000 on 1st July, 1500 on the 30th September, 2500 on 1st November. Cup&rsquo;s capital is \u20a6100000 and current balance is \u20a640000. He made no drawings during the period. what is the closing balance in Tea&rsquo;s current account<\/p>","options":["36,925Cr","40,000Cr","50,000Dr","36,295Dr"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>To account for expenses paid by head office on behalf of the branch, the branch should___________<\/p>","options":["Debit profit and loss account and credit head office account","Debit head office account and credit cash","Credit cash and debit profit and loss account","Credit profit and loss account and debit head office account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Use the information below to answer the question.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; Calculate the balance in the bank statement.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<table border=\"1\" cellpadding=\"1\" cellspacing=\"1\">\r\n\t<tbody>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>&nbsp;<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\u20a6<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Balance as per cashbook<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>13560<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Unpresented cheques<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>5120<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Dividend received<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>2000<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Uncredited cheque<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>2300<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Bank charges<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>280<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Standing order<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>600<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t\t<tr>\r\n\t\t\t<td>\r\n\t\t\t<p>Balance as per bank statement<\/p>\r\n\t\t\t<\/td>\r\n\t\t\t<td>?<\/td>\r\n\t\t<\/tr>\r\n\t<\/tbody>\r\n<\/table>","options":["\u20a610,740","\u20a611,860","\u20a616,380","\u20a617,500"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Which of the following is not an inventory costing method?<\/p>","options":["FIFO","LIFO","Average cost method","LILA"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The major source of document which enables employer to calculate&nbsp; the employee wages&nbsp; is the?<\/p>","options":["norminal roll of employees","records of number of hours worked","effort of the employee","Record of independence per employee"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The total credit sales for a period can be extracted from the?<\/p>","options":["Cash book","Sales day book","Petty cash book","Returns inwards"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>If the scrap value is presently N15,000, what will be the yearly depreciation using the straight line method?<\/p>","options":["N4,000","N7,000","N11,000","N24,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Mrs. Okoro who lives in the riverine community of Rivers State makes her living through crabbing and fishing. This type of occupation is?&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["commercial","manufacturing","service","Extractive"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The yearly depreciation using the straight line method would be<\/p>","options":["N8,800","N6,500","N5,200","N4,400"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The accounting entries used to record a cheque issued by a business is to?<\/p>","options":["debit cash book and credit drawer","credit cash book and debit drawer","debit cash book and credit suspense account","credit cash book and debit suspense account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>In government accounting , the method used which records on the basis of financial entity with self balancing books instead of entity of propietorship is?<\/p>","options":["virement","fund accounting","consolidated fund","financial regulation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>which of the following&nbsp; affects the accuracy and authenticity of trial balance?&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["error of ommission","error of commission","error of transposition","error of original entry"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The major advantages of an imprest system is that it ?<\/p>","options":["ensures a proper accountability for every expenditure","trains the young accountants in the preparation for greater responsibility","relieves the chief cashier of the numerous petty cash payments","serves as an analysis column for every expenses"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The value of the current assets will be?<\/p>","options":["N10,361","N10,651","N17,396","N17,848"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Determine the current liabilities.<\/p>","options":["N8,553","N8,263","N7,940","N1,228"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The excess of sales over cost of goods sold is?<\/p>","options":["gross sales","gross profit","net profit","net sales"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The control account is used in facilitating?<\/p>","options":["the various location of errors in the various accounts","up to date bank transactions","the payment of debts and liabilities of the firm","assets distribution with respect to income"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The main objective of accounting report is to provide information about?<\/p>","options":["the efficacy of assets","a company's shareholding","company's economic resources","an entity's management"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>from the data above, compute the prime cost.&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["N6,500","N\t8,500","N6,000","N7,500"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>calculate the sales ledger balance<\/p>","options":["N13,000","N10,000","N\t6,000","N3,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>what is the purchase ledger balance?<\/p>","options":["N29,000","N24,000","N4,000","N23,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>lubricating oil and spare parts of machines are example of?<\/p>","options":["indirect expense","direct expense","indirect material","direct material"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>for an incomplete record to provide necessary information, it must be converted to?<\/p>","options":["double entry","single entry","complete records","statement of affairs"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The main difference between the ordinary and preference shareholders is that?<\/p>","options":["the former have voting rights while the latter do not","in the case of winding up, the former are paid first before the latter","the latter are not members of the company while the former are","the former receives dividends while the latter do not"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>A club received rent N10,000 and donation of N30,000. it paid N6,000 for entertainment and is still owing N16,000 . The balance of the receipts and payments account is?<\/p>","options":["N14,000","N24,000","N8,000","N42,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The N6,000 subscription received is?<\/p>","options":["capital","fixed asset","current liability","current asset"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>what is the subscription to be charged to income and expenditure account?<\/p>","options":["N20,000","N30,000","N34,000","N36,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>A cash book had a opening balance of N15,200, closing balance of N18,400 and total cash received during the period of N36,000. What was the amount of cash paid out during the same period?<\/p>","options":["N29,200","N17,800","N32,800","N19,600"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The current growth in the volume of trading and financial dealings in nigerian is helped by?<\/p>","options":["credit as a factor in business","payments for goods in cash","increased financial activities","government intervention"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>when a bill is negotiated to a bank , it is said to be?<\/p>","options":["accepted","discounted","surrendered","cashed"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Bala ltd acquired the business of bello ltd and caused the separate existence of the latter company to terminate.&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["conversion","dissolution","merger","absorption"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>In order to make the cash book balance equal to the bank statement, it is usually to add?<\/p>","options":["uncredited cheques","direct payments by bank","bank charged","unpresented cheques"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The company&#39;s earnings yield is?<\/p>","options":["N20.00%","N25.00%","N31.33%","N39.17%"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>what will be the price earnings ratio of the company?<\/p>","options":["N3.91","N3.19","N2.95","N2.55"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The partnership deed normally specifies?<\/p>","options":["how profits or losses are to be shared","the capital to be contributed annually","how salaries are paid to employees","the profit that should be earned annually"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The accumulated fund of a non-trading concern can equally be referred to as?<\/p>","options":["members equity","share capital","general fund","surplus fund"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>calculate the net profit.&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["N12,500","N10,000","N8,000","N7,500"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>what is the gross profit margin?<\/p>","options":["100%","50%","40%","30%"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>Kakaku limited with three departments has a total of N7,200,000 as net debtors for the year ended 31\/12\/2106. The company&#39;s policy, provides for 15%bad debt annually. Which of the following represents the total balance of debtors before adjustment?<\/p>","options":["N6,120,000","N8,280,000","N6,120,300","N8,820,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The basic role of accounting is to?<\/p>","options":["detect fraud","attest to financial statements","measure performance","protect shareholders"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>The fixed amount of money given to a petty cashier at the beginning of a period is called?<\/p>","options":["Imprest","float","cash advance","cash"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"<p>A provision for bad debt account had N33,800 at the beginning of the year and N4,220 at the close of the year. If bad debts are calculated at the rate of 1\/20% of annual credit sales, what was the credit sales for the period?<\/p>","options":["N210,000","N844,400","N840,000","N500,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2018"},{"question":"Which of these accounts is dissolution expenses credited?","options":["partners capital account","revaluation account","partners current account","Realization account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Capital for a profit making organization is generated through","options":["Subscription","shares","donation","gift"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"The account where the profit are distributed to the partner in their profit sharing ratio in partnership","options":["trading account","appropriation account","balance sheet","profit and loss account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"In manufacturing account, depreciation of office machine is charged to","options":["trading account","appropriation account","balance street","profit and loss account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Given: <br>\r\nI. Cash refunds <br>\r\nII. Debit note issued <br>\r\nIII. Dishonored cheque <br>\r\nIV. Purchases<br>\r\nThe item on the credit side of purchases ledger control account includes","options":["I,II and III only","I and II only","III and IV only","I, III and IV only"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"You add the following when starting with the balance as per cash book when preparing the bank reconciliation statement except","options":["Unpresented","Dividend","Uncredited cheque","credit transfer"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c}     &  \\text{N}  \\\\ \\hline \\text{Debtors opening} & 4000 \\\\ \\hline  \\text{Debtors closing} & 1500   \\\\ \\hline  \\text{Cash received from debtors} & 8500 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Bad debts written off}  & 350 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Discount allowed} & 500 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Discount received} & 1000<br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf the gross profit is N5 000, what is the net profit?","options":["\u20a64,350","\u20a66,000","\u20a65,150","\u20a64,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Which fund is used to meet unforeseen or urgent expenditure","options":["General reserve fund","Consolidated Reserve Fund","contingencies fund","special fund"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"In the period of rising prices, which method of stock valuation is most appropriate?","options":["Last in First Out","weighted average","First in First Out","Simple average"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Which of these is the subsidiary book for return inwards?","options":["Sales day book","Sales return journal","Purchases day journal","Cash book"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"A double entry for a transaction that offsets one amount against another on both sides of the cashbook is a","options":["original entry","contra entry","prime entry","contract entry"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"What is the main purpose of transaction file?","options":["To record assets and liabilities","To update income and expenses","to update master files","to make organization decision"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Processed data is only useful to user if it is","options":["complex","quantitative","relevant","qualitative"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Changes can occur in partnership when: <br>\r\ni. partnership is dissolved <br>\r\nii. There is amalgamation of partnership <br>\r\niii.There is a change in the profit or loss sharing ratio <br>\r\nIv. Intangible asset increase","options":["I,II and IV","I & III","I,II and III","I, III and IV"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"The authority warrant issued prior to the approval of the appropriate bill at the beginning of the year","options":["provisional general warrant","annual general warrant","Reserved expenditure warrant","contigencies"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"one of the options below is not the source of income for non- profit organization","options":["Entrance fees","subscription\/dues","odrinary shares","Donations"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c}   & N \\\\ \\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Stock Jan 1} & 2600 \\\\ \\hline  \\text{Purchases} & 4000 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Carriage inwards}  & 500 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Sales}  & 9000 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Carriage outwards} & 500<br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the net profit","options":["\u20a64,000","\u20a64,500","\u20a65,000","\u20a61,400"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Salaries in arrears is treated in the balance sheet as a","options":["current asset","current liability","fixed asset","long term liability"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c}  & N \\\\ \\hline \\text{Plant and Machinery}  & 190 000 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Motor Vehicle} & 170 000 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Stock}  & 60 000 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Current Liabilities} & 50 000 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Purchase consideration}  & 400 000 \\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the amount of goodwill","options":["\u20a6110 000","\u20a6 80 000","\u20a6 90 000","\u20a6 30 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"When starting with the cash book balance in preparing the bank reconciliation statement, the followings are added","options":["Unpresented cheque","Dividend","Uncredited cheque","credit transfer"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Which of these is the main source document for recording cash paid into bank?","options":["invoice","cheque book","credit note","pay-in-slip"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nI. It records subscription in arrears <br>\r\nII. Payments of liabilities is effected <br>\r\nIII. The account does not show if cash payment is revenue or capital expenditure <br>\r\nIV. It performs the same function as cashbook <br>\r\nThe features of receipts and payment account includes","options":["I,II and IV","II,III and IV","III and IV","I,II and III"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"The movement of goods from head office to a branch is treated in the head office as","options":["Sales","issue","purchases","requisition"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"The following are the importance of branch account except","options":["it enable the organization to determine the branch that is making either profit or loss","it allows proper control over the branch by the head office","it assist the organization to determine the performance of a branch manager","it allows fraud and wastage of resources"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"The current growth in the volume of trading and financial dealing in Nigeria is helped by","options":["increased financial activities","government intervention","credit as a factor in business","Payment for goods in cash"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"One of the options below have the same features as the profit and loss account in non-profit organization","options":["Income and expenditure account","profit and loss account","receipts and payment account","Non profit account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Calculate the discount received in Department B <br>\r\n\\(\\begin{array}{c|c}  & \\text{Dept A} & \\text{Dept B} \\\\ \\hline   &  N &  \\\\ \\hline \\text{Sales} & 250 000 & 500 000 \\\\ \\hline  \\text{Purchases} & 150 000 & 250 000 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Discount received} & 24 000 &   \\\\ \\hline \\text{Discount allowed}  & 15 000  &  &  <br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)","options":["\u20a612,000","\u20a615,000","\u20a616,000","\u20a69,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"An advantage of FIFO method of stock valuation is that","options":["it serves-as a control during inflation","it is calculated at the end of the year","it is progressive in nature","its flow of cost is in sequence with the flow of stock."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Discount allowed is enjoyed by","options":["Managers","Customers","Suppliers","Staff of the company"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c}  & \\text{Dept A} & \\text{Dept B} \\\\ \\hline   &  N &  \\\\ \\hline \\text{Sales} & 250 000 & 150,000 \\\\ \\hline  \\text{Purchases} & 500,000 & 250 000 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Discount received} & 24 000 &   \\\\ \\hline \\text{Discount allowed}  & 15 000  &  &  <br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the discount allowed by Department A","options":["\u20a65,000","\u20a69,375","\u20a65,625","\u20a68,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"The accounting entries for goods stolen in branch will be to debit","options":["The accounting entries for goods stolen in branch will be to debit","branch stock account and credit branch adjustment account","branch adjustment account and credit profit and loss account","branch adjustment account and credit branch stock account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c}  & \\text{N} \\\\ \\hline \\text{Balance as per cashbook}  & 5 467 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Uncredited cheques}  & 4 410 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Unpresented cheques}  & 19 404 \\\\ \\hline  \\text{Cheques wrongly debited by bank} & 1 404 \\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe balance as per bank statement is","options":["\u20a621,901","\u20a619,021","\u20a621,109","\u20a621,091"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"The following appears in trading account except","options":["sales","carriage outward","carriage inward","opening stock"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Goodwill can be created in the books of a partnership firm when","options":["the partnership experiences super profit","a new member is admitted","the business is being expanded","the business suffers high loss"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c}  & \\text{N} \\\\ \\hline \\text{Debtors opening} & 4000 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Debtors clsoing} & 1500 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Cash received from debtors} & 8500 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Bad debts written off} & 350 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Discount allowed} & 500 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Discount Received} & 1000\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the amount of sales of sales for the year?","options":["\u20a63850","\u20a66650","\u20a61550","\u20a66850"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Given: <br>\r\nI. Settlement of debts <br>\r\nII. Cessation of business<br>\r\nIII. Introduction of assets <br>\r\nIV. Disposal of assets <br>\r\nWhich of these constitutes dissolution of partnership?","options":["II and IV only","I,II and IV only","I,II and III only","II,III and IV only"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"The use of a three column cash book is determined by","options":["cash discount","trade discount","cash transaction","Bank transaction"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"The discount column on the left-hand side of cashbook represents a discount","options":["received from a creditor","allowed to a debtor","received from a debtor","allowed to a creditor"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Which of the following is used to service all operations of government?","options":["Consolidated Revenue Fund","Consolidated Reserve Fund","Special Operational Fund","General-Reserve Fund"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c}   & \\text{N} \\\\ \\hline \\text{Balance as per cashbook} & 5 467 \\\\ \\hline  \\text{Uncredited cheques}  & 4 410 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Unpresented cheque} & 19 404 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Cheques wrongly debited by bank} & 1 440 <br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)","options":["\u20a64207","\u20a69527","\u20a66907","\u20a69877"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"The tier of government that uses financial memorandum","options":["Federal government","state government","local government","municipal government"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"What is the effect of transaction when cash is paid into the bank","options":["Bank balance decrease and cash balance increase","bank balance decrease and cash balance decrease","cash balance increase and bank balance increase","cash balance decrease and bank balance increase"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"The principle of double entry developed from the axioms of accounting equation is given as","options":["Assets + Liability = Equity","Assets + Equity = Liabilities","Liabilities + Equity = Asset","Liabilities + Equity = Net assets"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c}  & \\text{N} \\\\ \\hline \\text{Stock Jan 1} & 2000 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Purchases} & 4000 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Carriage inwards} & 500 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Sales} & 9000 \\\\ \\hline \\text{Carriage outwards} & 500\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCarriage outwards","options":["\u20a69,000","\u20a62,500","\u20a63,000","\u20a61,500"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"The correct expression of accounting equation is","options":["Assets = Liabilities + Equity","Net assets = Liabilities + Equity","Assets + Liabilities = Equity","Assets = Equity - liabilities"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Subscription in advance is treated in the balance sheet as a","options":["current asset","current liability","fixed asset","long term liability"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Which of these is a content of a master file?","options":["All records relevant to the organisation.","Records of assets of the organisation","A collection of data items","All records relating to employees"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"An evidence of payment issued to a government ministry by a revenue collector is","options":["treasury receipt","receipt voucher","payment voucher","treasury card"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"A part of public company's profits belonging to the shareholders is","options":["public issue","bonus","right issue","dividends"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"When expenses are paid on behalf of the venture, the accounting entries is to debit","options":["bank account and credit joint venture account","expenses account and credit bank account","joint venture account and credit expenses account","joint venture account and credit bank account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"Balance as per cashbook        2, 970<br>\r\nBank Charges            220<br>\r\nUnpresented cheques     3, 950<br>\r\nUncredited cheques      4, 178<br>\r\nDirect debit by bank    1, 0000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the balance as per bank statement.","options":["# 1,978","# 1962","# 1,522","# 2,522"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The records of Superstores shows a loan of #14,000 from Bala,creditor #8,000 and assets #190,500. What is the firm's capital?","options":["#184, 000","#196,500","#212,000","#168,500"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The major advantage of the journal proper is that it","options":["helps in the preparation of the balance sheet","prevents fraud and theft of item of the business","serves as a book of instruction to the bookkeeper","help the banking industry to be efficient"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Departments    K          Y<br>\r\nOpening       2,500      800<br>\r\nPurchases     120,000    100,000<br>\r\nSales         180,000    200,000<br>\r\nSalary        8,000      30,000<br>\r\nClosing stock 3,000      1,500<br>\r\nRate expenses of 1,500 are apportioned in the ratio 1:2<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe gross profit for K is","options":["# 60,700","#23,500","#60,500","#82,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"One of the objectives of accounting is that it can be used for","options":["business decision making","due process in business","motivating employees","determining the work force"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The ratio that gives the indication of the efficiency of a firm's sales with respect to cost of goods sold is a","options":["return on capital employed","gross profit margin","net profit margin","return on equity"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The instrument used in analysis and interpretation of financial statement is the","options":["accounting ratios","income and expenditure extract","balance sheet extract","found accounting"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"An item in the balance sheet of a limited liability company is","options":["accrued expenses","lighting and heating","salaries and wages","general expenses"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The documents that provide instant information to firms on their tranactions with banks are","options":["bank statement and debit note","cheque book and cashbook","cheque stub and deposit slip","payslip and credit invoice"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Which of the following is the capital reserve of a company?","options":["Accumulated depreciation","Retained profit","Share premium","Loss on forfeited shares"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The effect of overstating revenue expenditure in the profit and loss account is that the","options":["opening stock will be increased","net profit will be understand","net profit will be overstead","opening stock will be decreased"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Which of the following condition would attract credit and debit notes to be used?","options":["When goods are received from supplier","When a trial balance is extracted","When a buyer is under or over charged","When goods are sold to a buyer"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Given:                 #<br>\r\nDrawings              3,500<br>\r\nNet loss              2,500<br>\r\nCapital 1.1,2007      35,000<br>\r\nAdditional capital    10,000<br>\r\nThe adjusted capital as at 31 : 12 : 2007 is","options":["#45,000","#39, 000","#35,000","#46,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"A receipt is an evidence of","options":["payments","stocking","delivery","discounts"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Turaki Youth Club Income and Expenditure for the year ended 31\/12\/04<br>\r\n<br>\r\n                 #                              #<br>\r\nBal.b\/d         390    Expenses on cleaning    300<br>\r\nSales of         -     New tool                510<br>\r\ntrickets        4,000  Repairs                 400<br>\r\nDonations       3,000  Electricity             350<br>\r\nSubscription    6,500<br>\r\nWhat is the total income for the period?","options":["#10,500","#13,500","#13,890","#9,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"An organization which has records of only personal accounts is said to be operating on the basis of","options":["single entry","real accounts","nominal accounts","double entry"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"A proprietor started business with #13,000. Assets and liabilities at the end of the year; fixed assets #8,800, stock #, 600, debtors #1,000, cash #3, 000 and creditors #1,000. Determine the profit for the year?","options":["#2,400","#3,000","#9,800","#1,400"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Badge Plc issued 450,000 ordeinary shares of 50k each at #1.50 per share <br>\r\nApplication and allotment 45k<br>\r\n1st call 50k<br>\r\n2nd call 55k<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the amount received on final call.","options":["#225,000","#236,250","#247,500","#202,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"When goods are sent to the branch at cost plus mark-up, it means that the branch should sell at","options":["a price above or below the stipulated price","any price but not below the transfer price","cost price","a price that is equal to the mark-up"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The income and expenditure account differs from receipts and payments account because it","options":["accounts for notional charges","records transactions that relate to the period on cash basis","records transactions that relate to the period on accrual basis","accounts for balance of cash at bank"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The major sources of revenue for the state and local governments is","options":["value added tax","statutory allocation","taxes and levies","recurrent revenue"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"<b>1. The amount of the imprest is the same from one organization to another.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n2. At the end of a fixed period, the petty cashier received a fixed sum of money.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n3. At the end of a period, the petty cashier is reimbursed with the amount spent in that period.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n4. The system is a method by which a measure of control is kept on petty cash expenses.<\/b> <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhich of the following is correct about the imprest system?","options":["II and IV","I, III and IV","I, II and III","III and IV"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"When the fixed capital method is used, the partners' share of profits and remunerations are credited to the","options":["current account","profit and loss account","profit and loss appropriation account","capital account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"A discount that is allowed to encourage a debtor to pay off his debt within a period is the","options":["annual discount","trade discount","periodic discount","cash discount"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The costs of acquiring fixed assets and bringing them into the firm is a","options":["general expenses","recurrent expenditure","revenue expenditure","capital expenditure"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Impersonal account is subdivided into","options":["real and nominal accounts","nominal and personal accounts","real and current accounts","personal and real accounts"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Opening balance of Dikscompany was #12,202, closing balance #15,300, total cash received during the period #40,000. What wasthe amount of cash paid during the same period?","options":["#36,902","#27,502","#12,498","#43,098"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The total cash and cheques received from customers in a control account is derived from the","options":["income and expenditure account","cashbook","purchases day book","sales journal"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Which of the foloowing is a credit item in creditors ledger control account?","options":["Returns outwards","Discount Received","Bad debts","Purchases"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The trader is capital in a single entry system is ascertained by preparing","options":["gross profit","statement of affairs","suspense account","appropriation account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"<b>I. Members subscription <br>\r\nII.  Fines from members<br>\r\nIII. Donation<br>\r\nIV.  Loan from bank <\/b><br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the informaation above, sources of income for a Not-for-profit-making organization include","options":["I,III,IV","I,II,III","I,II,IV","I and IV"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Clifford pays rent of #200 per month for premises He paid #2,800 within the year. Computer the prepayment.","options":["#300","#400","#600","#200"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Purchases can be ascertained through the preparation of a","options":["stock account","sales account","total debtors control account","total creditors control account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"When stock is withdrawn for personal use, the accounting entries is to debit","options":["stock account credit drawings","drawing account, credit stock account","personal account credit cash account","cash account, credit personal account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Sundry debtors in the balance sheet of Onoja Bakery and Sons totaled #800,000. A provision for bad and doubtful debts. <br>\r\nFind the amount for  sundry debtors after provision.","options":["#744,800","#760,000","#784,000","#744,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Which of the following is accounted for in receipts and payments account?","options":["Accrued expenses on annual dances","Subscriptions due but not yet received","interest on bank deposit","Depreciation of the club house"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"When the purchase consideration is lower ttan the net asset, the buyer has gained the advantage of","options":["capital reserve","revenue reserve","net income","net loss"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"An increase in government expenditure within a year is taken care of by means of","options":["virement","financial regulations","supplementary estimate","warrant"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"A business organization prepares departmental account in order to","options":["asertian the contribution of each department to the organization","ascertain interdepartmental transfer","build other branches","know the number of departments in the organization"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The objective of departmental account is to","options":["ascertain the amount of profits or losses for the enterprise","ascertain the amount of profits or losses for each department","ascertain the cost of running the organization","offset the loss of each department"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Which of the following expenses relate to the profit and loss account of a manufacturing firm?","options":["Administrative overhead","Direct labour","Direct materials","Work-in-progress"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The difference between book keeping and accounting is that while","options":["book keeping interprets  data, accounting records it","book keeping is regarded as the language of the business accounting ascertians its strength and weakness","book keeping records data accounting interprets it","book keeping summaries information accounting communicatesit"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Alaka who owed Saka N15,000, settled his debt after deducting cash discount of 10%. To record the discount in the book of Saka, debit","options":["Saka's account and credit discount received account","Alaka's account and credit discount received account","Discount received account and credit Alaka's account","Discount allowed account and credit Alaka's account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"If the scrap value is now N15,000. What will be the yearly depreciation using the straight line method.?","options":["N11,000","N7,000","N4,000","N24,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The yearly depreciation using the straight line method would be?","options":["N5,200","N6,500","N8,800","N4,400"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"What is the total sales for the period?","options":["N37,000","N36,000","N35,000","N40,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"What is the total purchase for the period?","options":["N30,200","N30,000","N25,000","N31,200"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"An expenses is said to be revenue in nature if it","options":["adds or contributes to the operating income of the business","necessitates the introduction of additional capital","reduces the capital of the business","adds to or improves the value of fixed assets"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"An entry in a subsidiary book which does not form part of the double entry system is a","options":["contra entry","single entry","journal entry","memorandum entry"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p>Determine wage expenses from the given information, wages outstanding at the beginning, wages paid during the period 15000 and wages outstanding of the period 2,000<\/p>","options":["N16,000","N17,000","N13,000","N14,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Which method of pricing can be used satisfactorily in either rising or falling price situation?","options":["Market price","Average method","FIFO","Standard price"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} <br>\r\n\\text{Stock} & 11,250 \\\\ <br>\r\n\\hline <br>\r\n\\text{Debtors} & 18,750 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Creditors} & 3,750 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Bank} & 4,000 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Net profit} & 7,500 \\\\ <br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Net} & 60,000 \\\\<br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the acid test ratio","options":["5 : 1","6 : 1","6 : 1 : 1","4 : 1"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the following information to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nClub building   400,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSubscription prepaid  3,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSport kits      150,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBar creditors    85,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSubscription owing    32,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the club\u2019s accumulated fund?","options":["N699, 000","N641, 000","N402, 000","N605, 000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"What will be the number of shares to be issued to a subscriber who applied for 50,000 units.","options":["20,000","18,000","15,000","12,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBuhari and Osinbajo are in partnership with the following partnership agreement <br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\n <br>\r\n               Buhari            Osinbajo<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital        40, 000             70, 000 <br>\r\n<br>\r\nSalary         10, 000             15, 000 <br>\r\n<br>\r\nInterest on capital  5%             5% <br>\r\n<br>\r\nProfit\/loss sharing ratio  40        60 <br>\r\n <br>\r\n               <br>\r\nThe net profit for the year ended is N80,000.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n\"Drawings are N80, 000 and N12, 000 for Buhari and Osinbajo respectively\"<br>\r\nWhat is Osinbajo share of profit?","options":["N19, 800","N49, 500","N48, 000","N29, 700"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The major distinguishing element between the final account of a partnership and that of a sole trader is the","options":["drawing A\/C","capital A\/C","Creditor A\/C","Appropriation A\/C"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} <br>\r\n\\text{Stock} & 11,250 \\\\ <br>\r\n\\hline <br>\r\n\\text{Debtors} & 18,750 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Creditors} & 3,750 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Bank} & 4,000 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Net profit} & 7,500 \\\\ <br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Net} & 60,000 \\\\<br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the debtors collection period","options":["114 days","68 days","37 days","41 days"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Prime cost is one of the following","options":["expenses which can be identified with an allocated to cost centers","aggregate direct material cost, direct labour cost and variable direct expenses","the cost taken into account in the production process whether direct or indirect","the cost of commodities supply to an undertaking"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The accounting concept that allows the cost of kitchen cutlery to be expensed, though it can be used for more than one year is","options":["Materiality","Accrual","Going concern","Business entity"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTimo and Chris are computer engineers who went into partnership as Teachi and Co. Timo brought cash ofN12,000 furniture worth of N18,000 and vehicle worth of 70,000. Chris equally brought in cash of 10,000 his building valued at 105,000 and personal computers worth N35,000.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the profit sharing ratio if it\u2019s based on capital contribution by Teechi and Co?","options":["2 : 3","3 : 2","6 : 5","5 : 6"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"When the invoice of a customer is overcast, the supplier will send to him a","options":["debit note","cheque","credit note","payment voucher"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Using LIFO method of stock valuation, analyze the issue quantities and their prices","options":["260 units at N1.50","700 units at N1.50","200 units at N1.50 and 500 units at N1.00","350 units at N1.50 and 350 units at N1.00"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"CR. \t          DR.<br>\r\nSales ledger balance \t9, 500<br>\r\nSales ledger balance \t420 \t <br>\r\nBought ledgers balance \t6, 115 \t <br>\r\nBought ledger balance \t350 \t <br>\r\nCredit sales \t        82, 000 \t <br>\r\nPurchases journal \t54, 700<br>\r\nDiscount allowed \t450 \t <br>\r\nDiscount received \t200 \t <br>\r\nCash refunded to customers (debtors) \t120<br>\r\nPurchases ledger balance \t  \t250<br>\r\nSales ledger balance \t                120 \t <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe amount brought down in the sales ledger control account would be","options":["N9, N1740; N120","N90, N990","N90, N870; N120","N80, N750"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The ledger entries to be made if cash sales is banked is debit","options":["cash, credit sales","sales, credit cash","bank, credit cash","bank, credit sales"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"In a bank reconciliation statement, Dishonoured cheques is added to","options":["unpresented cheques","uncredited cheques","statement of account","aggregate balanace as per cash book"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Which of the following is a debit entry in debtors control account?","options":["discount allowed","return inwards","credit sales","cash from debtors"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a proper form of the accounting equation","options":["fixed assets + current assets  - liabilities = capital","fixed assests + current assests + liabilities = capital","fixed assets \u2013 liabilities + current assets = capital","fixed asset + current asset \u2013 capital = liabilities"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The accounting convention that state that stock should be value that the lower of cost and net realized value is --------------- convention","options":["marching","consistency","realization","prudency"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"What does liquidity ratio measure?","options":["measures operating efficiency of a company","measures the ability of a company to meet its current obligations.","measures the value of investments of a company","measures the financial leverage of a company"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Derive the stock turnover period.(Average stock = 23,000. Cost of sales = 300,000 year = 365 days).","options":["28 days","42 days","27 days","23 days"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The following accounting entries are made when bad debt is recovered","options":["debit bad debts accounts and credit bad debt recovered account","debit debtors accounts and recovered account","debit bad debts recovered account and credit bad debts account","debit bad debts account and credit profit and loss account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"One of the items listed below will not be found in a company\u2019s memorandum and article of association. Which is it?","options":["objects and their alteration","location of business","bank signatories","powers of directors"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The act of making necessary adjustment after comparing the actual cost with targeted cost is cost ----------------------------","options":["conversion","control","allocation","analysis"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Sales ledger control account contains the total amount in respect of","options":["creditors","debtors","investors","shareholders"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The following account are prepared when goods are sent to branch except","options":["Branch stock","Goods set to branch account","Branch adjustment account","Branch debtors account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The basis of accounting for public sector is","options":["accrual basis","cost basis","revenue basis","cash basis"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSegunOjo, didn\u2019t keep her books on double principle. On 1st Jan, 2014, cash in hand was 850, bank overdraft 3500, debtor 15,500,stock 18,000, fittings 9,000 and creditors 12,700. As at Dec, 2014, cash in hand was 1200, cash at bank 2,500, debtors 10,000, stock 20,500, furnishing 4,000 and creditors 17,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the closing capital 31\/12\/2014","options":["17,500","38,200","20,700","27,200"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"If the partnership agreement does not specify how net profit is to be divided, the profit should be divided<br>\r\n<br>\r\n .","options":["equally","in accordance with an established","in proportion of current account balances","in proportion of weighted average of capital"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA business has three departments x, y and z<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou are given the following information<br>\r\n<br>\r\n    Selling and distribution expenses N5200<br>\r\n    Rent for the yearN6000<br>\r\n    Department turnover floor space in square metres<br>\r\n<br>\r\n    X N60,000 80<br>\r\n<br>\r\n    Y N80,000 60<br>\r\n<br>\r\n    Z N100,000 60<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow much rent is apportioned to department Z?","options":["N1, 500","N3, 000","N1, 800","N2, 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"A sales for N2,570 was recorded in the sales day book as N2750. The error committed was","options":["error of principle","error of commission","error of original entry","compensating error"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSegun Ojo, didn\u2019t keep her books on double principle. On 1st Jan, 2014, cash in hand was 850, bank overdraft 3500, debtor 15,500,stock 18,000, fittings 9,000 and creditors 12,700. As at Dec, 2014, cash in hand was 1200, cash at bank 2,500, debtors 10,000, stock 20,500, furnishing 4,000 and creditors 17,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCompute the capital as at 1st Jan, 2014.","options":["27,150","43,350","16,200","34,350"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Keeping records under single entry system has the advantage of","options":["Quality in terms of records","Simplicity in terms of operation","Accuracy in terms of operation","Completeness in terms of records"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Which of the following is true in public sector accounting? Cost of assets is","options":["depreciated on straight line method","expensed in the year of purchase","charged to federation account","depreciated on reducing balance method"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Which of the following accounts is debited when a delivery van is sold for cash?","options":["sales account","delivery van account","cash account","profit and loss accounts"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"When shares are sold at more than the per value, they are said to have been issued at","options":["A premium","Normal value","A discount","A profit"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Calculate the total purchase of a business from the given information, cash purchases 3000; payments to creditors 54,000; creditors at the beginning 4000; creditors at the end 2,000","options":["N52,000","N51,000","N55,000","N50,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Which of the following is shown in the profit and loss appropriation account of a company","options":["interest charges","depreciation","directors emoluments","dividends"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDangote acquired Dantata\u2019s business for N350,000. The total asset work were N820,000 and liabilities amounted to N 640,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe double entry to record the goodwill in the books is debt","options":["purchase of business account and credit cash account","goodwill account and credit purchase of business account","cash account and credit goodwill account","goodwill account and credit cash account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The income and expenditure account of a club is the same as","options":["single entry account","a profit and loss account","a trading account","a cash book"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Goods stolen at the branch is debited to","options":["branch stock account","defalcations account","branch debtors account","branch adjustment account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Specific principles, bases, conventions, rules and practices adopted by an enterprise in preparing and presenting financial statements are known as ---------------------","options":["financial accounting","accounting policies","cost accounting","accounting conventions"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Which of the following cannot be realized?","options":["creditors","debtors","motor vehicles","goodwill"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"If a trail balance is in agreement, one of the statement is untrue","options":["the accounting system is error free","equal debit entries and credit entries were recorded for each transaction","the debit and credit from the journal were posted to the accounts","account balances were correctly computed"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the following information to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nClub building   400,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSubscription prepaid  3,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSport kits      150,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBar creditors    85,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSubscription owing    32,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the club\u2019s total liabilities","options":["N11, 700","N26, 700","N88, 000","N85, 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"If sales return is understated, it implies that ------------------------------ is overstated","options":["return inward","sales figure","cost of sales","return outward"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Accounting information is used by investors and creditors of a company to predict","options":["potential merger candidates for the company","appropriate remunerations for the company\u2019s staff","future cash flows of the company","future tax payments of the company"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} <br>\r\n\\hline & \\text{Dept A} & \\text{Dept B} \\\\ <br>\r\n\\hline <br>\r\n\\text{Sales} & 180,000 & 150,000 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Cost of sales} & 79,000 & 85,000 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Expense} & 28,000 & 40, 000 \\\\<br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow much is the gross profit for department A?","options":["N101,000","N73,000","N79,000","N152,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"An advantage of using accounting ratios is that","options":["can be easily calculated","show errors and frauds","facilitate decision making","are stipulated by law"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The document setting out the regulations regarding shares, meetings and internal organization of a company is known as","options":["prospectus","memorandum of association","company law","articles of association"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The loss made by a non profit making organization is called","options":["deficit","surplus","discount","shortage"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"If rent account is debited instead of rate account, the error committed is that of;","options":["omission","commission","principle","original entry"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the following information to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProvision for bad debt 1500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAdditional information<br>\r\n<br>\r\n1. Bad debt written off amount to 3000<br>\r\n2. Debtors balance as at the end of the year is 28,000<br>\r\n3. Provision for bad debts stand at 10%<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow much is to be charged to profit and loss account as provision for bad debt?","options":["N2, 800","N1, 000","N2, 500","N3, 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA limited liability company has an authorized shares capital of 50 million split into 100 millions shares. 80million shares are offered for subscriptions at 60k per share in full on application. These have been fully subscribed on issue<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the nominal value of each share","options":["N2","N0.80","N0.60","N0.50"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The interest of a petty cashier is N2450<br>\r\nExpenses N Printing 420 Cleaning 250 Stamp and postage 175 How much was received to maintain the interest at the end of the month?","options":["N1, 605","N8, 45","N2, 450","N1, 300"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The ware and tear of a fixed assets of a company which is chargeable to company\u2019s financial statement is called ------------------------------","options":["appreciation","amortization","provisions","depreciation"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"To realize an asset means to","options":["mortgage it","open its account in the ledger","turn it to cash","give it out as a collateral"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The process of cost apportionment is carried out so that","options":["indirect costs may be controlled","cost units could gather overhead as they pass through cost centres","variable costs may be controlled","common costs are shared among cost centres"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Preliminary expenses is an example of","options":["fictitious assets","liquid assets","wasting assets","tangible assets"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} <br>\r\n\\text{Raw materials jan.} & 5,000 \\\\ <br>\r\n\\hline <br>\r\n\\text{Raw materials dec.} & 5,800 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Purchase of raw materials} & 45,000 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Salary} & 61,000 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Factory lubricant} & 2,050 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{plant depreciation} & 1,300 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Factory insurance} & 1,250 \\\\<br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe prime cost for the company is","options":["N169, 200","N44, 200","N55, 800","N230, 200"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"What is the ledger entry for sale of generator on credit to Patrick?","options":["credit sales account and debit Patrick\u2019s account","credit generator account and debit cash account","credit sales account and debit cash account","credit generator account and debit Patrick\u2019s account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Sai Baba made sales of N10,000 having computed his gross profit % to sales to be 20. His opening stock was N250 and ending stock is N200. Calculate his purchases.","options":["N7950","N8050","N7050","N8950"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJejelaye Plc stock records for 2009 was given below:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJan 1    received    100 units   at         N1.00<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJan 8    received    260 units   at         N1.05<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJan 20   issued      700units   at       .........<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFeb 3    received    400 units  at         N1.15<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat will be the issued price of 700 units, using simple average method","options":["N1.183","N1.025","N1.00","N1.05"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Income and expenditure account is more detailed than receipts and payments account because it disclosed","options":["cash","cheques","debtors","stocks"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Capital reserves includes the following except","options":["revaluation surplus","pre-incoporation profit","share premium","general reserves"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a feature of accounting information?","options":["timeliness","accuracy","completeness","affordability"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The accounting concepts which assumes that business will continue to be in existence into the foresee ablefure is","options":["periodicity","business entity","dual aspect","going concern"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The purpose of a trading account is to ascertain","options":["sales","carriage outwards","gross profit or loss","net profit or loss"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"One of the the differences between bookkeeping and accounting is that the former","options":["records data while the latter interprets","is regarded as the language of the business while the latter ascertains its strenght","interprets data while the latter records it","summarises information while the latter communicates it"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The concept which states that revenue should be recognized at the point when the sale is deemed to have been made is","options":["matching","consistency","realization","going concern"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A cheque of #5,000 paid to Sulieman had been correctly entered in the cash book but had not been entered in Sulieman's account. To correct this error, debit Sulieman's account and credit","options":["cash account","bank account","suspense account","purchases account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Aduke Motors  bought three Toyota Hilux vans on cash at the cost of #6,000,000, on debiting the vehicle account, the corresponding credit for the purchase will appear in the","options":["sales day book","purchases day book","sales subsidiary book","cash book"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Which of the following affects the accuracy and authenticity of the trial balance?","options":["Error of ommission","Error of commission","Error of transposition","Error of original entry"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A ledger is classified into","options":["private, sales and purchases","personal, general and private","general, private and sales","sales, purchases and general"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The book of account in which information from the source documents are recorded consists of","options":["debit and credit notes","ledger and subsidiary books","prepayments and accruals","profit and loss and balance sheet"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The accounting entries to record a cheque issued by a business is to","options":["debit cash book and credit drawer","credit cash book and debit drawer","debit cash book and credit suspense account","credit cash book and debit suspense account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf Emeka Enterprises settles its suppliers for goods purchased within 7 days, it can earn a cash discount of 12 and half percent. Assuming #22,800 worth of goods were purchased and settled within 5 days, what will be the amount to be credited in the cash column of the company's cash book?","options":["#25,650","#22,800","#19,950","#18,240"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The major advantage of an imprest system is that it","options":["ensures a proper accountability for every expenditure","trains the young accountants in preparation for greater responsibilities","relieves the cheif cashier of the numerous petty cash payments","serves as an analysis column for every expenses"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Petty cash book records transactions on","options":["the debit side only","the credit side only","both credit and debit sides","reversed entry"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A major way by which the headquarters guard against fraud in branches on cash remittance is through the introduction of","options":["imprest system only","direct purchase by branch","separate accountant for the branch","credit sales by only the headquarters"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"1.   Cash sales<br>\r\n11.  Cash purchases<br>\r\n111. Cash discount allowed<br>\r\n1V.  Cash payment<br>\r\nV.   Cash receipts<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhich of the following are recorded on the debit side of the cash book","options":["1 and 11","1 and 111","1 and V","1 and 1V"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"An item credited in the bank statement but yet to be recorded in the firm's cash book is","options":["bank loan","contract payment","standing order","direct deposit"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The major focus of the trading account is to show","options":["net profit","gross margin","total purchases","total sales"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"If goods were bought from Tanko at a cost price of #9,000 with a cash discount of 5%, how much will be paid assuming prompt payment was made?","options":["#4,500","#8,550","#9,000","#9,450"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"If machine X cost #600,000 with anticipated life span of five years and estimated scrap value of #50,000, using straight line method; depreciation charged for two years will be","options":["#700,000","#240,000","#220,000","#202,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Balance sheet (Extract)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCreditors                         #7,940<br>\r\nPrepaid expenses                  #  290<br>\r\nAccrual expenses                  #  323<br>\r\nStock                             #4,500<br>\r\nCash balance                      #4,956<br>\r\nDebtors                           #  905<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe value of the current assets will be","options":["#10,361","#10,651","#17,396","#17,848"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Balance sheet (Extract)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCreditors                         #7,940<br>\r\nPrepaid expenses                  #  290<br>\r\nAccrual expenses                  #  323<br>\r\nStock                             #4,500<br>\r\nCash balance                      #4,956<br>\r\nDebtors                           #  905<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the current liabilities","options":["#8,553","#8,263","#7,940","#1,228"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The excess of sales over cost of goods sold is","options":["gross sales","gross profit","net profit","net sales"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"2\/3  Purchases 900 books at #1,000 each<br>\r\n4\/3  Purchases 590 books at #  950 each<br>\r\n15\/3 Sales 300 books at #900 each<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the cost of goods sold using FIFO","options":["#285,000","#300,000","#570,000","#600,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"2\/3  Purchases 900 books at #1,000 each<br>\r\n4\/3  Purchases 590 books at #  950 each<br>\r\n15\/3 Sales 300 books at #900 each<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the cost of goods available for sale using LIFO","options":["#801,000","#1,100,500","#1,160,500","#1,175,500"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The control account is used in facilitating","options":["the location of errors in the various accounts","up to date bank transactions","the payment of debts and liabilities of the firm","assets distribution with respect to income"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A book of account that possesses the features of both day book and ledger is","options":["sales day book","cash book","purchases day book","returns day book"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The value of the sales ledger control account is derived from the summation of","options":["the total debtors' account","the total creditors' account","all day books","both the debtors'and creditors' accounts"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Subscription in arrears is treated in the balance sheet of a club as","options":["current asset","current liability","fixed asset","intangible asset"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Social Club Subscription (Extract)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n31\/12\/2009 Subscription accrued             #18,900<br>\r\nSubscription received in advance            #16,400<br>\r\nSubscription received during <br>\r\nthe year 2009                               #38,570<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the amount of subscription for the year","options":["#57,470","#41,070","#40,210","#35,300"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Social Club Subscription (Extract)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n31\/12\/2009 Subscription accrued             #18,900<br>\r\nSubscription received in advance            #16,400<br>\r\nSubscription received during <br>\r\nthe year 2009                               #38,570<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the amount of subscription to be shown as liability in the balance sheet as at December 2009","options":["#14,200","#16,400","#18,900","#20,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSales                          #180,000<br>\r\nStock 1\/1                      # 25,000<br>\r\nPurchases                      #110,000<br>\r\nSales returns                  #  1000<br>\r\nPurchases returns              #  1,500<br>\r\nGross profit                   # 58,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the value of stock as at 31st December","options":["#8000","#9,500","#12,500","#15,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"In a departmental account, where no basis of apportionment exist, apportionment is","options":["on profit basis","according to employee decision","according to material available","on equal basis"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"In a departmental account, the expenses to be apportioned on the basis of turnover is","options":["carriage inwards","returns outwards","discount recieved","carriage outwards"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"If goods are sent to to branch at 25% on cost, what will be the cost of goods sent to the branch at a selling price of #100,000?","options":["#130,000","#125,000","#80,000","#75,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Hussaina Enterprises sent goods worth #800,000 at cost plus mark-up of 20% to its branch<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the cost price of the goods sent to the branch","options":["#600,000","#620,000","#640,000","#700,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Hussaina Enterprises sent goods worth #800,000 at cost plus mark-up of 20% to its branch<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the profit on the goods sent to the branch at profit margin of 25% mark-up","options":["#150,000","#160,000","#170,000","#180,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"In the absence of a partnership deed, the act stipulates that","options":["an amount should be fixed as salary for partners","interest on partners loan should be 25%","interest should not be allowed on partners drawings","profits and losses should not be shared equally"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The profit of a branch is usually credited to the","options":["adjustment account","head office sales","head office goods account","head office current account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Where partnership is converted into a limited liability company, current account balances of partners are transferred to a","options":["realization account","savings account","share capital account","capital account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The expenses incurred in purchasing a vehicle is a","options":["revenue expenditure","capital expenditure","recurrent expenditure","concurrent expenditure"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Payment for shares in excess of amount offered  gives rise to","options":["subscription in advance","revenue reserves","capital reserves","calls-in-advance"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The details of the share capital which a company is authorized to issue is contained in the","options":["Articles of Association","Companies and Allied Matters Act","Memorandum of Association","Share capitak certificate"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"#800,000 worth of ordinary shares of 50k were issued at #1 each, payable in full on application. The entry in the cash book would be to","options":["credit #1,600,000","debit #1,600,000","credit #1,600,000","debit #800,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Oil and Buns issued to the public 1,300,000 ordinary shares of 75k at a price of #1.50k. Application and allotment were received for 900,000 shares at 25k each.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the amount received on application and allotment","options":["#224,950","#225,000","#324,950","#325,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Oil and Buns issued to the public 1,300,000 ordinary shares of 75k at a price of #1.50k. Application and allotment were received for 900,000 shares at 25k each.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe book value of issued share capital is","options":["#675,000","#975,000","#1,350,000","#1,950,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The account of government into which all monies are received and from which all expenditures are disbursed is the","options":["Federation account","Petroleum Technology Development Fund","Central Bank Account","Development fund"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"In government accounting, the method used which records on the basis of financial entity with self-balancing books instead of entity of proprietorship is","options":["virement","fund accounting","consolidated fund","financial regulation"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The formula for calculating depreciation using straight line method is","options":["\\( \\frac{\\text{Scrape Value} + \\text{Sales}}{Useful life} \\)","\\( \\frac{\\text{Cost } - \\text{Scrape Value}}{Useful life} \\)","\\( \\frac{\\text{Sales } - \\text{Scrape Value}}{Useful life} \\)","\\( \\frac{\\text{Purchases } + \\text{Sales }}{Useful life} \\)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Determine the closing stock.","options":["N30,000","N40,000","N50,000","N60,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"What is the total income for the period?","options":["N13,890","N13,500","N10,500","N9,500"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"What is the balance carried down?","options":["N11,680","N11,930","N12,330","N13,430"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Accounting information seeks to provide","options":["permanent records for all transactions","analysis of accounts to trade debtors","audited reports on the accounts of a company","data about the employees of a company"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"When the debit side total of an account, t means that the account has","options":["been overdrawn","been understand","debit balance","credit balance"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"July 1 - Started business with #10,500<br>\r\nJuly 31- Paid Agromachinex #6,000 owing<br>\r\n         them<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe double entry for July 1 would be","options":["debit capital and credit cash","credit cash and debit bank","debit cash and credit capital","debit purchases and credit cash"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"July 1 - Started business with #10,500<br>\r\nJuly 31- Paid Agromachinex #6,000 owing<br>\r\n         them<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe double entry for July 31 would be","options":["debit Agromachinex and credit cash","debit  equipment and credit  Agromachinex","credit capital and debit cash","credit cash and debit purchases"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The total credit sales for a period can be extracted from the","options":["cash book","sales day book","petty cash book","returns inwards"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The major source document which enables an employer to calculate the employee wages is the","options":["nominal roll of employees","record of number of hours worked","effort of the employee","record of number of dependants per employee"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Which of the following items is a capital expenditure?","options":["Maintenance of office machine","Purchase of office stationery","Carriage inwards","Purchase of office machinery"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The corresponding entry of personal accounts found in the debit side of the cash is to","options":["credit real accounts","debit real accounts","credit the ledger","debit the ledger"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Alaka who owed Saka #15,000, settled his debt after deducting cash discount of 10percent. To record the discount in the book of Saka, debit","options":["discount recieved account and credit Alaka's account","Alaka's account and credit discount recieved account","Saka's account and credit discount recieved account","discount allowed account and credit Alaka's account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"1. The amount of the imprest is the same from one organization to another<br>\r\n11.At the end of a fixed period, the petty cashier received a fixed sum of money.<br>\r\n111. At the end of a period, the petty cashier is reimbursed with the amount spent in that period.<br>\r\n1V. The system is a method by which a measure of control is kept on petty cash expenses.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhich of the above is correct about the imprest system?","options":["1, 11 and 111","1, 111 and 1V","11 and 1V","111 and 1V"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"A machine bought for #35,000 was estimated to have a life span of 5 years with a scrap value of #9,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe yearly depreciation using the straight line method would be","options":["#8,800","#6,500","#5,200","#4,400"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"A machine bought for #35,000 was estimated to have a life span of 5 years with a scrap value of #9,000.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf the scrap value is presently #15,000 what will be the yearly depreciation using straight line method?","options":["#4,000","#7,000","#11,000","#24,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The purchase of mattresses from Freehold enterprises by cheque amounted to #305,150. The correct entries for this transaction in the book of the buyer is to debit","options":["sales account and credit bank account","purchases and credit bank account","cash and credit freehold","bank and credit freehold"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Sales             -     #232,000<br>\r\nOpening stock     -     # 28,000<br>\r\nPurchases         -     #128,000<br>\r\nCarriage inwards  -     #  4,000<br>\r\nCarriage outwards -     #  6,000<br>\r\nClosing stock     -     # 10,000<br>\r\nDiscount received -     # 18,000<br>\r\nExpenses          -     # 20,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the gross profit","options":["#100,000","#86,000","#82,000","#76,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Sales             -     #232,000<br>\r\nOpening stock     -     # 28,000<br>\r\nPurchases         -     #128,000<br>\r\nCarriage inwards  -     #  4,000<br>\r\nCarriage outwards -     #  6,000<br>\r\nClosing stock     -     # 10,000<br>\r\nDiscount received -     # 18,000<br>\r\nExpenses          -     # 20,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the expenses debited to the profit and loss account","options":["#17,000","#23,000","#26,000","#30,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOpening capital     -    #1,500<br>\r\nCapital introduced  -    #  500<br>\r\nProfit for the year -    #  800<br>\r\nCash drawings       -    #  250<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the closing capital","options":["#2,550","#2,500","#2,350","#2,250"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"What type of stock valuation would a vegetable seller adopt in valuing it's product?","options":["LIFO","FIFO","Simple average","Weighted average"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The total cash and cheques received from customers in a control account is derived from the","options":["purchases day book","cash book","income and expenditure account","sales journal"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"1\/1\/2010         31\/12\/2010<br>\r\nCreditors         -       #9,000             #9,800<br>\r\nRent owing        -       #3,800             #2,500<br>\r\nRates prepaid     -       #2,000             #3,500<br>\r\nMotor van         -       #8,000             #8,000<br>\r\nPremises          -       #10,000            #10,500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind the opening capital","options":["#5,700","#7,700","#9,800","#14,900"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"1\/1\/2010         31\/12\/2010<br>\r\nCreditors         -       #9,000             #9,800<br>\r\nRent owing        -       #3,800             #2,500<br>\r\nRates prepaid     -       #2,000             #3,500<br>\r\nMotor van         -       #8,000             #8,000<br>\r\nPremises          -       #10,000            #10,500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the closing capital","options":["#8,700","#9,500","#9,700","#10,700"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOpening capital          -     #50,000<br>\r\nClosing capital          -     #64,000<br>\r\nDrawings                 -     #16,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the net profit","options":["#2,000","#14,000","#20,000","#30,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The estimated profit or loss for a period is calculated by","options":["closing capital less opening capital add drawings","opening capital less closing capital add drawings","opening capital less drawings add closing capital","opening capital add closing add drawings"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDrawings           -    #3,500<br>\r\nNet loss           -    #2,500<br>\r\nCapital 1\/1\/2007   -    #35,000<br>\r\nAdditional capital -    #10,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe adjusted capital as at 31\/1\/2007 is","options":["#35,000","#39,000","#45,000","#46,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"When goods produced are transferrd at cost plus mark-up sale, the difference between the cost and the transferred price is a","options":["discount","sales commission","manufacturing profit","factory reserves"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The addition of prime cost, indirect cost and opening work-in-progress less the closing work-in-progress will result in cost of","options":["goods available for sale","goods sold","goods manufactured","materials put into production"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Opening stock of raw materials  -   #75,000<br>\r\nPurchase of raw materials       -   #330,000<br>\r\nClosing stock of raw materials  -   #80,000<br>\r\nDirect wages                    -   #30,000<br>\r\nCarriages of raw materials      -   #10,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the cost of raw materials used","options":["#495,000","#415,000","#335,000","#305,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Purchase of raw materials       -   #330,000<br>\r\nClosing stock of raw materials  -   #80,000<br>\r\nDirect wages                    -   #30,000<br>\r\nCarriages of raw materials      -   #10,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the prime cost","options":["#525,000","#515,000","#465,000","#365,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"In manufacturing account, the work-in-progress at the end of the year is","options":["deducted from the cost of goods completed during this year","added to the cost of goods completed","stated in the profit and loss account","stated in the prime cost section"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Which of the following is accounted for in receipts and payment account","options":["Subscriptions recieved in advance","Subscriptions due not yet recieved","Accrued expenses on annual dances","Depreciation of the club house"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Which of the following expenses relates to the profit and loss account of a manufacturing firm","options":["Direct materials","Direct labour","Administrative overhead","Work-in-progress"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"1. Direct materials<br>\r\n11.Direct labour<br>\r\n111.Direct expenses<br>\r\n1V. Factory expenses<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPrime cost consist of","options":["1,11 and 111","1,11 and 1V","1,111 and 1V","11,111 and 1V"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The amount paid by a new partner on admission as a compensation for the reputation built up by old partners is a","options":["bonus","commission","premium","goodwill"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"A partnership's internal regulations are set out by","options":["a deed","a law","a constitution","an article"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"In a partnership account, interest on drawings is","options":["debited to appropriation account","credited to appropiation account","treated as an expense in profit and loss account","recorded in the balance sheet as current assets"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"When a share valued at 50k is issued at #1.59, it is said to be issued  at","options":["par","premium","discount","interest"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The purchase consideration that is lower than the net asset implies that, the buyer has gained the advantage of","options":["net income","revenue reserve","capital reserve","net loss"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"When shares are issued at a discount, entries  are to debit","options":["application allotment account and credit discount accoun","discount account and credit","cash account and credit discount account","discount account and credit bank account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"When there is no basis of apportionment in an organization, the expenses should be apportioned based on","options":["sales","purchases","equality","floor space"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Department              K                 Y<br>\r\nOpening stock          #2,500          #800<br>\r\nPurchases              #120,000        #100,000<br>\r\nSales                  #180,000        #200,000<br>\r\nSalaries               #8,000          #30,000<br>\r\nClosing stock          #3,000          #1,500<br>\r\nRate expenses of #1,500 are apportioned in the ratio 1:2.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe gross profit for K is","options":["#23,500","#60,500","#60,700","#82,500"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Department              K                 Y<br>\r\nOpening stock          #2,500          #800<br>\r\nPurchases              #120,000        #100,000<br>\r\nSales                  #180,000        #200,000<br>\r\nSalaries               #8,000          #30,000<br>\r\nClosing stock          #3,000          #1,500<br>\r\nRate expenses of #1,500 are apportioned in the ratio 1:2.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is he net profit of Y?","options":["#52,000","#68,300","#68,800","#69,700"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The objective of departmental account is to","options":["ascertain the cost of running the organization","ascertain the amount of profit or loss for each department","ascertain the amount of profits for losses for the enterprises","offset the loss of each treatment"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Which of the following is the capital reserve of a company","options":["Share premium","Retained profit","Accumulated depreciation","Loss on forfeited shares"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nApplications were invited by the directors of Abiodun PLC for 500,000 ordinary shares of #1:00 each at #1:10 per share payable as follows;<br>\r\nOn application            46k<br>\r\nOn allotment              20k<br>\r\n1st Call                  15k<br>\r\n2nd Call                  19k<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow much is to be paid for application?","options":["#230,000","#280,000","#500,000","#550,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The issued share capital is the number of shares that are","options":["authorized by share holders","shared among the directors","fully subscribed","in the share certificate"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The distributable profit available to shareholders at the end of each year is the","options":["total profit and debtors balance","general reserve and retained profit","retained profit and fictitious assets","total profit less creditors balance"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The debenture issued at par above the nominal value is said to be issued at a","options":["cost price","mark-up","premium","margin"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Accountant-general of the federation is responsible for","options":["the general supervision of all auditing personnel in all the ministeries","the compilation of annual financial statement","the interpretation of rules and regulations affecting the private sectors","ensuring the efficient operation of the ministries"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAssets and Liabilities of a Local Government<br>\r\nBank balance                   #6,484,000<br>\r\nCash                           #  900,000<br>\r\nGeneral revenue balances       #9,774,500<br>\r\nAccrued salaries               #1,220,000<br>\r\nInvestment in shares           #1,480,000<br>\r\nVehicles                       #7,620,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the liabilities of the local government","options":["#10,994,500","#17,394,500","#18,774,500","#18,874,500"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"An instrument which allows public officers to increase expenditure within a year is","options":["statutory allocation","supplementary budget","virement","warrant"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The basis upon which assets of an organization is valued is the","options":["historical concept","business entity concept","periodicity concept","materiality concept"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"An accountant must not only be interested in record keeping but also in","options":["the application of proffessional competency","the accuracy of postings","the casting of financial figures","effective preparation of balance sheet"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The correct posting in a double entry system of account when there is an increase in double assets, expenses, capital or liabilities is to debit","options":["capital and debit liabilities","liabilities and credit assets","assets and credit capital","capital  and credit assets"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The capital of a sole trader can be increased by","options":["debiting the capital account","crediting the capital account","debiting the cash account","crediting the cash account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Akirika bought a motor van for his business by cash. The entries are to debit","options":["motor van and credit Akirika","sales and credit Akrika","motor van and credit cash","cash and credit motor van"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Ibrahim, a micro business operator, sold 10 bags of sugar to Jide at a total cost of #12,000.<br>\r\nIn the book of Ibrahim, the entry to record the transaction would be to debit","options":["sugar account  #12,000 and credit Jide #12,000","Jide  #12,000 and credit sales account #12,000","Ibrahim #12,000 and credit Jide #12,000","sugar account #12,000 and credit Ibrahim #12,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Ibrahim, a micro business operator, sold 10 bags of sugar to Jide at a total cost of #12,000.<br>\r\nThe record in Jide's book would be to debit","options":["purchases #12,000 and credit Ibrahim #12,000","purchases #12,000 and credit sugar account #12,000","Jide #12,000 and credit purchases","Ibrahim #12,000 and sugar account #12,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"In a three-column cash book, dishonored cheques will be shown on the","options":["bank column (debit)","bank column(credit)","cash column(debit)","cash column(credit)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Cash can be drawn from the bank using","options":["a bank teller","a credit card","a recharge card","ATM card"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"In a modern day banking system, cash transfer cannot be made where the transferor","options":["has no sufficient cash with the bank","has no account with the bank","does not reside in the bank's country","does not possess the domestic currency"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nCash book balance-             #5000<br>\r\nDishonored cheque-             #1000<br>\r\nDirect credit    -             # 800<br>\r\nDirect debit     -             # 500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe adjusted cash book balance is","options":["#6,300","#4,300","#3,700","#2,700"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"At the end of a financial period, the trading<br>\r\nprofit and loss account of a sole trader <br>\r\nshows a profit of #180,000. it is however<br>\r\ndiscovered that revenue of #15,000 is<br>\r\nrecorded as expenses while expenses of<br>\r\n#4,000 is recorded as revenue.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the adjusted net profit","options":["#210,000","#202,000","#195,000","#184,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"At the end of a financial period, the trading<br>\r\nprofit and loss account of a sole trader <br>\r\nshows a profit of #180,000. it is however<br>\r\ndiscovered that revenue of #15,000 is<br>\r\nrecorded as expenses while expenses of<br>\r\n#4,000 is recorded as revenue.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe revenue to be added as an adjustment is","options":["#34,000","#30,000","#15,000","#4,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Which of the following is an item of special assets?","options":["Fixed assets","Current assets","Trademark","Gratuity"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"1\/5\/07  Purchased 100 bags of milk at #10.00k each<br>\r\n3\/5\/07  Purchased 60 bags of milk at #11.50k  each<br>\r\n15\/5\/07 Issued 85 bags of milk<br>\r\n15\/5\/07 Purchased 180 bags of milk at #12.80K each<br>\r\n22\/5\/07 Issued 145 bags of milk.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nUsing FIFO method, what would be the value of stock as at 9\/5\/07?","options":["#862.50","#840.00","#806.25","#750.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"1\/5\/07  Purchased 100 bags of milk at #10.00k each<br>\r\n3\/5\/07  Purchased 60 bags of milk at #11.50k  each<br>\r\n15\/5\/07 Issued 85 bags of milk<br>\r\n15\/5\/07 Purchased 180 bags of milk at #12.80K each<br>\r\n22\/5\/07 Issued 145 bags of milk.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nUsing simple average method, calculate the value of stock after 22\/5\/07","options":["#1,198.00","#1,218.38","#1,257.67","#1,408.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The LIFO method has an advantage over FIFO in that stocks are valued at","options":["previous prices","current prices","average rates","flat rates"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"In sales ledger control account, returns inwards is usually","options":["debited and debtors credited","credited and sales returns debited","debited and cash credited","credited and bank credited"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Purchasers ledger control account can also be referred to as","options":["sales day book","purchasers day book","creditors legder","debtors ledger"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Which of the following is a debit item in the sales ledger control account","options":["Cheque reciepts","Dishonoured cheques","Discount allowed","Bills recievable"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"In manufacturing accounts, finance expenses are charged to the","options":["departmental account","trading acount","profit and loss account","balance sheet"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Total production cost-  #360,000<br>\r\nFactory overhead cost-  #56,000<br>\r\nSelling price per unit- #   120<br>\r\nProduction volume 4000 units<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the total manufacturing profit?","options":["#64,000","#120,000","#360,000","#480,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Total production cost-  #360,000<br>\r\nFactory overhead cost-  #56,000<br>\r\nSelling price per unit- #   120<br>\r\nProduction volume 4000 units<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the value of prime cost","options":["#416,000","#304,000","#240,000","#184,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The main advantage of a departmental account is that its","options":["expenses are shared","gross profit is computed","net profit is computed","balance sheet is obtained"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The excess revenue over expenditure is charged to","options":["profit and loss","revenue account","accumulated fund","income and expenditure acccount"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nFixtures-#30,000<br>\r\nDebtors-#7,000<br>\r\nStock- #8,000<br>\r\nCreditors-#3,000<br>\r\nGoodwill-#10,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the capital","options":["#10,000","#42,000","#45,000","#52,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"In the head office ledger, the value of goods sent to the branch are","options":["debited to the head office current account","debited to the branch current account","credited to the head office current account","credited to the branch current account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Which of the  following methods of invoicing goods to branches  facilitate easy checks on the activities of branches?","options":["cost price","fixed percentage on cost","selling price","invoice price"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The partners capital are: Modibbo #60,000<br>\r\nand Jakata #90,000. The partners share<br>\r\nprofit and losses in the ratio of their capital <br>\r\ncontributions.<br>\r\nThe net profit for the year is #12,000.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind Modibbo's share of the profit","options":["#62,000","#48,000","#44,000","#43,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The partners capital are: Modibbo #60,000<br>\r\nand Jakata #90,000. The partners share<br>\r\nprofit and losses in the ratio of their capital <br>\r\ncontributions.<br>\r\nThe net profit for the year is #12,000.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is Jakata's sharing profit?","options":["3:5","1:2","2:5","1:5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"In what way can goodwill be written off in a partnership business?","options":["Using the partners' profit and loss sharing ratio","By neglecting the ratio of partners capital contributions","By sharing it unequally among the partners where no agreement exists","By sharing it among the active partners only"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Ngozi and Musa with a capital of #30,000 each decide to admit Mary into the partnership business with a capital of #20,000 and goodwill #15,000.If the profits and losses are to be shared equally, the journal entries to record goodwill are","options":["debit goodwill #15,000, cash #20,000 and credit Mary's capital #35,000","credit goodwill #15,000, cash #20,000 and debit Mary's #35,000","debit goodwill #15,000, credit cash #20,000 and credit Mary's capital #20,000","debit old partners capital #15,000, credit cash #20,000 and Mary's capital #35,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"In converting a partnership into a limited liability company, the necessary accounts to be opened in the books of the company are","options":["business purchase account and ordinary share capital account","Business purchase account, vendor account and ordinary share capital account","business purchase account and vendor account","ordinary share capital account, vendor account and unpaid share capital account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n1. The Memorandum of Association of the Company<br>\r\n11.The Article of Association of the Company<br>\r\n111. The Incorporation documents<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the above, which of the following is delivered to the Registrar of companies for incorporation","options":["1 and 11","1, 11 and 111","1 and 111","11 and 111"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"When shares are oversubscribed and money returned to unsuccessful applicants, the entry to record such money is to debit","options":["application and allotment account and credit unsubscribed shares","application and allotment account and credit cash","oversubscribed shares and credit allotment account","oversubscribed shares and credit allotment account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Investment at cost of a company is to be disclosed under","options":["trading accounts","profit and loss account","balance sheet","source and application of fund"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Purchasers         - #44,880<br>\r\nSales              - #85,850<br>\r\nTrade creditors    - #12,250<br>\r\nTrade debtors      - #24,000<br>\r\nAccrued expenses   - #   350<br>\r\nPrepaid expenses   - #   700<br>\r\nStock 1\/1\/2006     - #25,120<br>\r\nStock 31\/12\/2006   - #27,840<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the acid test ration","options":["1:94:1","1:96:1","1:1:94","1:1:96"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Purchasers         - #44,880<br>\r\nSales              - #85,850<br>\r\nTrade creditors    - #12,250<br>\r\nTrade debtors      - #24,000<br>\r\nAccrued expenses   - #   350<br>\r\nPrepaid expenses   - #   700<br>\r\nStock 1\/1\/2006     - #25,120<br>\r\nStock 31\/12\/2006   - #27,840<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the number of times stock was turned over during the period to the nearest figure","options":["1","2","3","4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Which of the following is a source of revenue to the federation account?","options":["Market fees","Bicycle licences","Tarrifs","Property rates"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The book into which all types of a ministry's expenditure are recorded is the","options":["ledger book","payment book","vote book","expenditure book"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The Petroleum Technology Development Fund is under the","options":["general fund","contingency fund","trust fund","capital fund"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The power to appoint the Auditor General of the Federation is vested in the","options":["National Assembly","President","Judicial Service Commission","Civil Service Commission"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the balance","options":["415,000 debit","215,000 credit","215,000 debit","315,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the above information, the gross profit fro department X is","options":["N3,800","N2,300","N2,200","N2,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Debtors opening and closing balances amount to N6,500 and N7,600 respectively, What is the sales value?","options":["N15,300","N17,500","N28,400","N31,600"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The 5% discount shown above indicates","options":["trade discount","cash discount","discount allowed","discount received"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Use the information above to answer the question <br>\r\nFind the gross profit.","options":["N370,000","N230,000","N150,000","N140,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Use the information above to answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the net profit.","options":["N35,000","N40,000","N105,000","N115,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Determine the bank balance","options":["N 6,950 credit","N6,950 debit","N6,000 credit","N6,000 debit"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The historical development of accounting reveals that it?","options":["deals with debit and credit of items","is a product of financial development","is a product of its own evironmnent","is an ideal subject for finacial development"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"In a trial balance, income and liabilities are?","options":["debited and credited respectively","credited","credited and debited respectively","debited"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The principle of double entry system ensures?","options":["mathematical accuracy in trial balance","balances at the bank","increase in the assets and liabilities","balance of cash account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"i)  Deducted the smaller side figure from the bigger side figure .<br>\r\nii) Add up both side <br>\r\niii)Take the difference to the smaller and add to the smaller figure <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe correct procedure for balancing account is?","options":["ii, i and iii","i, iii and ii","ii, iii and i","i, ii and iii"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLight expenses...................N400<br>\r\nPurchases........................N3,000<br>\r\nSales............................N1,200<br>\r\nCreditors........................N2,250<br>\r\nDebtors..........................N50<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the total of the trial balance?","options":["N4,250","N3,500","N4,300","N3,450"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The major feature of a journal is that it has?","options":["six columns, date, particulars, folio, amount, debit and credit","five columns, date particulars, folio, debit and credit","three columns, date particulars and folio","four columns, date particulars, folio and amount"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The medium of correcting errors whose differences are shown in the trial balance is by the use of?","options":["debtors' account","creditor's account","suspense account","ledger account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAdamu Stores bought accessories from Mu'azu  Beverages for N400 on credit. A trade discount of 10% and a cash discount of 15% were provided.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind the total amount paid?","options":["N260","N300","N200","N380"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAdamu Stores bought accessories from Mu'azu Beverages for N400 on credit. A trade discount of 10% and a cash discount of 15% were provided.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the cash discount?","options":["N60","N90","N40","N100"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"In bank  reconciliation process, discrepancies cause by timing arises as a result of?","options":["cash book bank statement","bank statement only","cash book,  bank statement and other incidental records","cash book only"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The process of reconciling cheques between banks is termed cheque?","options":["clearing","truncation","holding","confirmation"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"In a bank reconciliation  statement, interest charged for overdrawn balances should be added to the?","options":["balance as per bank statement","bank balance as per adjusted cash book","aggregate balance as per cash book","bank balance as per cash book"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\ni)  Stock of goods<br>\r\nii) Furniture <br>\r\niii)Creditors<br>\r\niv) Cash at bank<br>\r\nv)  Loan from the bank<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the current liabilities?","options":["iii and v","ii and iii","iv and v","i and ii"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\ni) Stock of goods<br>\r\nii) Furniture<br>\r\niii)Creditors<br>\r\niv) Cash at bank<br>\r\nv) Loan from the bank<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind the current assets?","options":["iii and v","ii and i","iv and v","i and iv"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The type of expense charged against administration of a firm is the?","options":["repairs on building","interesr paid on loan","discount allowed","tax expense"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"In a period of declining price, which of the following methods would result in higher profit?","options":["FIFO","Simple average","LIFO","Weighted average"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The item on the credit side of the trading account is the?","options":["returns outwards","caarriage on sales","sales","purchases"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Use the information above to answer questions 19 and 20.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJuly 30 Closing stock 100 units at N90<br>\r\nJuly 8  Purchased 200 units at N95<br>\r\nJuly 10 Sold 160 units<br>\r\nJuly 17 Returned 80 faulty units purchased at N95<br>\r\nJuly 18  Purchased 200 units at N105<br>\r\nJuly 20 Sold 180 units<br>\r\nJuly 28  Purchased 200 units at N110<br>\r\nJuly 29 Sold 120 units<br>\r\nJuly 30 Sold 100 units<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow many units were at hand as at July 30?","options":["80","100","60","160"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"What is the value of stock as at the end of July 10 using FIFO?","options":["N14 400","N13 300","N15 200","N12 600"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"A typical example of a real account is?","options":["prepayment","expenses","plant","income"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The control accounting can be used in?","options":["recording all the business transactions of the enterprise","Keeping records of all direct deposit in the bank account","monitoring the books of original entry","monitoring the efficiency of bookkepping by accountants"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 23 and 24.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIncomplete Record (Extract)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSales......................................N10,600<br>\r\nRent...........................N200<br>\r\nDepreciation of vehicle (cost N5000) 10%<br>\r\nGross profit margin is 20%<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the cost of goods sold?","options":["N4 800","N8 480","N2 320","N 9 900"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Calculate the net profit?","options":["N1 620","N1 920","N1 420","2 120"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The cost that are directly traceable to the the goods being produced is?","options":["party manufactured goods","overhead cost","total factory expenses","prime cost"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The product cost that does not form part of the product but is incidental to product and facilitates the production activities is the?","options":["prime cost","indirect cost","total cost","direct cost"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Work-in-progress is the?","options":["value of party finished goods","value of finished goods sold","sales less cost of goods sold","value of goods produced"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The major festure of not-for-profit-making-organization is that they are formed?","options":["to use accumulated fund to described  the net amount owed to members","mainly to improve the welfare of her member","to engaged in trading activities to sponsor its activities","in order to compute the receipts and payment account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The subscription paid in advance is treated in the balance sheet of a club as?","options":["a surplus","a liability","a deflicit","an asset"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The capital of not-for-profit-making organization is referred to as?","options":["entity fund","capital owned","accumulated fund","capital employed"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The major objective of departmental accounts is to ascertain the?","options":["contribution of each department to profit","materials sold in each department","insurance premium payable on employees","number of employees in each department"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The transactions relating to liquidation in partnership account is drawn by using?","options":["current account","cash account","capital account","realization account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The cost method of charging goods to branch is used where?","options":["branch stock adjustment account is in use","the retention of branch trading account is in addition to the cost of goods sold","goods are sent without invoice or any source documents","goods are of a perishable nature on which a pre-determined price is inapplicable"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The correct entries to record goods transferred to branch from head office is to debit?","options":["branch stock account and credit goods sent to branch account","branch supplies account and credit branch stock account","branch stock account and credit purchases account","goods sent to branch account and credit branch stock account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The two accounts that are normally opened in the head office when goods are transferred to a branch are?","options":["branch supplies and branch receipts","branch stock account and goods sent to branch accounts","goods sent to brannch account and branch receipt account","goods sent to branch accounts and branch supplies"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Goods invoiced to a branch can be sent using?","options":["cost price, selling price and fixed percentage on selling price","cost price, selling price and fixed percentage on cost price","cost priceand fixed percentage on cost price","cost price and fixed percentage on selling price"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The major point of agreement carried by the partnership deed is?","options":["5% interest annum on any loan","an oral agreement among the partners","method of inhertance by the partners' children","the profit and loss sharing ratio of the partners"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 40 and 41.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nKeme and Kemi are in partnership sharing profit and losses in the ratio 3:2.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital  - Keme.............N20 000<br>\r\n........ - Kemi.............N10 000<br>\r\nDrawings - Keme.............N2  000<br>\r\n........ - Kemi.............N3  000<br>\r\nProfit......................N6  000<br>\r\nInterest on capital.........5%<br>\r\nInterest on drawings........10%<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe interest on Kemi's capital is?","options":["N1 000","N2 000","N500","N3 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The interest on Keme's drawings is calculated as?","options":["N200","N150","N300","N100"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Which of the following can be used on admission of a new partnership?","options":["Revaluation account","Profit account","Capital account","Trading account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Goodwill is determined using?","options":["capital contribution","number of partnerd admitted","the business and customer relations","number of active partners"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The founders of a company are?","options":["promoters","shareholders","canvassers","stakeholders"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The fund in which all government receipt are paid is?","options":["consolidated revenue fund","development fund","trust fund","contingency fund"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Which of the following accounts for the highest revenue to Nigeria?","options":["Import duties","Personal income tax","Petroleum income tax","Company tax"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"If Aboki Holdings Limited issued 120, 000 ordinary share of N2.00 each at market value of 5.50k each, the share premium would?","options":["N500 000","N450 000","N550 000","N420 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Which of the following is a signatory to federal government account?","options":["Auditor-General","Governor of Central Bank","Accountant-General","Persident"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The chief accounting officer of a local government is the?","options":["Chairman","Treasurer","Director of personnel","Auditor"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Which of the following signs general warrant for the release of money from the consolidated revenue fund?","options":["Minister of Finance","Chairman, Economic Advisory Committee","Permanent secretary","Minister of Economic Planning"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Find the average stock for the period","options":["N27 000","N23 000","N28 000","N20 500"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Calculate the cost of goods sold.","options":["N61 000","N58 000","N62000","N57 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The major function of accounting bodies in Nigeria is to?","options":["provide proper financial management of businesses","provide good remuneration to the members","promote the ethics of the profession","show the dynamic nature of the profession"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Ledger  account is mainly classified into?","options":["nominal, real and personal accounts","fixed and current accounts","management, financial and public sector  accounting","bank and cash accounts"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"If salary account is debited instead of stationery account, the error committed is that of?","options":["commission","omission","principle","compensation"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"If stationery bought for N200 has been entered as N2000. To correct this error?","options":["debit stationery with N2,200","credit stationery with N1,800","debit stationery with N1,800","credit stationery with N2,200"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The account which refers to the tangible assets of a company that is of permanent nature is the?","options":["personal account","real account","nominal account","cash account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Th major feature of an invoice is that, it?","options":["passes information through the sales day book","has cash and bank column","specifies the particular of goods bought","indicates only the cash sales"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The source documents include?","options":["cash book","petty cash book","general ledger","credit notes"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"A major cause of discrepancy between bank statement and the cash book that overstates the bank statement balance is the?","options":["commission paid","interest received","direct payment","direct withdrawal"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The bank charges levied on a current account holder is the charge on?","options":["transaction","turnover","transfer","cash received"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The course of discrepancies between the bank statement and the cash book that overstates the cash book is the?","options":["dividend received","uncredited expenses","uncredited cheques","interest on lodgement"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question 14 and 15.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSales....................................N10,900<br>\r\nStock 1\/1................................N1, 000<br>\r\nStock 31\/12..............................N2, 000<br>\r\nPurchases................................N4, 000<br>\r\nReturns outwards.........................N800<br>\r\nReturns inwards..........................N600<br>\r\nCarriage outwards........................N300<br>\r\nCarriage inwards.........................N200<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind the gross profit.","options":["N7 800","N7 900","N9700","5700"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The cost of goods available for sale is?","options":["N4 600","N5 000","N6 400","N4 400"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Benefit enjoyed for which payments have not been made are?","options":["accruals","prepayments","acquisitions","provisions"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 16 and 17.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSundry debtor..................N20,000<br>\r\nProvision for bad debts........N500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProvision for bad debt at 4% of sundry debtors.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the provision for bad debts to profit and loss account?","options":["N500","N820","N1300","N300"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Calculate the provision to be taken to the balance sheet?","options":["N780","N800","1200","N200"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"If an organization maintains a periodic stock system, the stock quantities are?","options":["updated at the end of the accounting year","not considered inthe updating process","updated continuously","updated at the beginning of the accounting year"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"If a company values its stock in the period of rising prices using LIFO method, there is a tendency for it to?","options":["have a higher cost of goods sold","have a higher gross profit","pay higher gross profit","have a higher value for closing stock"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 23 and 24.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n............................31\/12\/07.......31\/12\/08<br>\r\nStocks........................N4 200.........N3 900<br>\r\nRates in advance..............N1 000.........N1 500<br>\r\nAccrued wages.................N1 150.........N1 350<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCost of goods sold was valued at N6 000.<br>\r\nCash paid for rates and wages during the year was N1 300 and N2 200 respectively.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the value of purchases for the year 2008?","options":["N6 000","N9 900","N14 100","N5 700"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 25 and 26.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n........................31\/12\/08...........31\/12\/09<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFurniture and fittings..N21 000,............N28 000<br>\r\nOffice equipment........N9 800,.............N13 200<br>\r\nDebtors.................N6 800,.............N5  200<br>\r\nCreditors...............N4 900,.............N5  100<br>\r\nCash at bank............N7 000,.............N4  600<br>\r\nAccrued electricity bills...................N1  200<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMonthly drawings average N330.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind the opening capital?","options":["N39 700","N35 900","N35 740","N43 660"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Determine the net profit ?","options":["N5 000","N3 960","N1 040","N8 960"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The gross loss on manufacturing is always transferred to the?","options":["credit side of balance sheet","debit side of profit and loss account","credit side of profit and loss account","debit side of balance sheet"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The depreciation on a motor vehicle that is being used for manufacturing and administration is charged to the?","options":["debit side of manufacturing and profit and loss  account","debit side of profit and loss account only","credit side of profit and loss account only","debit side of manufacturing and balance sheet"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The prime cost is the total of the?","options":["production cost + selling expenses","direct material + direct labour + direct expenses","direct material + work overhead expenses","administrative expenses  + selling + distribution expenses"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"In the not-for-profit-making organization, the excess of income over expenditure is?","options":["deducted from the capital","added to the accumulated fund","added to the capital","deducted from the the accumulated fund"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The equivalent of a club's receipts and payment account is the?","options":["trading account","revenue account","cash account","suspense account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The summary of receipts ans payments account represent?","options":["cash at hand","journal proper","general journal","ledger accounts"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The Akachala Limited has four department W, X Y and Z. The profits or loss of the departments were N20 000 loss, X N25 profit, Y were N30 000 loss and Z N1800 profit. How much is the net profit or loss of the company?","options":["N7 000 loss","N5 000 loss","N5 000 profit","N7 000 profit"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"If goods were returned to branch by the customers, the correct posting for this transaction is to debit?","options":["branch debtor's account and credit head office account","head office account and credit branch stock account","branch stock account and credit branch debtors'  account","branch cash account and credit branch stock account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The branch expenses paid by the head office is recorded in the books by debiting branch?","options":["bad debt account and crediting branch  debtor's account","expenses account and crediting bank account","profit and loss account and crediting  branch stock account","discount allowed account and crediting branch debtors'  account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Goods returned to branch by customers is recorded in the head office books be debiting?","options":["bank account and crediting branch stock account","goods sent to branch account  and crediting branch debtors''account","branch stock account and crediting branch debtors account","branch debtors' and credting cash acount"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Which of the following is mostly used in treating partners' current earnings?","options":["Savings account","Current account","Capital account","Share capital account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The salary of a partner is usually debited to the?","options":["sundry debtors' account","appropriation account","profit and loss account","suncry current account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The rules which govern the internal management of a firm and its financial affairs in a partnership business is a?","options":["memorandum","bye-law","deed","financial regulation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The interest on partners' loans is?","options":["debited in current account","credited in profit and loss account","debited in profit and loss account","credited in current account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The capital contribution by the partners is treated in the?","options":["current account","capital account","trading account","balance sheet"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nN6 000 10% preference shares of N0.50 each <br>\r\nN6 000 ordinary shares of N1 each <br>\r\nCapital reserves N2 700 000<br>\r\nLong-term liabilities N4 000 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind the value of authorized share capital?","options":["13 000 000","12 000 000","9 000 000","15 700 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The directors' salaries paid are items of?","options":["current liabilities","profit and loss account","trading account","current account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Sundry debtors in the balance sheet of Onoja Bakery and Sons totaled N800.<br>\r\nA provision of 2% was made for discount and 5% provision for bad and doubtful debts.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind the amount for sundry debtors after provision?","options":["N760 000","N744800","N744 000","N784 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The financial plan of the government for a year is contained in the?","options":["budget","cash analysis book","vote book","gazette"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"An ordinary share of N80 was issued at N96. The share was issued at?","options":["premium","par","discount","loss"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"An increase in government expenditure within a year is taken care of by means of?","options":["financial regulations","virement","warrant","supplementary estimate"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"As evidence of payments to a government ministry, the revenue collectors will issue?","options":["treasury receipt","receipts vourcher card","treasury card","stores receipts vourcher"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"How much rent is apportioned to department K?","options":["N1200","N1800","N2000","N750"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"How much selling and distribution expenses is apportioned to department M?","options":["N 800","N 600","N400","N1800"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Credit sales is given at 160% of cash received.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the balance c\/d?","options":["N333 000","N234 000","N343 000","N243 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"When Your Silence Is Loud..& Your Eyes Speaking Volumes..<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the value of credit sales","options":["N484 000","N448000","N584 000","N558 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"If Fatima was granted a discount of 2% what will be discount allowed?","options":["N20","N40","N60","N4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Calculate the cash balance after the discount","options":["N2760","N4 300","N6 200","N2.400"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Which of the following branches of accounting was first developed?","options":["Cost accounting","Financial acounting","Management accounting","Petroleum accounting"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The accounting convention which states that the performance of a business should be determined by matching all expenses against revenues is?","options":["accruals","materiality","objectivity","periodicity"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The process of bookkeeping includes records produced from?","options":["ledgers","source documents","minutes of meeting","imtuitive reasoning"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Musa, a prepaid customer of XYZ and KLM, bought N1500 recharge card from XYZ, and N2000 recharge recharge card from KLM, for business calls. The entry to record these transaction is debit?","options":["telephone N3,500 credit XYZ and KLM, N3,500","telephone N3,500, credit cash N3,500","sundries N3,500, credit KLM N3,500","sundries N3,500, credit telephone N3,500"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital...............................N2375 000<br>\r\nDebtors...............................N495  000<br>\r\nMotor vehicle.........................N870  000<br>\r\nCreditors.............................N245  000<br>\r\nPrepayment............................N500  000<br>\r\nBills receivable......................N505  000<br>\r\nFurniture.............................N150  000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the total debit for the trial balance?","options":["N4 690 000","N2 620 000","N2 520 000","N1 565 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"If Odukoya takes money out of business bank account for his own private use, the effect of the transaction is?","options":["increase in assets and increase in capital","increase in assets and decrease in capital","decrease in capital and increase in assets","decrease in capital and decrease in assets"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Use the information to answer below to answer questions 7 and 8.<br>\r\n<br>\r\ni  Operating machines <br>\r\nii Furniture <br>\r\niii Fixtures and fitting <br>\r\niv Loan from friends <br>\r\nV  Creditors <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat are the current liabilities?","options":["i and ii","iv and v","iii and v","ii and iv"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Find the fixed assets?","options":["i, ii and v","i, ii and iv","i, ii and iii","iii, iv and v"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Use the information above to answer question 9 and 10.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPeriod 1:<br>\r\n........Cash to petty cashier.............N1000<br>\r\n........Petty cashier pays out............N780<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPeriod 2:<br>\r\n........Petty cashier pays out............N840<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf the float is increased to N1200, how much should the petty cashier receive after period 2?","options":["160","840","1000","1040"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"What is the balance of cash with the petty cashier at the end of period 1?","options":["220","780","980","1780"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Cash discount is often recorded on?","options":["the debit side of the cash book","the credit side of the cash book","the folio column of the cash book","both credit and debit side of the cash book"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The standing order is a payment instruction given by a?","options":["customer to the bank","bank to the customer","bank to an employee","customer to a fellow customer"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Which of the should not be added or subtracted from the bank statement balance to determine the adjust cash balance?","options":["Error by the bank","Undercasting of the cash book","Overcasting of the cash book","Bank service charges"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBalance as per cash book...................N20,000<br>\r\nUnpresented cheques........................N5, 200<br>\r\nDirect credit to the bank..................N1, 000<br>\r\nDirect debit from the bank.................N1, 000<br>\r\nCredit in the cash book....................N500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the balance as bank statement at the end of the year?","options":["N24,700","N25,200","N26,200","N27,700"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 17 and 18.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTotal current assets..................N2,000<br>\r\nTotal fixed assets....................N4,000<br>\r\nCurrent liabilities...................N1,200<br>\r\nDrawings..............................N200<br>\r\nLong-term loan........................N2,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the capital of the business?","options":["N9,400","N6,000","N3,400","N3,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"What is the  net working capital?","options":["N2,600","N1,800","N800","N600"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Which of the following items are current assets?","options":["Stock, bills receivable, cash and debtors","Stock, bill receivable, cash and debtors","Stock, bad debt, bills receivable and cash","Stock, work-in-progress, cash and bills payable"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 20 and 21.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJan. 1   Received 1,000 units at N10 each<br>\r\nJan. 2   Received 2,000 units at N12 each<br>\r\nJan. 3   Issued   1,500  units <br>\r\nJan. 4   Received 1,000 units at N11 each<br>\r\nJan. 5   Issued   1,000  units<br>\r\n<br>\r\nUsing FIFO method, what is the value of the closing stock?","options":["N34,000","N29,000","N17,000","N12,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"What is the value of closing stock using simple average?","options":["N11,500","N17,000","N17,500","N28,500"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Which of the following methods gives a conservative closing stock value during a period of rising prices?","options":["LIFO","FIFO","Simple average","Periodic simple average"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Apart from the common control accounts, a control account can also be opened for?","options":["sales account","purchases account","cash account","wages account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Which of the following is a debit item in the purchases ledger control account.","options":["Balance b\/d","Cheque dishonoured","Purchases","Balance c\/d"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Which of the following is an item in the debit side of the sales ledger control account?","options":["Interest charged by suppliers","Bills receivable honooured","Transfer of credit balances from credit control account","Transfer of debit balance from creditors  control account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The cost incurred by departments that support the production departments with such activities as maintenance, production control and storage are called?","options":["autonomous costs","service costs","supporting cost","subsidiary costs"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 29 and 30.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWork-in-progress 1\/1........................N1,000<br>\r\nWork-in-progress 31\/12......................N2,000<br>\r\nProduction cost of goods manufactured.......N20,000<br>\r\nSales.......................................N50,000<br>\r\nStock of finished goods 1\/1.................N4,000<br>\r\nStock of finished goods 31\/12...............N5,000<br>\r\nSelling and distribution expenses...........N2,000<br>\r\nAdministrative expenses.....................N1,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the gross profit?","options":["49,000","48,000","31,000","30,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"What is the net profit?","options":["N46,000","N45,000","N28,000","N27,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Receipt and payments account is a summary of the?","options":["budget","trading account","cash book","profit and loss account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFurniture and fittings..................N20,000<br>\r\nEquipment...............................N15,000<br>\r\nBank overdrafts.........................N6, 500<br>\r\nBar creditors...........................N4,800<br>\r\nSubscription in arrears.................N4,700<br>\r\nSubscription in advance.................N650<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the accumulated fund?","options":["23,700","27,750","29,650","51,650"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"i   Space occupied by each department.<br>\r\nii  Average value of stock held by each department.<br>\r\niii Departmental turnover.<br>\r\niv  Number of articles sold by each department .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the information above, the two most logical bases for apportioning expenses that are common to departments are?","options":["i and ii","i and iii","ii and iii","iii and iv"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Use the information to answer questions 334 and 35.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.........................Departments<br>\r\n...........................P..........Q...........R<br>\r\nSales value...............N?........N23,400....N?<br>\r\nSelling expenses..........N1,100....N1,400.....N1,280<br>\r\nAdministrative expenses...N1,400....N1,000.....N1,020<br>\r\nCost of sales.............N6,900....N6,700.....N5,500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSales value of department Q doubles that of p, which is 1\/3 of R.  Depreciation which amounts to N1,800 is to be apportioned among the three departments in the ratio 3:5:7 respectively.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the sales value of department R?","options":["N7,800","N11,700","N23,400","N35,100"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Determine the total expenses of department P?","options":["9,760","9,400","2,860","2,500"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"One of the purposes of maintaining the account of a branch at the head office is to?","options":["record charges in shareholdings","record charges in liabilities","check the excesses of customers","check the excesses of members of staff"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Which of the following is a common cause of a discrepancy between head office and branch trial balance?","options":["Debtors and cash in transit","Creditors and cash in transit","Stock and cash in transit","Stock and prepayments"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Sule and Ahmad are in partnership sharing profits and losses equally. If Khadija is admitted as new partner tot take 1\/5 as her share, what is the new partner to take 1\/5th as share, what is the new profit or loss sharing ratio?","options":["Sule 1\/3, Ahmad 1\/3 and Khadija 1\/3","Sule 1\/5, Ahmad 15 and Khadija 3\/5","Sule 2\/5, Ahmad 2\/5 and Khadija 1\/5","Sule 2\/5, Ahmad 1\/5 and Khadija 2\/5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNet profit b\/d.....................N10,000<br>\r\nInterest on capital:...M...........N2, 000<br>\r\n.......................K...........N1, 000<br>\r\nPartners' on salary....K...........N800<br>\r\nInterest on drawings...M...........N500<br>\r\nProfit sharing ratio M and K 3:2<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine M's share of profit?","options":["6,280","4,020","2,820","2,280"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Use the information to answer questions 40 and 41.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital balances b\/d:.....P.............N20,000<br>\r\n..........................K.............N10,000<br>\r\nDrawings:.................P.............N2, 000<br>\r\n..........................K.............N1, 000<br>\r\nShare of profits:.........K.............N4, 000<br>\r\n..........................K.............N2, 000<br>\r\nSalary....................P.............N1, 000<br>\r\nInterest on drawings:.....K.............N100<br>\r\n..........................K.............N20<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAssuming that the partnership maintains a fixed capital, what is P's closing capital?","options":["N25,000","N24,900","N22,900","N20,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"In a partnership account, conversation of non-cash assets into cash is referred to as?","options":["realization","disposal","dissolution","revaluation"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 43 and 44.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA company advertised and issued N750,000, 12% preference shares of N1 each to be issued at N1.50 per share. Applications for N1,370,000 were received at 30k per share. 70k per share (including premium) was due om allotment while 25k per share was due on each of the remaining two calls. All amounts due were received . Application money for 120,000 shares was refunded to unsuccessful applicants were allotment shares on pro-rata basis.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe share premium account would be?","options":["credited with application and allotment N187, 500","debited with appllication and allotment N375,000","credited with application and allotment N375, 000","debited with application and allotment N187, 500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The second and final call account was debited with?","options":["ordinary share capital account N187,500","12% preference share capital N375,000","bank account N187,500","12% preference share capital account N187,500"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Provision for bad and double debts in companies final accounts is treated in?","options":["trading account","profit and loss account","fund flow statement","cash flow statement"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The book value per share is obtained by dividing?","options":["shareholders equity by outstanding shares","total assets by outstanding shares","gross profit by outstanding shares","net profit by outstanding shares"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Expenditure incurred on consumables and goods for resale is?","options":["revenue expenditure","capital expenditure","sunk cost","miscellanous expenses"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Replacement and renewal of fixed assets are?","options":["revenue receipt","capital receipt","capital expenditure","revenue expenditure"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Which of the following is credited to the consolidated revenue fund?","options":["Recurrent expenditure","Capital expenditure","Transfer to revenue fund","International revenue"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"One of the reasons for the existence of the public sector is to?","options":["Take adequate care of the needy","supplement the commerical sector","provide cheap services to all citizens","correct perceived inequalities"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"If the gross profit margin is 10% what is the value of the cost of goods sold?","options":["N10,000","N90,000","N105,600","N110,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"If the opening stock is 5% of sales. calculate the purchases","options":["N95,600","N95,000","N9,600","N85,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Use the information to answer the question.<br>\r\n..........................30\/9\/06.......30\/9\/07.....<br>\r\n............................N.............N.........<br>\r\nAccrued insurance premium...600...........710.......<br>\r\nPrepaid rent income.........490............630......<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe cash book includes N1,850 and N,2,100 in respect of insurance premium and rent income respectively.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe insurance premium to be taken to the profit and loss account would be.","options":["N1,340","N1,850","N1,990","2,210"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Use the information to answer the question.<br>\r\n..........................30\/9\/06.......30\/9\/07.....<br>\r\n............................N.............N.........<br>\r\nAccrued insurance premium...600...........710.......<br>\r\nPrepaid rent income.........490............630......<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe cash book includes N1,850 and N,2,100 in respect of insurance premium and rent income respectively.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat amount is to be credited to the profit and loss account in respect of rent income?","options":["N1,710","N1760","N2000","N2240"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"One of the major features of bookkeeping is that it?","options":["provides permanent records for all financial transactions","is futuristic in nature","accpets responsibility for all wrong postings","does not give room for double entry procedures"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Which of the following accounting conventions suggests that accountants should use a method of valuation that understates rather than over-states results?","options":["Conservatism","Historical","Monetary","Cost"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A financial analyst needs accounting information to?","options":["maintain the production section of the business","know why transactions cause increase and decreases in assets","advise on how to manage the business","know how to record transaction in T account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"One basic assumption of the double entry theory is that it allows?","options":["two credit entries at the same time","two debit entries at the same time","debit and credit two credit entries at the same time","debit and credit two credit entries in corresponding account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSales.....................N4000<br>\r\nLight expenses............N2900<br>\r\nRent......................N1500<br>\r\nPurchases.................N7500<br>\r\nDebtors...................N6000<br>\r\nCreditors.................N29000<br>\r\nDrawings..................N25<br>\r\nBank......................N400<br>\r\nGeneral expenses..........N1500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the total of trial balance?","options":["N64 300","N46 825","N41 850","N33 325"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Bariga, a stock broker bought stationery for N 12000 by cash. To record this transaction, debit?","options":["cash and credit stationery","purchase and credit stationery","stationery and credit cash","stationery and credit purchases"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions .<br>\r\n<br>\r\n(i) Cash at bank  (ii) Cash in hand  (iii) Premises<br>\r\n(iv) Land  (v)Creditors (vi)loan from friends\/bank.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the fixed assets?","options":["i and v","ii and iv","ii and vi","iii and iv"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions .<br>\r\n<br>\r\n(i) Cash at bank (ii) Cash in hand (iii) Premises<br>\r\n(iv) Land (v)Creditors (vi)loan from friends\/bank.<br>\r\nWhat are the current assets?","options":["i and ii","i and v","ii and iv","iii and v"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n................Cash Book........................<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital..........N6  500........purchases.....N12 250<br>\r\nSales............N30 000........Rent..........N9  100<br>\r\n................................Motor vehicle.N2  400<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind the bank balance?","options":["N71 250 credit","N71 250 debit","N95 000 credit","N95 000 debit"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"An entry made in bank column of cash book to record movement of cash between the office and the bank is the?","options":["real entry","special entry","direct entry","contra entry"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Abba offers 5% cash discount on goods worth N10 000, The discount allowed account is to be?","options":["debited with N10 000","credited with N10 000","debited with N500","credited with N500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Commission-on-turnover is charged on?","options":["current accounts only","savings accounts only","fixed deposit accounts only","all bank accounts"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The medium that enables the ATM to read the account details and process transaction directly with the account held in the bank is the?","options":["smart card","communication network","magnetic strip","computerized account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital.......N12 700........Purchases......N7 100<br>\r\nDebtors.......N4  000........Stationery.....N1 900<br>\r\nSales.........N2  400........Wages..........N1 230<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe owners  wishes to maintain an account equal to of capital as drawings.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the amount withdrawn?","options":["N9525","N9000","N7100","N6400"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} <br>\r\n\\text{Capital} & 12,700 & \\text{Purchases} & 7,100 \\\\ <br>\r\n\\hline <br>\r\n\\text{Debtors} & 4,000 & \\text{Stationery} & 1,900 \\\\<br>\r\n\\hline<br>\r\n\\text{Sales} & 2,400 & \\text{Wages} & 1,230 \\\\<br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the closing balance of the cash book?","options":["N655 credit","N655 debit","N130 credit","N130 debit"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The factor that determine the periodic depreciation charge are?","options":["asset cost, market value and useful life","asset cost, market value and residusl value","asset value, cash value  useful life","asset cost, salvage and useful life"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAug. 1  Received 20 units at N60 each<br>\r\nAug. 6  Received 20 units at N68 each<br>\r\nAug. 10 Issued  16  units <br>\r\nAug. 20 Received 40 units at N80 each<br>\r\nAug. 31 Issued   48 units<br>\r\n<br>\r\nUsing the simple average method, what is the cost per unit of the closing stock?","options":["N80","N74","N64","N60"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAug. 1  Received 20 units at N60 each<br>\r\nAug. 6  Received 20 units at N68 each<br>\r\nAug. 10 Issued  16  units <br>\r\nAug. 20 Received 40 units at N80 each<br>\r\nAug. 31 Issued   48 units<br>\r\n<br>\r\nUsing the FIFO method, what is the value of the closing stock?","options":["N1280","N1184","N1024","N960"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"In a period of inflation, which of the following method normally gives a closing closing stock?","options":["FIFO","LIFO","Sinple average","periodic simple average"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The main purpose of control account is to?","options":["detect errors and irregularities","assist purchases","assist sales","check management incompetence"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Which of the following is a credit item in creditors ledger control account?","options":["Purchases returns","Bills payable","Purchases","Cash receipts"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Discount allowed as represented in the control account appears on the?","options":["credit side of the purchases control account","debit side of the purchases control account","credit side of the sales control account","debit side of the sales control account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Use the information  below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.........................31 Dec. 05........31 Dec. 06<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTotal fixed assets.........N7  800............N6 600<br>\r\nTotal current assets.......N12 100............N17800<br>\r\nTotal current liabilities..N4  700............N3 800<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDrawings for 2006 is N5 200.<br>\r\nDetermine the capital balance as at Dec. 31,2005?","options":["N20 600","N15 200","N13 800","N11 600"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.........................31 Dec. 05........31 Dec. 06<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTotal fixed assets.........N7 800............N6 600<br>\r\nTotal current assets.......N12 100............N17800<br>\r\nTotal current liabilities..N4 700............N3 800<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDrawings for 2006 is N5 200.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the  net profit for 2006?","options":["N19 000","N16 000","N12 600","N10 600"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The floor space occupied by manufacturing and administration departments in a company is 200 sqm and 300 sqm respectively. N20 000 rent incurred is shared using floor space occupied. How much is the rent chargeable to manufacturing?","options":["N8  000","N10 000","N12 000","N18 000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock of material 1\/1..............N10  000<br>\r\nPurchase of raw material...........N160 000<br>\r\nManufacturing wages................N420 000<br>\r\nRoyalties..........................N3   000<br>\r\nStock of raw materials 31\/12.......N14  000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the cost of raw materials consumed?","options":["N173 000","N170 000","N160 000","N156 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock of material 1\/1..............N10 000<br>\r\nPurchase of raw material...........N160 000<br>\r\nManufacturing wages................N420 000<br>\r\nRoyalties..........................N3 000<br>\r\nStock of raw materials 31\/12.......N14 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the prime cost?","options":["N597000","N579000","N576000","N5967000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Receipt and payment account discloses?","options":["debtors","creditors","prepayment","depreciation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSubscription in arrears 01\/10\/06...........N2 000<br>\r\nSubscription in advance 01\/10\/06...........N1 500<br>\r\nSubscription paid during the year..........N7 000<br>\r\nSubscription in arrears 31\/12\/06...........N3 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the amount of subscription included in the income and expenditure account for the year?","options":["N3500","N7000","N9500","N13 500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The main reason for adopting a departmental account is to?","options":["record transactions for each department for betterdocumentation","tackle any recording problem as a result of expansion","continuously evaluate the profitability of different departments","ensure that departmental mangers are adequately monitored"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n(i)   Cost price (ii) Selling price (iii) Cost plus fixed percentage (iv) Price above cost and selling price<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the information above, the prices used in charging goods to the branches are?","options":["i and ii","i, ii and iii","i, ii, iii and iv","iii and iv"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If a GSM operator based in Lagos supplies recharge cards to its branch in Akure, the head office can charge the goods at?","options":["selling price","Akure price","company price","Lagos price"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital:..G...........N5 000<br>\r\n..........T...........N8 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDrawings: G...........N2 000<br>\r\n..........T..........N1 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nInterest on capital..10%<br>\r\nInterest on Drawings..5%<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind the interest on drawings of G?","options":["N50","N100","N200","N250"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The entry in the partnership books of accounts for interest on drawings is to?","options":["credit partners capital account","debit partners capital account","credit drawings account","debit drawings account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"In partnership dissolution, an asset taken over by a partner is debited to?","options":["partners capital account and credited to realization account","Partners capital account and credited to asset account","asset account and credited to realization account","realization account and credited to capital account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Goodwill can be in the balance sheet as?","options":["fixed tangible asset","current asset","fictitious asset","liquid asset"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Cash received from the subscribed shares is recorded by debting?","options":["application, allotment  and crediting cash","allotment and crediting cash","cash and crediting subscribed shares","cash, crediting application and allotment account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Ordinary shareholders received dividend before?","options":["creditors","debtors","preference shareholders","deferred shareholders"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A source of revenue that is compulsory payment without any derived benefit is?","options":["fees","taxes","fines","royalties"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The salary of the chief Justice of the Federation is paid from the?","options":["consolidated revenue fund","development fund","contigency fund","special fund"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Which of the following is among the categories of government cash book?","options":["Receipt cash book","Payment cash book","Petty cash book","Treasury cash book"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The Auditor General of the Federation can be removed by the?","options":["National Assembly","Chief Justice","The president","Head of Service"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Given that the balance as per cash book after adjustment was N6315, nu-presented cheques N1000 and the bank statement balance N3240. What was the balance of the nu-credited cheques?","options":["N4075","N4240","N3315","N3075"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Use this information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTrading Account (Extract)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.................N.............................N......<br>\r\nOpening stock...19500........Sales............96 000..<br>\r\nAdd purchases...68700.................................<br>\r\n................88200.................................<br>\r\nLess closing stock..?.................................<br>\r\nCost of goods sold..?.................................<br>\r\nGross profit C\/D....?.................................<br>\r\n....................?..........................?......<br>\r\nThe gross profit margin is 20%<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the gross profit?","options":["N88 200","N76 800","N 19 200","N12 900"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Use this information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTrading Account (Extract)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.................N.............................N......<br>\r\nOpening stock...19500........Sales............96 000..<br>\r\nAdd purchases...68700.................................<br>\r\n................88200.................................<br>\r\nLess closing stock..?.................................<br>\r\nCost of goods sold..?.................................<br>\r\nGross profit C\/D....?.................................<br>\r\n....................?..........................?......<br>\r\nThe gross profit margin is 20%<br>\r\nDetermine the closing stock","options":["N76 800","N67 800","N14 100","N11 400"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Give:<br>\r\n1. Ascertainment of the particulars of the proposed company<br>\r\nII. Preparation of the incorporation documents<br>\r\nIII. Filling of the documents<br>\r\nIV. Registration of the company <br>\r\nFrom the information above, the stages involved in the formation of a company are","options":["I, II and III","I, II, III and IV","I,IIand  IV","II, III and IV"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The debit ratio is approximately","options":["43%","42%","41%","23%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Which of the following is true of Uju Nig.Ltd?","options":["It is a highly geared company","It has no liquidity problem in the short term","It is adequately secured in fixed assets","It's working capital is zero"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Goods worth N300 was transferred from department Q to P Similarly, P's total expenses for the period was N200<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat was department Q's gross profit?","options":["N2 500","N2 300","N 2 200","N1700"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Goods worth N300 was transferred from department Q to P Similarly, P's total expenses for the period was N200<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDepartment P's net profit was","options":["N5 200","N3000","N2800","N2 500"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A company has departments X, Y and Z. Department X occupies a space of Y while Z occupies half the space of Y. If the company pays N70 000 on rent, what is the amount of rent that should be allocated to Y?","options":["N30 000","N40 000","N20 000","N10 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nEntrance fees.........................N1200<br>\r\nSubscriptions(including N850 arrears).N4310<br>\r\nDonations received....................N1500<br>\r\nProceeds from sales...................N2300<br>\r\nTotal payments........................N8200<br>\r\nDepreciation..........................N2100<br>\r\nClosing cash balance..................N1110<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe club deposited 200% of the closing cash balance in he bank during the period.<br>\r\nCalculate the total figure for the receipt and payments account?","options":["N11 410","N13 630","N9 310","N11 530"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nStock at start:<br>\r\nRaw materials................N57 000<br>\r\nWork-in-progress.............N42 000<br>\r\nFinished goods...............N71 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPurchase of raw materials amount to N81 000, direct labour is N38 000 and factory overhead N29 000.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the prime cost?","options":["N176 000","N170 000","N167 000","N156 000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"(i)   Profits and looses will be shared unequally.<br>\r\n(ii)  Interest is not allowed on capital.<br>\r\n(iii) Salaries are not allowed.<br>\r\n(iv)  Interest is charged on drawings.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the above, which of the following would apply where there is no agreement  during partnership formation?","options":["i only","i, ii and iii","i, ii and iv","ii and iii"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock (1\/1\/02) at selling price..........N2000<br>\r\nGoods sent to branch (selling price).....N?<br>\r\nSales by branch (selling price)..........N4500<br>\r\nStock (31\/12\/02).........................N?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOpening stock is 1\/4 of goods sent to branch.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the closing stock?","options":["N5 500","N6 500","N2 500","N4 500"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock (1\/1\/02) at selling price..........N2000<br>\r\nGoods sent to branch (selling price).....N?<br>\r\nSales by branch (selling price)..........N4500<br>\r\nStock (31\/12\/02).........................N?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOpening stock is 1\/4 of goods sent to branch.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe value of goods sent to branch is?","options":["N4 000","N6 000","N8 000","N2 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Expense paid during the conversion of a partnership to a company are?","options":["debited to the partners' capital account","debited to the realization account","debited to the cash account","credited to the realization account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"In the trading and profit and loss account of a manufacturing organization, purchases is?","options":["always the same amount as the total factory overhead cost","given separately","equivalent to the total cost of goods manufactured","always the same as the prime cost"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Goods worth N50 000 were sent at different times from head office to the branch during the year.<br>\r\nBy the end of the period, only N40 000 worth of goods had arrived at the branch. Which of the following is correct about the treatment of this transaction?","options":["Branch should debit goods received from head ofice with N50 000","Head office should debit goods sent to branch account with N10 000","Head office should debit goods sent to branch account with N50 000","Branch should debit goods received from head office with N10 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"An accounting ratio that considers only quick assets to determine the short-term safety margin of a firm is the?","options":["fixed assets ratio","capital gearing ratio","current assets ratio","acid test ratio"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA company's authorized share capital was one million ordinary shares at N1 each. Issued 80% of its shares at N1.10 per share. 70k was payable on application, 25k on allotment, 10k due on first call and the balance on second call.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat would be the total amount received on second call?","options":["N240 000","N280 000","N40 000","N56 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nA company's authorized share capital was one million ordinary shares at N1 each. Issued 80% of its shares at N1.10 per share. 70k was payable on application, 25k on allotment, 10k due on first call and the balance on second call.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe total amount of money received on application was?","options":["N560 000","N220 000","N800 000","N1000 000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nShaku Company Ltd.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock..........................N3600 000<br>\r\nCash at hand...................N800  000<br>\r\nCash at bank...................N2400 000<br>\r\nDebtors........................N580  000<br>\r\nTrade creditors................N920  000<br>\r\nBank overdraft.................N200  000<br>\r\nTax liabilities................N600  000<br>\r\nSalary owed to staff...........N180  000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the working capital?","options":["N7380 000","N8480 000","N5480 000","N6480 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"the receipt and payment s acpunt of a not-for-profit-making organization plays a similar role in a profit-making organization as?","options":["a cash acount","a balance sheet","an income account","an expenses account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Osei and Yabo were in partnership sharing profits and losses in the ratio of 2:3. On admitting Takwa, the profit and loss sharing ratio was charged to 1:1:1. Suppose Takwa paid N30 000 for goodwill , this amount would be?","options":["credited to Takwa's current acount","debited to goodwill account","share to all the partners' capital account","credited to the old partners' capital account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The amount of subscriptions accrued is reported in the balance sheet under?","options":["fixed asset","long-term liability","current asset","current liability"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information above to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nLighting..................N2925<br>\r\nRent......................N2640<br>\r\nSalary....................N4050<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe expenses are for three different product:<br>\r\nZema, Zeta and Zera. They are appointed on the basis of population. 4500 units of the products are produced, out of which 1260 and 2060 units are for zema and zeta respectively.<br>\r\n <br>\r\nThe lighting charge to be apportioned to zema is?","options":["N891","N819","N927","N975"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information above to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nLighting..................N2925<br>\r\nRent......................N2640<br>\r\nSalary....................N4050<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe expenses are for three different product:<br>\r\nZema, Zeta and Zera. They are appointed on the basis of population. 4500 units of the products are produced, out of which 1260 and 2060 units are for zema and zeta respectively.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind the salary charged to Zera product?","options":["N1854","N1845","N1062","N1134"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The gross profit disclosed in the branch stock adjustment account represents?","options":["head office profit","unrealized profit","estimated profit","branch profit"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Partners' share of profit is credited to?","options":["a partner's current account","a partner's capital account","the profit and loss account","the profit and loss appropriation account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"A pension granted to any past president or vice-president shall be charged to the?","options":["consilidation revenue fund","special pension fund","contingency fund","development  fund"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The federal government approved N140m to local governments W, X, Y and  Z. The amount is to be shared on the basis of 40% equality, 35% population and 25% internal revenue generation. Calculate the share of local government W on equality?","options":["N35m","N14m","N56m","N28m"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Stock valuation is useful because it forms the sales department on the?","options":["price of the competing goods","prices that will affect profitability","number of goods to produce","number of goods to sell"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nAn asset was purchase for N343m in 2003. <br>\r\nThe estimated life of the asset was 3 years with a residual value of N28m.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nUsing the straight method. The depreciation of the asset in the first year was?","options":["N210m","N343m","N105m","N270m"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nAn asset was purchase for N343m in 2003.<br>\r\nThe estimated life of the asset was 3 years with a residual value of N28m.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat was the asset value at the beginning of the third year?","options":["N63m","N133m","N36m","N28m"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n <br>\r\nOpening capitaL................N7 000<br>\r\nAdditional capital.............N3 500<br>\r\nNet............................N2 500<br>\r\nClosing........................N10 250<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe drawings for the period stand at?","options":["N2570","N3750","N2500","N2570"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\n........................1\/7\/2005............30\/6\/2006<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDrawings.....................................N3 000<br>\r\nCapital.................25 000...............N42 500<br>\r\nFurniture...............6  500...............N10 200<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAdditional capital during the year amounts to 300% of  the drawings.<br>\r\nCalculate the net profit or loss made during the year.","options":["N15 100 profit","N15 100 loss","N11 500 profit","N11 500 loss"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\n........................1\/7\/2005............30\/6\/2006<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDrawings.....................................N3 000<br>\r\nCapital.................25 000...............N42 500<br>\r\nFurniture...............6  500...............N10 200<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAdditional capital during the year amounts to 300% of  the drawings.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the amount of the additional capital?","options":["N900","N900 000","N90 000","N9 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"(i) Facilitating the preparation of final accounts<br>\r\n(ii) Making the existence of error easy to detect <br>\r\n(iii)Checking the accuracy of positions periodically.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the above, which of the following are among the uses of control accounts?","options":["i, ii and iii","i and iii","ii and iii","i and ii"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nDebtors.................................N20<br>\r\nProvision for bad debts..................10%<br>\r\nProvision for discount on debtors........5%<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the amount provided for discount allowed on debtors?","options":["N1000","N3000","N900","N1500"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDebtors.................................N20<br>\r\nProvision for bad debts..................10%<br>\r\nProvision for discount on debtors........5%<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe provision for bad debt is?","options":["N2000","N800","N3000","N1900"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The purchases ledger control account showed a credit balance of N525 000 on April 30, 2006.<br>\r\nThis amount shows?","options":["what the debtor of a business enterprise owed the business","the total amount which each debtor owed the business","what a business enterprise owed its creditors","the amount whicih a business enterprise owed creditor"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPrepaid b\/f.......................N10 000<br>\r\nCash paid during the year.........N20 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe amount to be charged to the profit and loss account is?","options":["N30 000","N25 000","N5 000","20 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nNet loss.......................N2300<br>\r\nCapital........................N10500<br>\r\nLiabilities....................N7200<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind the value of the total assets?","options":["N17 700","N10 500","N20 000","N15 400"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nNet loss.......................N2300<br>\r\nCapital........................N10500<br>\r\nLiabilities....................N7200<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat  will be the equity of the business?","options":["N12 800","N4900","N8200","N9500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The process whereby a cheque received by one person is given to another is known as?","options":["cheque crossing","payment in cheque","cheque transfer","cheque endorsement"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Journal proper is used in recording?","options":["transactions that are not regular","returns from customers","credit sales","the receipt and payment for money"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nBalance as per cash book................N13560<br>\r\nUnpresented cheques.....................N5120<br>\r\nUncredited lodgements...................N2300<br>\r\nDividend received not entered<br>\r\nin the cash book........................N2000<br>\r\nBank charges............................N280<br>\r\nStanding order payments.................N600<br>\r\nBalance as per bank statement............?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the balance in the bank statement.","options":["N14 680","N15 560","17 500","16 380"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nBalance as per cash book................N13560<br>\r\nUnpresented cheques.....................N5120<br>\r\nUncredited lodgements...................N2300<br>\r\nDividend received not entered<br>\r\nin the cash book........................N2000<br>\r\nBank charges............................N280<br>\r\nStanding order payments.................N600<br>\r\nBalance as per bank statement............?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the adjusted cash book balance?","options":["N14 680","N15 560","N16 440","N17 000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The fourth stage of the accounting information system is?","options":["recording","interpreting","summarizing","classifying"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nGiven:<br>\r\nReturns inwards............N1500<br>\r\ncash.......................N1550<br>\r\nDiscount...................N2850<br>\r\nCapital....................N3800<br>\r\nDebtors....................N900<br>\r\nSundry.....................N?<br>\r\nThe value of sundry expenses is 150% of returns inwards plus 50% of debtors.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow much is sundry expenses?","options":["N2700","N2250","N1550","N2000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nGiven:<br>\r\nReturns inwards............N1500<br>\r\ncash.......................N1550<br>\r\nDiscount...................N2850<br>\r\nCapital....................N3800<br>\r\nDebtors....................N900<br>\r\nSundry.....................N?<br>\r\nThe value of sundry expenses is 150% of returns inwards plus 50% of debtors<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe total of the trial balance is?","options":["N6600","N6650","N5600","N5900"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"If Mr. Ajasin paid his creditors N5000 out of N20 000 owed, what would be the effect of this transaction on the accounting equation?","options":["A decraese in the total asssets by N5000","An incraese in the total liabilities and owners' equity by by N15 000","An increase in the total assets by N15 000","A decrease in owners' equuity by N5000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"One of the benefits of book-keeping records is that they?","options":["give prospective investors accurate and direct information for decisions-making","provide the public and creditors with details of the operations of an entity","give legal backing to all the transactions undertaken by a business entity","provide information without which the task of management would be difficult"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBank overdraft..............N2000<br>\r\nCash........................N2000<br>\r\nFurniture...................N4000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the total amount on the credit side of the trial balance?","options":["N4000","N2000","N6000","N8000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"A sole trader purchased goods in cash worth N2000 at 2% discount and made a cash sale of N1000 at the same rate of discount. Determine the amount of discount allowed?","options":["N20","N40","N400","N200"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"If cheques of N40 000 were received but a cheque of N8 000 was dishonoured, the amount owed was","options":["N9 000","N20 000","N 1000","N17 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"If the discount allowed is 2.5% of sales, calculate the closing balance in the sales ledger account","options":["N 1400","N6 600","N16 600","N18 600"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the surplus income.","options":["N45 000","N44 000","N30 000","N14 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nEntrance fees.........................N1200<br>\r\nSubscriptions(including N850 arrears).N4310<br>\r\nDonations received....................N1500<br>\r\nProceeds from sales...................N2300<br>\r\nTotal payments........................N8200<br>\r\nDepreciation..........................N2100<br>\r\nClosing cash balance..................N1110<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe club deposited 200% of the closing cash balance in he bank during the period.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the opening cash balance of the","options":["N3070","N2220","N5710","N4320"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Fatima withdraws goods from the business for personal use. the accounting treatment is to debit?","options":["stock account and credit profit and loss account","drawings account and credit stock account","profit and loss account and credit drawing  account","stock account and credit drawings account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOn January 1\/2005, a machine was bought for N56,000 to last for five years with a residual value of N1000.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the yearly depreciation expense using the straight line method.","options":["N11 000","N11 200","N11 400","N11 300"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOn January 1\/2005, a machine was bought for N56,000 to last for five years with a residual value of N1000.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nthe rate of the yearly depreciation expense would be?","options":["50%","40%","30%","20%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The objective of the purchase ledger control account is to established the?","options":["credit purchases","net profit","total purchases","gross profit"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The objective of a trading account is to establish the?","options":["cost of goods sold","gross profit","manufacturing profit","net profit"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A seller of vegetables and fruits should be encouraged to value his stock at the end of a period using the?","options":["weighted average method","simple average method","FIFO method","LIFO method"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital.....................N?<br>\r\nProfit and loss.............N3500<br>\r\nCurrent assets..............N?<br>\r\nCurrent liabilities.........N2000<br>\r\nfixed assets................N11000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe company maintains a current ratio of 3:1.<br>\r\nThe capital balance is?","options":["N95 00","N12 500","11 500","10 00"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital.....................N?<br>\r\nProfit and loss.............N3500<br>\r\nCurrent assets..............N?<br>\r\nCurrent liabilities.........N2000<br>\r\nfixed assets................N11000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the current assets?","options":["N7 000","N6 000","N8 000","N9 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The difference in the sales ledger control account is transferred to the?","options":["profit and loss account","sales account","balance sheet","trading account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Tunde purchased goods from Femi by cash worth N1000 with 10% cash discount. Tunde's  ledger control account is to be?","options":["deited by N100","credited by N100","credited by N1000","deited by N1000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"After receiving the financial statement the Auditor General of the Federation must submit a report to the National Assembly within?","options":["60 days","30 days","120 days","90 days"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Gross earnings........................N950 000<br>\r\nCurrent liabilities...................N100 000<br>\r\nOperating expenses....................N350 000<br>\r\n10% debentures........................N400 000<br>\r\nShareholder's fund....................N1300 000<br>\r\nCorporate tax is 30%<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the data above calculate the returns on equity?","options":["33%","35%","20%","30%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nTurnover...........................N120 000<br>\r\nNet profit before tax..............N40  000<br>\r\nNet profit b\/f.....................N68  000<br>\r\nProposed dividends:<br>\r\nOrdinary shares....................N8   000<br>\r\nPreference shares..................N6   000<br>\r\nCorporate tax is 30%...............N10  000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe undistributed profit carried forward is?","options":["N 68 000","N 20 000","N 74 000","N 34 000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Accrual accounting differs from cash accounting because it recognizes?","options":["cash and creditors","debtors and creditors","cash and debitors","prepayment and cash"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions Turnover...........................N120 000 Net profit before tax..............N40 000 Net profit b\/f.....................N68 000 Proposed dividends: Ordinary shares....................N8 000 Preference shares..................N6 000 Corporate tax is 30%...............N10 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the tax charged to profit and loss account?","options":["N 14 000","N 60 000","N 34 000","N 20 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A private company is different from a public company because?","options":["it does not restrict the right to transferits shares","it cannot invite members of the public to subscribe for its shares","its shares are owned by one person","it can only offer its shares to members of the publicfor subscription"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The use of a three-column cash book is determine by?","options":["cash discounts","trade discounts","cash transactions","bank transactions"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A major factor that enhanced the early development of accounting is the?","options":["Industrial Revolution","growing of trade and commerce","development of arithmetic","invention of writing"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"which of the following is source of document for the preparation of debtors' ledger account?","options":["Debit note","General journal","Purchases invoice","Sales invoice"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Stationary which will be used over a long period of time is usually recorded as an expense instead of an asset.  <br>\r\nThis concept is called?","options":["entity","materiality","realization","accrual"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Adaobi mistakenly entered N7000 as credit sales  in Abba's account. This is?","options":["an error of principles","a compensating error","an error of commission","an error omission"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital.................................N60 000<br>\r\nBank....................................N12 500<br>\r\nGeneral expenses........................N5  250<br>\r\nCreditors...............................N17 000<br>\r\nStock...................................N98 500<br>\r\nFixed assets............................N42 000<br>\r\nInsurance and rates.....................N18 800<br>\r\nPurchase................................N63 850<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the cash balance on the debit side if it is the only item omitted?","options":["N6745","N6754","N6475","N6574"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital.................................N60 000<br>\r\nBank....................................N12 500<br>\r\nGeneral expenses........................N5  250<br>\r\nCreditors...............................N17 000<br>\r\nStock...................................N98 500<br>\r\nFixed assets............................N42 000<br>\r\nInsurance and rates.....................N18 800<br>\r\nPurchase................................N63 850<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the total of the trial balance?","options":["N123 325","N160 050","N166 525","N326 575"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock of raw materials 1\/40............N11 150<br>\r\nPurchases of raw materials.............N112 550<br>\r\nRaw material returned..................N31 150<br>\r\nStock of Raw materials 31\/12\/04........N27 150<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the cost of raw materials consumed?","options":["N156 000","N38 300","N183 150","N66 550"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Use the information below were to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\n...................Stationary Dept.............Video Dept.<br>\r\nSales ..............N10,600.....................N15,175<br>\r\nCost of goods sold..N5,247......................N6704<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe expenses incurred were rent N4500, motor repairs N1200 and telephone N900.<br>\r\nThe basis of cost apportionment is 1\/2 stationary 1\/3 video.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the net profit of the business?","options":["N6600","N6271","N5353","N7224"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Use the information below were to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\n...................Stationary Dept.............Video Dept.<br>\r\nSales ..............N10,600.....................N15,175<br>\r\nCost of goods sold..N5,247......................N6704<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe expenses incurred were rent N4500, motor repairs N1200 and telephone N900.<br>\r\nThe basis of cost apportionment is 1\/2 stationary 1\/3 video.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFind the total expenses allocated to the stationary department?","options":["N3600","N1400","N4400","N3800"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Stock 1\/1\/2002..................................N40 000<br>\r\nGoods received from head office.................N800 000<br>\r\nGoods returned to head office...................N34 000<br>\r\nSales...........................................N916000<br>\r\nStock 31\/12\/2000................................N72 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the data above determine the cost of goods credited to the head office trading account.","options":["N766 000","N840 000","N734 000","N806 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPrime cost..................N12 100<br>\r\nlighting....................N10 000<br>\r\nHeating.....................N15 000<br>\r\nFactory  overhead............?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe production department share of factory overhead is 1\/4 and 1\/2 of lighting and heating  respectively.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe factory overhead is?","options":["N5050","N7250","N2750","N5500"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPrime cost..................N12 100<br>\r\nlighting....................N10 000<br>\r\nHeating.....................N15 000<br>\r\nFactory  overhead............?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe production department share of factory overhead is 1\/4 and 1\/2 of lighting and heating  respectively.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nInterest on the drawings of partners is treated in the?","options":["profit and loss appropriation account","goodwill account","profit and loss account","trading account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Departmentalization of accounts is useful because it shows the?","options":["overall performance of a firm","price per unit of a product","cost per unit of a product","overall performance of a division"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"When goodwill is not retained in the business, the entries in the new partners' book will be to debit?","options":["good account and credit partners' capital account","partners' capital account and credit goodwill  account","cash account and credit goodwill account","goodwill account and credit cash account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n....................January.............December<br>\r\nAssets................N28,320.............N25,320<br>\r\nCreditors.............N5,620..............N10,320<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe proprietor made drawings of N755 per month for personal use.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe profit for the period is?","options":["N3000","N1,360","N9060","N7700"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSubscriptions received.........N200 000<br>\r\nSubscriptions owed.............N10  000<br>\r\nSubscriptions in advance.......N25  000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the subscription in the income and expenditure account?","options":["N200 000","N235 000","N185 000","N225 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Boro Limited apportion 1\/6 of its rent  for factory and 10% of the balance for warehouse. If rent paid is N48 600, how much is paid for warehouse?","options":["N4000","N6000","N10000","N8000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"MPOBA Club's annual donations from members amount to 112% of its internally generated revenue from the following.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSales of drinks...................N212 500<br>\r\nAnnual dues.......................N112 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow much is the total receipt of the club?","options":["N563 440","N687 940","N363 440","N524 500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"In converting  a to a partnership company, the loss on asset revaluation is?","options":["debited to the revaluation account","debited to the profit and loss account","credited to the revaluation account","credited to the profit and loss account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Determine the opening cash balance of the club?","options":["N3 070","N2 220","N5 710","N4 320"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The subscriptions received represent 80% of total payments and the opening balance is 30% of gate-fee collections.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the closing cash balance?","options":["N35 000","N211 000","N5 000","N10 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The subscriptions received represent 80% of total payments and the opening balance is 30% of gate-fee collections.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe subscriptions received would be","options":["N200 000","N240 000","N300 000","N24 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"LOAN IS 30% OF CREDITORS.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the capital  balance?","options":["N1000","N2 100","N900","N1200"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"LOAN IS 30% OF CREDITORS.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA company has departments S,T and U. The sales are N20 000,20 000, N40 000 AND N60 000 respectively if the sales commission paid is  N12 000, how much is T's share?","options":["N8000","N2000","N4000","N6000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Head office sends goods to its branch at cost plus mark-up of of 25%. A debit of N40,000 to the branch stock account in the head office books will indicate that the head office has sent goods with a profit of","options":["N4000","N6000","N10000","N8000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Which of the following is a journal as well as a ledger?","options":["Nominal ledger","Sales day book","General ledger","cash book"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"On Jan. 30 Khalifa withdraw N2500 from the bank for office use.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe cash balance at end of the month was","options":["N1 600","N4 100","N 6 600","N6 100"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"What was the bank balance at the end of the month?","options":["N7 000","N6 500","N 7 500","N 9 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The value of Y is","options":["N11 500","N 8 500","N13000","N10000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"X represents","options":["bank charges","an unpresented cheque","dividends","an uncredited cheque"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Assuming the closing stock was valued at N19 000 at the end of November, what was the gross profit?","options":["N30 000","N50 000","N70 000","N100 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Determine the value of closing stock using the LIFO method","options":["N2 000","N2500","N4000","N35000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The double principle of accounting was developed by?","options":["Frank Wood","Luca Pacioli","Akintola Williams","William Pickles"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The concept that has much influence over asset valuation and income determination is?","options":["entity","realization","conversactism","matching"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The journal entries for the purchase of stock on credit are to debit?","options":["stock account and credit cash account","stock account and credit liability account","ourchase account and credit liability account","suspense account and credit cash account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLiabilities..............N23,700<br>\r\nCurrent assets...........N20,300<br>\r\nFixed assets.............N64,500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the capital introduced by the proprietor?","options":["N40,800","N61,100","N88,200","N108 500"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRent..............N10,000<br>\r\nRates.............N5,000<br>\r\nCapital...........N50,000<br>\r\nSalaries..........N14,000<br>\r\nCash..............N26,000<br>\r\nCreditors..........N5,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe total trial balance is?","options":["N110,000","N65,000","N55,000","N45,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"What are the appropriate recording procedures for entries in the trial balance?","options":["source documents, ledgers and trial balance","Ledgers,  trial balance and  source documents","Ledgers,  source documents and trial balance","Cash account, ledgers and trial balance"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Mr Bassey purchased a motor vehicle for use in his business and debited the purchases account with the same value. This is an error of?","options":["omission","principle","commission","original entry"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Yahya,s bank account shows a credit balance of N1500,000. He paid N1700,000 into the bank.<br>\r\nWhat is his expected balance?","options":["Credit balance of N 200,000","Debit balance of N 200,000","credit balance of N 3 200,000","Debit balance of N3 200,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"five hundred naria monthly is allowed on an imprest system. The following transactions took place.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPeriod1:<br>\r\nCash advanced to petty cashier......N500<br>\r\nPetty cashier paid out: stamp.......N200<br>\r\nNewspaper...........................N250<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPeriod 2:<br>\r\nCash to petty cashier...............N450<br>\r\nCashier paid for writing materials..N350<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow much should the petty cashier receive after period 2?","options":["N150","N250","N350","N500"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"five hundred naria monthly is allowed on an imprest system. The following transactions took place.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPeriod1:<br>\r\nCash advanced to petty cashier......N500<br>\r\nPetty cashier paid out: stamp.......N200<br>\r\nNewspaper...........................N250<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPeriod 2:<br>\r\nCash to petty cashier...............N450<br>\r\nCashier paid for writing materials..N350<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat was the balance of cash with the petty cashier ata the end of period 1?","options":["N50","N200","N300","N450"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"In a three-column cash book,the discount allowed is shown on the?","options":["debit side","credit side","folio column","memorandum  column"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A rent received by a trader for sub-letting part of his business premises should be added to the?","options":["gross profit","total profit","net profit","total revenue"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"In a three-column cash book,the discount allowed is shown on the?","options":["debit side","credit side","folio column","memorandum  column"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Given: <br>\r\n...............................Jan.2003.........Dec. 2003<br>\r\nProvision for bad debt........N1000<br>\r\nDebtors..........................................N20000<br>\r\nBad debt to be written off.......................N2000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe provision for bad debt stands at 10% of debtors. How much is to be charged to profit and loss account as provision for bad debt?","options":["N800","N1000","N1800","N2000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Goods withdraw from business for private use are credited to?","options":["drawings","purchases","sales","capital"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Use the information to answer question .<br>\r\nA piece of equipment costing N120,000 was purchased on 1\/1\/1996. Depreciation was provided at 20% per annum on a straight-line basis. it was sold on 30\/6\/1999 for N31,500.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe accumulated depreciation provision at the time of sale was?","options":["N12 000","N60 000","N72 000","N84 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Use the information to answer question .<br>\r\nA piece of equipment costing N120,000 was purchased on 1\/1\/1996. Depreciation was provided at 20% per annum on a straight-line basis. it was sold on 30\/6\/1999 for N31,500.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe net book value of the piece of equipment at the time of sale was?","options":["N96 000","N48 000","N36 000","N24 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The item that are contained in the bought ledger control account are?","options":["discount allowed, bad debts and purchases","dishonoured cheques, returns inwards and sales","returns outwards, bad debts outewards and sales","discount received, returns outwards and purchases"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\npurchases ledger balance..............N4000<br>\r\npurchases for the period..............N50000<br>\r\nCash refunded by suppliers............N290<br>\r\nCheques paid to suppliers..............N42300<br>\r\nReturns outwards.......................N2000<br>\r\nDiscount received from suppliers.......N400<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe balance of the purchases ledger control account is?","options":["N10390","N9990","N9590","N9010"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Which of the following item is found on the credit side of the sales ledger control account?","options":["Discount received","Dishonoured cheques","Credit sals","Bills receivable"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"If the assets and liabilities of a firm were valued at N17,200 and N5,120 respectively, the capital of the firm would be?","options":["N22 320","N17 200","N12 080","5 120"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions<br>\r\n<br>\r\nZazzau Company:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCash in hand................N50<br>\r\nCash in bank................N1 250<br>\r\nStock.......................N4 880<br>\r\nFurniture...................N9 60<br>\r\nBuilding....................N5 500<br>\r\nDebtor......................N1 750<br>\r\nCreditors...................N2 150<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDrawings of N125 were made by the shareholders of the company.<br>\r\nThe capital of the company stands at?","options":["N12 240","N12 115","N2  510","N2 150"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 25 and26.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nZazzau Company:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCash in hand................N50<br>\r\nCash in bank................N1 250<br>\r\nStock.......................N4 880<br>\r\nFurniture...................N9 60<br>\r\nBuilding....................N5 500<br>\r\nDebtor......................N1 750<br>\r\nCreditors...................N2 150<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDrawings of N125 were made by the shareholders of the company.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThey company's net current assets amount to?","options":["N5 780","N5 70","N6 580","N7 930"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A component of an overhead manufacturing cost is?","options":["cost of work-in-progress","cost of finished goods","labour","rent"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nDirect labour...................N50 000<br>\r\nBeginning work-in-progress......N4  000<br>\r\nRaw materials used..............N18 000<br>\r\nIndirect labour.................N4  000<br>\r\nEnding finished goods...........N16 000<br>\r\nEnding work-in-progress.........N9  000<br>\r\nFactory supplies used...........N7  000<br>\r\nSelling expenses................N25 000<br>\r\nBeginning finished goods........N21 000<br>\r\nOther factory overheads.........N19 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the cost of goods manufactured?","options":["N117 000","N104 000","N97 000","N93 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nDirect labour...................N50 000<br>\r\nBeginning work-in-progress......N4  000<br>\r\nRaw materials used..............N18 000<br>\r\nIndirect labour.................N4  000<br>\r\nEnding finished goods...........N16 000<br>\r\nEnding work-in-progress.........N9  000<br>\r\nFactory supplies used...........N7  000<br>\r\nSelling expenses................N25 000<br>\r\nBeginning finished goods........N21 000<br>\r\nOther factory overheads.........N19 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the prime cost?","options":["N50 000","N68 000","N70 000","N75 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nPurchase:..Raw materials.................N15 000<br>\r\nFinished goods...........................N11 400<br>\r\nStock:....(1\/7\/01)Raw materials..........N2  250<br>\r\nWork-in-progress.........................N1  875<br>\r\nWages:.....Direct........................N17 100<br>\r\nIndirect.................................N5  400<br>\r\nStock:.....(30\/06\/02)Raw materials.......N3  000<br>\r\nWork-in-progress.........................N3  375<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe cost of raw materials consumed is?","options":["N17 250","N15 750","N15 000","N14 250"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nPurchase:..Raw materials.................N15 000<br>\r\nFinished goods...........................N11 400<br>\r\nStock:....(1\/7\/01)Raw materials..........N2  250<br>\r\nWork-in-progress.........................N1  875<br>\r\nWages:.....Direct........................N17 100<br>\r\nIndirect.................................N5  400<br>\r\nStock:.....(30\/06\/02)Raw materials.......N3  000<br>\r\nWork-in-progress.........................N3  375<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the cost of manufactured goods?","options":["N49 125","N48 750","N37 625","N35  250"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nPurchase:..Raw materials.................N15 000<br>\r\nFinished goods...........................N11 400<br>\r\nStock:....(1\/7\/01)Raw materials..........N2  250<br>\r\nWork-in-progress.........................N1  875<br>\r\nWages:.....Direct........................N17 100<br>\r\nIndirect.................................N5  400<br>\r\nStock:.....(30\/06\/02)Raw materials.......N3  000<br>\r\nWork-in-progress.........................N3  375<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the accumulated fund value?","options":["N9360","N6320","N4200","N3000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The not-for-profit-making organizations generate their income mainly from?","options":["bar sales","subcriptions","rents","pools"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Gamji Memorial Club carried out an activity which yield a profit of N10 000. This amount is to be transferred to the?","options":["debit side of its profit and loss account","credit side of its profit and loss account","debit side of its income and expenditure account","credit side of its income and expenditure account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Departmental accounts are prepared to aid the comparison of the?","options":["previous year's transactions","daily profits","workers' performances","management performances"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A company incurred N21 000 in running its four departments, namely J,K,L and M with a corresponding number of employees as 1500, 2000, 3000 and 500 respectively. What is the share of department K?","options":["N9000","N6000","N4500","N1500"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The movement of goods from head office to a branch is treated in the in the head office accounts as?","options":["sales","issue","purchase","requisition"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The head office of Emeka Stores maintains the financial accounts of all its branches. The branch store account in the head office serves as the branch?","options":["debtors' account","trading account","expenses account","cash account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"In reconciling the branch and head office accounts, remittance in transit in the branch books is treated as a?","options":["debit entry","credit entry","contra entry","reversal entry"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Profit or loss in a partnership is usually arrived at after deducting from gross profit all expenses including?","options":["partners'  salaries","interest on capital","partners'  drawings","interest on loans"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nJide and Haruna contribute N12000 each as capital and share profit equally. Jide draws N1500 and Haruna N1700 half-yearly. The profit for the year is N10000. Jide receives a salary of N2000.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the profit available for appreciation?","options":["N12 000","N10 000","N8 000","N7 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nJide and Haruna contribute N12000 each as capital and share profit equally. Jide draws N1500 and Haruna N1700 half-yearly. The profit for the year is N10000. Jide receives a salary of N2000.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe balances of current accounts of Jide and Haruna are respectively?","options":["N6000 and N5000","N3000 and N3400","N4000 and N4000","N3000 and N600"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"When assets are realized during a partnership dissolution, the entries for the proceeds are to debit?","options":["cash account and credit realization account","rassets account and credit realization account","realization account and credit realization account","assets account and credit  cash account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A company paid cash in redemption of N10,000 debenture. <br>\r\nThe accounting entry to record this will be to debit?","options":["cash and credit debenture","debenture and credit cash","cash and credit capital","capital and debit cash"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The accounting method that reports incomes when earned and expenses when incurred is called?","options":["cash accounting","commitment  accounting","fund accounting","accrual accounting"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The tier of government that uses financial memorandum is the?","options":["federal government","state government","local government","municipal  government"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Musa merchants Trading and profit and Loss Account for the year ended Dec.31st, 2003<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the closing stock","options":["N20 000","N30, 000","N40 000","N50,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The capital employed is","options":["N13 000","N9 900","N8 400","N9 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Determine the closing stock under LOFO method","options":["N575","N500","N375","N275"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Calculate the closing stock under FIFO method","options":["N875","N675","N600","N300"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The current ratio is","options":["1:1","2:1","2.8:1","3.5:1"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The quick ratio is","options":["1:2","1:3:1","1.7:1","3:1"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The accounting principle that is applied to check arbitrary actions on the part of accountants is?","options":["consistency","materiality","objectivity","realization"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The loss of equipment in a fire disaster results in?","options":["a decrease in current assets","an increase in liabiities and assets","a decrease in assets and capital","an increase in liabilities and a decrease in assets"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A source document is used for verifying the?","options":["amount due to creditors","actual cost of an asset","selling price of goods","amount due from debtors"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The rule of accounting equation requires that account payable should be placed under?","options":["liabilities","equities","assets","capital"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A debit in the suspense accounting will appear in the balance sheet as?","options":["a current asset","a current lability","capital","drawings"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The receipt whose name appears on a cheque is called a?","options":["payer","drawer","drawee","payee"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The imprest account is subsidiary to the?","options":["ledger account","bank account","cash book","bank column"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Zakari started a business in January 2000. He bought a shop costing N54,000 and stock worth N7,600. Profit for the year amounted to 22,100. His closing capital was N73,800.<br>\r\nZakari's personal drawings amounted to?","options":["N2,300","N9,900","N17,100","N19,500"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The balance on the provision for depreciation account is?","options":["added to fixed assets on the balance sheet","deducted from the fixed assets on the balance sheet","deducted from the profitand loss account","added to current liabilities of the account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nRates paid during the year amounted to N2,250 at N125 per month and 1,035 was paid for electricity in the same period at N115 per month.<br>\r\nDetermine the amount of prepaid rates?","options":["N345","N750","N1,380","N1,500"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Where closing stock is undervalued, the effect is?","options":["an increase in gross profit","a decrease in gross profit","an increase in purchases","a decrease in purchase"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The balancing figure in the purchases ledger control account is?","options":["N15,828","N15,720","N14,940","N14,694"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The balancing figure in the purchases ledger control account is?","options":["N15,828","N15,720","N14,940","N14,694"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 17 and 18.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOpening balance.............................N10,640<br>\r\nPurchases...................................N26,912<br>\r\nReturns inwards.............................N492<br>\r\nReturns outwards............................N810<br>\r\nCash discount received......................N1,348<br>\r\nCash discount allowed.......................N1,560<br>\r\nCash paid to suppliers......................N20,808<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt the year end, the purchases ledger showed a debit balance of N108.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe total on the debit side of the purchases ledger control account will be?","options":["N22,966","N22,156","N21,834","N21054"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"In a sales ledger, contra entry is found on the?","options":["debit side of the debtors' control account","debit side of the crebtors' control account","creadit side of the debtors' control account","creadit side of the credtors' control account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The beginning and ending accounts receivable balances were N20,000 and N30,000 respectively.<br>\r\nThe collection from customers during the period was N70,000. What was the total sale on account?","options":["N20,000","N60,000","N80,000","N120,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nGeneral expenses account.<br>\r\nPaid by cheque..................N671<br>\r\nPaid by cash....................N70<br>\r\nAccrued b\/f.....................N65<br>\r\nAccrued c\/f.....................N115<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine how much to be charged to profit and loss account?","options":["N606","N786","N791","N856"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"In converting single entry to final account, the balancing figures on the income and expenses accounts are transferred to the?","options":["revenue and expenditure account","receipts and payments account","profit and loss apporpriation account","profit and loss account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 23 and 24.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBeginning inventory............N?<br>\r\nPurchases......................N?<br>\r\nEnding inventory...............N4,800<br>\r\nSales..........................N12,800<br>\r\nWages..........................N1,040<br>\r\nGross profit...................N5,900<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe beginning inventory was estimated at 80% of sales.<br>\r\nDetermine the amount for the beginning inventory?","options":["N20,140","N10,240","N8,140","N7,240"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Cost classification in relation to charges is determined by the level of?","options":["raw materials","labour","activity","profitability"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 26 and 27.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMaterials consumed...................N16,600<br>\r\nDirect cost..........................N5,400<br>\r\nFactory rent.........................N2,300<br>\r\nFactory lighting.....................N1,200<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCost of production to be transferred at cost plus 20% mark-up.<br>\r\nThe gross profit on manufacture is?","options":["N6,120","N6,100","N5,100","N5,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The market value of goods produced is?","options":["N30,500","N30,600","N31,600","N31,620"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 28 and 29.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOn January 1,2000, a club's assets and liabilities were as follows:<br>\r\nClub house...................N8,000<br>\r\nSubscription.................N300<br>\r\nCash.........................N1,000<br>\r\nWages owed...................N100<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe club has 50 members and annual subscription is N100 per member.<br>\r\nSubscription received is N4,000 and this includes 1999 arrears of N200.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe accumulated fund is?","options":["N9,400","N9,300","N9,200","N9,100"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"In the balance sheet, the subscription in arrears will be?","options":["N200","N300","N1,200","N1,300"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Where the debit side of the income and expenditure account is higher than the credit side, the difference is a?","options":["deflicit","surplus","gain","loss"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"In the balance sheet of a not-for-profit-making organization, subscription paid in advance is regarded s a?","options":["current assets","current liability","capital","reserve"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A rapidly growing business organization with multiple units that is interested in comparing the performances and weaknesses of each unit should adopt?","options":["manufacturing accounts","consolidated accounts","departmental accounts","joint venture accounts"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"How are credit sales by a department treated?","options":["the same way as normal debtors' transactions","in a different way from normal debtors' transactions","as an addition to the production manager's  account","as an addition to the production managers' account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Discounts granted branch customers are treated as a debit to branch?","options":["stock account and a credit to branch debtors'account","discount account and a credit to branch bank account","stock account and a credit to branch bank account","discount account and a credit to branch debtors' account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Transfers from the head office to branches are best carried out at?","options":["cost price","selling price","cost plus mark-up","market price"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"On dissolution, the final distribution of cash to partners is based on?","options":["patnership agreement","Articles os asssociation","goodwill","capital balances"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 39 and 40.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJumoke and Kunle have an original investment of N25,000 and N15,000 respectively in a partnership. The articles of partnership provides 3% interest on capital and salaries of N1,500 and N1,000 respectively for the partners. The profits and losses are to be shared in the ratio 3:2.<br>\r\nMiscellaneous expenses of N2,500 were incurred with gross profit of N6,500 during the financial year.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe balance of profit and loss account will be?","options":["N4,000","N2,800","N1,500","300"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"What is Kunle's share of the profit?","options":["N600","N300","N180","N120"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"When a new partner is admitted to a partnership, there is a need to revalue the?","options":["capital of the business","capital and liabilities of the business","assets and capital of the business","assets and liabilities of the business"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The accounting entry to record the premium on goodwill is to debit?","options":["cash and credit old partners' capital","goddwill and credit revaluation","assets and credit capital","capital and credit assets"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Debentures can be redeemed out of?","options":["existing share capital reserve","existing general reserve","proceeds from new issue of shares","withholding tax"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The expenses incurred in promoting a company are?","options":["promoters' expenses","floating expenses","preliminary expenses","the borad's  expenses"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Share premium is an example of?","options":["revenue  reserve","capital  reserve","general  reserve","loan capital"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"According to the provisions of the 1999 Constitution, all revenues generated by the Federal Government must be paid into the?","options":["Consolidated Revenue Fund","Federation Account","Revenue Mobilization Allocation and Fiscal Commission's Account","Equalization Fund"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The budget statement presented to the legislature by the Chief Executive is called?","options":["an appropriation act","a budget bill","an appropriation bill","a budget proposal"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The statement of assets and liabilities in the public sector can be described as the?","options":["income and expenditure accountof government","appropriation account of government","balance sheet of government","funds flow statement of government"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"What is the value of the authorized share capital?","options":["N500,000","N600,000","N750,000","N1, 200,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The value of the owner's equity is","options":["N400,000","N900,000","N957,000","N1,357,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"What is the net profit made by department S?","options":["N3,600","N,3000","N2,400","N2,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The depreciation to be charged to department T is ?","options":["N30P00","N400","500","N600"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The owner wishes to maintain an amount equal to \\( \\frac{1}{3} \\)<br>\r\nof capital as drawings.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe amount withdrawn is","options":["N2,100","N2,200","N4,400","N6,400"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The owner wishes to maintain an amount equal to \\( \\frac{1}{3} \\)<br>\r\nof capital as drawings.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe cash book closing balance will be","options":["N900","N2,400","N4,200","N4,600"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"WHAT IS THE VALUE OF RAW MATERIALS ISSUED ON MAY 17TH BASED ON THE LIFO METHOD?","options":["N60","N61","N62","N64"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Based on the FIFO method of valuation the total cost of the raw materials issued is","options":["N150","N160","N240","N250"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Which of the following is used to update the cash book in bank reconciliation?","options":["Interest received and unpresented cheques","Commission and debit note","Unpresented cheques and direct credit","Interest received and direct credit"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The two legally recognized professional accounting bodies in Nigeria are the?","options":["Institute of Certified Public Accountants of Nigeria and  the Institute of cost and Management Accountants of Nigeria","Association of  Accountants of Nigeria and  the Institute of  Management Accountants of Nigeria","Institute of Chartered Accountants of Nigeria and the Association of National Accountants of Nigeria","Nigeria Accounting Association and the Excutive Cost and Management Accounts of Nigeria"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\nCapital ...................N2000<br>\r\nBank ......................N1200<br>\r\nPurchase ..................N2500<br>\r\nSales .....................N6700<br>\r\nStock .....................N1300<br>\r\nCreditors .................N1000<br>\r\nFixed assets...............N3700<br>\r\nDrawings ..................N?<br>\r\nDrawings are always estimated at 50% of capital.<br>\r\nThe trial balance total is?","options":["N9700","N8700","N7900","N7800"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Verifiability in accounting is only possible when there are?","options":["minutes of meetings","payment vouchers","source documents","audit certificates"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nEzekiel Malgwi is a retailer. He recorded sales representing 95% cash and 5% credit. He took the total cash sales of N19000 from the business tray and banked it.<br>\r\nThe credit sales for the period would be?","options":["N5000","N1900","N1000","N950"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nEzekiel Malgwi is a retailer. He recorded sales representing 95% cash and 5% credit. He took the total cash sales of N19000 from the business tray and banked it.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe transaction would be recorded in the cash book as debit?","options":["cash and credit bank","bank and credit cash","cash and credit cash","bank and credit bank"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Which accounting concept supports the assertion that economic reality takes precedence over legal issues?","options":["Realization  concept","Substance over form","Conservatism","Measurement concept"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The transaction that completes its double entry in the same ledger account appears in?","options":["cash account and personal account","bank account and general ledger","discount  received and discount allowed","cash account and bank accont"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The recording phase of accounting is known as?","options":["bookkeeping","trial balancing","ledger accounting","final accounting"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital ...........N1000<br>\r\nLiabilities........N500<br>\r\nAssets.............N1500<br>\r\nThe accounting equation can be expressed as?","options":["N1000 + N500 + N1500 = N3000","N1000 - N500 + N1500 = N2000","N1000 + N500 = N1500","N1500 + N500 = N2000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMotor Vehicle Account as at 31st December 2001.<br>\r\nDebit:<br>\r\nJan. 1, cost ................N1950 000<br>\r\nDec.31, Addition ............ N400 000 <br>\r\nCredit:<br>\r\nJan. 1, Depreciation ........N1360 000<br>\r\nJune 30, Sales proceeds...... N700 000<br>\r\nThe vehicle sold was purchase on January 1, 1998 at a cost of N1,000 000 and had depreciation at 25% on cost.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAssuming that depreciation is charged on the addition of the year  at the rate of 15% on reducing balance, what should be the net book value of the vehicle as at 31st December 2003?","options":["N280,000","N289,000","N250,000","N340,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMotor Vehicle Account as at 31st December 2001.<br>\r\nDebit:<br>\r\nJan. 1, cost ................N1950 000<br>\r\nDec.31, Addition ............ N400 000 <br>\r\nCredit:<br>\r\nJan. 1, Depreciation ........N1360 000<br>\r\nJune 30, Sales proceeds...... N700 000<br>\r\nThe vehicle sold was purchase on January 1, 1998 at a cost of N1,000 000 and had depreciation at 25% on cost.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the actual profit or loss arising from the vehicle disposed of?","options":["N250 000 loss","N50 000 loss","N450 000 profit","N575 000 profit"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n(i)  Order of performance <br>\r\n(ii) Order of liquidity <br>\r\n(iii)Vertical order <br>\r\n(iv) Horizontal order<br>\r\nThe order in which a balance assets is arranged are?","options":["i and ii","i and iv","ii and iii","iii and iv"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Provision for discount allowed can be recorded as debit to?","options":["the profit and loss account and a credit to provision for discount allowed","provision for discount allowed and a credit to the profit and loss account","discount allowed and a credit to the profit and loss account","expenses and a credit to customers' account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"In a control account, provision for bad debts is found on the?","options":["debit side of the purchases ledger control account","debit side of the sales ledger control account","credit side of the purchases ledger control account","credit side of the sales ledger control account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Advertising expenses incurred on a product in a business organization should be charged to?","options":["production department","sales department","administration department","purchases department"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The stock valuation data is important because it enables management to?","options":["separate debtors from creditors","determine the cost of stock at the end of business","determine the cost of stock at the beginning of business","determine the total cost of goods purchased"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"four broad classifications of overheads are?","options":["production, selling, distribution and material","production, selling, distribution and administration","selling, distribution and production and wages","distribution, selling, administration and material"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nCost of raw materials issued to production.....N37000<br>\r\nOpening stock of raw material..................N2000<br>\r\nPurchases of raw material......................N3800<br>\r\nWages .........................................N500<br>\r\nWhat is the closing stock of raw material?","options":["N4000","N3000","N2000","N1000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Income and expenditure account is more informative than receipts and payments account because it discloses?","options":["cash","cheques","debtors","stocks"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A company has two departments X and Y. Y transferred goods to X at a profit margin of 25%. N10,000 worth of goods was not sold at the end of the accounting period. <br>\r\nHow much is the unrealized profit?","options":["N2000","N2500","12000","12500"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n..............Rich Social Club...........<br>\r\nCash.........................N100,000<br>\r\nLoan ........................N30,000<br>\r\nSubscription in arrears......N5,000<br>\r\nSubscription in advance......N15,000<br>\r\nWhat is the accumulation fund?","options":["N60,000","N80,000","N90,000","N110,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"During the year ended  31st December 2001, <br>\r\nNuju Enterprises paid rent as follows:<br>\r\nJan. 20, N24 000 for a period of 4 months.  <br>\r\nMay. 16, N30 000 for a period of 5 months.<br>\r\nOct. 15, N36 000 for a period of 6 months.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the overpaid portion of the rent?","options":["N36 000","N18 000","N12 000","N6 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\n...........PQ Manufacturing  Company<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRaw materials (1\/11\/2001)...........N3 500<br>\r\nRaw materials (31\/12\/2001)..........N4 900<br>\r\nPurchase of raw materials...........N56 000<br>\r\nSalary .............................N63 000<br>\r\nWages...............................N148 000<br>\r\nFactory lighting ...................N3 080<br>\r\nPlant Depreciation..................N2 800<br>\r\nFactory Insurance ..................N2 170<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe overhead cost is?","options":["N71 050","N68 250","N67 970","N66 080"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\n...........PQ Manufacturing  Company<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRaw materials (1\/11\/2001)...........N3 500<br>\r\nRaw materials (31\/12\/2001)..........N4 900<br>\r\nPurchase of raw materials...........N56 000<br>\r\nSalary .............................N63 000<br>\r\nWages...............................N148 000<br>\r\nFactory lighting ...................N3 080<br>\r\nPlant Depreciation..................N2 800<br>\r\nFactory Insurance ..................N2 170<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe company consumed raw materials worth?","options":["N54 600","N56 000","N57 400","59 500"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A company has departments M and N. The expenses incurred wholly in M is N5000. General expenses incurred amount toN25000. Expenses are apportioned in the ratio 2:3 for departments M and N respectively. <br>\r\nWhat is N's share of the expense?","options":["N10 000","N15 000","N18 000","N20 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The first step in converting as single entry to a double entry system of bookkeeping is to prepare a?","options":["suspense account","statement of affairs","realization account","trial balance"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nTotal sales of ticket.......................N300 000<br>\r\nAmount received from the sales..............N260 000<br>\r\nCash purchase of club house.................N100 000<br>\r\nCredit purchase of equipment ...............N60  000<br>\r\nElectricity bill paid ......................N5   000<br>\r\nSalaries owed ..............................N2   000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the receipts and payment account balance?","options":["N260 000","N233 000","N155 000","N100 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nTotal sales of ticket.......................N300 000<br>\r\nAmount received from the sales..............N260 000<br>\r\nCash purchase of club house.................N100 000<br>\r\nCredit purchase of equipment ...............N60  000<br>\r\nElectricity bill paid ......................N5   000<br>\r\nSalaries owed ..............................N2   000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the balance of the income and expenditure account?","options":["N300 000","N293 000","N193 000","N133 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Receipts and payments accounts is the summary of?","options":["income and expenditure","cash book","balance sheet","profit and loss"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTotal debtors b\/d 31\/12\/99...............N25 000<br>\r\nCheques received from debtors ...........N255 000<br>\r\nTotal debtors c\/d 31\/12\/00...............N15 000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the sales figure?","options":["N295 000","N265 000","N245 000","N215 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Which of these is a capital expenditure warrant?","options":["Provisional general warrant","Development  fund general warrant","Reserved expenditure general warrant","Supplementary warrant"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"For the purpose of conversion of a partnership to a company, a total purchase consideration of N3.6m was paid. If 30% of the purchase consideration was in cash and the rest by 50k shares, how many shares issued?","options":["N1080 000","N2 160 000","N3 600 000","N5 040 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n(i) the consolidation revenue fund balance b\/d..N650 000<br>\r\n(ii) issue from contingency fund amount to......N240 000<br>\r\n(iii) amount transferred to contingency fund is.N210 000<br>\r\nWhat is the consolidation revenue fund balance?","options":["N1, 100 000","N680 000","N440 000","N410 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nGoods from head office................N13,400<br>\r\nReturns to head office ...............N118<br>\r\nRates and insurance paid .............N188<br>\r\nWages paid ...........................N913<br>\r\nCash remitted to head office..........N16,625<br>\r\nStock at 1\/1\/2000.....................N1,875<br>\r\nRents paid ...........................N325<br>\r\nStock at 31\/12\/2000 ..................N1,975  <br>\r\nSundry expenses ......................N200<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe profit realized from the trade is?","options":["N4 069","N1 817","N1 440","N1 328"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nGoods from head office................N13,400<br>\r\nReturns to head office ...............N118<br>\r\nRates and insurance paid .............N188<br>\r\nWages paid ...........................N913<br>\r\nCash remitted to head office..........N16,625<br>\r\nStock at 1\/1\/2000.....................N1,875<br>\r\nRents paid ...........................N325<br>\r\nStock at 31\/12\/2000 ..................N1,975  <br>\r\nSundry expenses ......................N200<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the total expenses?","options":["N1 875","N1 817","N1 626","N1 426"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The necessary accounts to be opened on the issue of ordinary share capital are?","options":["preference share capital, cash and allotment  accounts","bank and ordinary share capital accounts","cash and ordinary share capital accounts","nominal value and ordinary share capital accounts"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The amount of each invoiced goods sent to the branch is debited to?","options":["branch expense account and credited to branch debtors' accoount","branch stock account account and credited to the goods sent to branch account","branch debtors' account and credited to branch expense account","goods sent to branch expense account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Gross profit in the branch adjustment account is transferred to the branch?","options":["trading account","receipts and payments account","profit  and loss account","income and expenditure account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Mamsa Nigeria Limited issued 20 000 ordinary shares of N1.50 per share on 2nd July 2002.<br>\r\n1500 ordinary shares were fully subscribed for and their monies received as below:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOn application .........................N0.40<br>\r\nOn allotment ...........................N0.20<br>\r\nFirst call (including premium ofN0.50)..N0.70<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the balance of the ordinary share capital account after the first call was received?","options":["N300","N1050","N1200","1950"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\nCapital ...................N2000<br>\r\nBank ......................N1200<br>\r\nPurchase ..................N2500<br>\r\nSales .....................N6700<br>\r\nStock .....................N1300<br>\r\nCreditors .................N1000<br>\r\nFixed assets...............N3700<br>\r\nDrawings ..................N?<br>\r\nDrawings are always estimated at 50% of capital.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCompute the amount withdrawn","options":["N2000","N1500","N1250","N1000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n..............ZEBRA PLC..............<br>\r\n.............Balance sheet as at 31st March, 2002<br>\r\n...............N...............N............N......<br>\r\nCapital......100,000...Fixed assets:<br>\r\nCurrent................Land &..................<br>\r\nLiabilities...........buildings..50,000......<br>\r\nCreditors........30000..Furniture..10,000....60,000<br>\r\n.......................Current..................<br>\r\n.......................Assets: .......<br>\r\n..................Stock .........30,000...........<br>\r\n..................Debtors.......30,000.............<br>\r\n..................Cash..........10,000......70,000..<br>\r\n.............130,000.........................130,000<br>\r\nThe business was acquired on 1st April, 2002 at a purchase consideration of N120,000 by SOZ. All assets and liabilities were taken over except the cash to open the new firm's bank account additional N20,000 was paid into the bank.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe goodwill on purchase is","options":["N90,000","N30,000","N19,000","N18,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n..............ZEBRA PLC..............<br>\r\n.............Balance sheet as at 31st March, 2002<br>\r\n...............N...............N............N......<br>\r\nCapital......100,000...Fixed assets:<br>\r\nCurrent................Land &..................<br>\r\nLiabilities...........buildings..50,000......<br>\r\nCreditors........30000..Furniture..10,000....60,000<br>\r\n.......................Current..................<br>\r\n.......................Assets: .......<br>\r\n..................Stock .........30,000...........<br>\r\n..................Debtors.......30,000.............<br>\r\n..................Cash..........10,000......70,000..<br>\r\n.............130,000.........................130,000<br>\r\nThe business was acquired on 1st April, 2002 at a purchase consideration of N120,000 by SOZ. All assets and liabilities were taken over except the cash to open the new firm's bank account additional N20,000 was paid into the bank.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the network of the business","options":["N120,000","N90,000","N80,000","N30,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"What is the consolidated revenue fund balance?","options":["N1100,000","N680,000","N440,000","N410,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital..................N............N........<br>\r\nLand and building.......18470........24000....<br>\r\nMortgage on premises...................11090...<br>\r\nDrawings...............3000...................<br>\r\nProfit and loss........................3600...<br>\r\nFurniture and fittings...5120.................<br>\r\nMotor Vehicles...........3462................<br>\r\nClosing Stock............3000................<br>\r\nDebtors..................11474...............<br>\r\nCreditors..............................7354.<br>\r\nCash.....................1518................<br>\r\n..........................46044.........46044<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the capital employed?","options":["N44 600","N43 052","N43 044","N38 600"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital..................N............N........<br>\r\nLand and building.......18470........24000....<br>\r\nMortgage on premises...................11090...<br>\r\nDrawings...............3000...................<br>\r\nProfit and loss........................3600...<br>\r\nFurniture and fittings...5120.................<br>\r\nMotor Vehicles...........3462................<br>\r\nClosing Stock............3000................<br>\r\nDebtors..................11474...............<br>\r\nCreditors..............................7354.<br>\r\nCash.....................1518................<br>\r\n..........................46044.........46044<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the value of fixed assets","options":["N15 992","N18 470","N27 000","N27 052"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information to answer this question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDate.............Details........................<br>\r\nFeb........1 Purchased 400 units at N1.00 each<br>\r\n,, ........5 Purchased 200 units at N2.00 each <br>\r\n,,.........10 Purchased 200 units at N300 each<br>\r\n,, .........15 Issued 320 units <br>\r\n,,..........20 Issued 200 units at N4,00 each<br>\r\n,,..........25 Issued 120 units<br>\r\n <br>\r\nCalculate the price per unit of closing stock using the periodic weighted average method.","options":["N3.20","N3.00","N2.20","N2.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Use the information to answer this question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDate.............Details........................<br>\r\nFeb........1 Purchased 400 units at N1.00 each<br>\r\n,, ........5 Purchased 200 units at N2.00 each <br>\r\n,,.........10 Purchased 200 units at N300 each<br>\r\n,, .........15 Issued 320 units <br>\r\n,,..........20 Issued 200 units at N4,00 each<br>\r\n,,..........25 Issued 120 units<br>\r\n <br>\r\nUsing the periodic simple average method, the cost per unit is","options":["N4.25","N3.25","N2.25","N1.25"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Credit purchases are always put at 150% of the total cash paid to suppliers <br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the closing balance of the ledger account","options":["N6 900","N6400","N5000","N4000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Credit purchases are always put at 150% of the total cash paid to suppliers <br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the credit purchases","options":["N13 500","N15 500","N13 400","N12 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"What is the capital at start?","options":["N53 000","N63 000","N73 000","N83 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Given: <br>\r\nStock (1\/4\/94)    N800<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPurchases of flour N2450<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSales N4745<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWages of bakery staff  N675<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCarriage outwards N50<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSalary of administrative staff N225<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock (31\/3\/95) N940<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital N1540<br>\r\nDetermine the cost of goods sold?","options":["N2575","N2985","N3250","N3925"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"In preparing the final accounts, the bad debt account is closed by a transfer to the?","options":["balance sheet","provision for bad  debt account","profit and loss account","trading account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"In a petty cash book the imprest is N1380.<br>\r\nExpenses:<br>\r\nStationery   N350<br>\r\nCleaning material N335<br>\r\nGeneral expenses  N265<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow much was received to maintain the  imprest at the ends of the month?","options":["N950","N970","N430","N380"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"An entry in a subsidiary book which does not form part of the double entry system is a?","options":["contra entry","journal entry","single entry","memorandum entry"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"In an incomplete record, the preparation of the bank reconciliation ensures that?","options":["all cash taking are banked","the cash book is correct","there are no overdrafts","there are no hidden loans"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"In a petty cash book the imprest is N1380.<br>\r\nExpenses:<br>\r\nStationery   N350<br>\r\nCleaning material N335<br>\r\nGeneral expenses  N265<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow much was received to maintain the  imprest at the ends of the month?","options":["N950","N970","N430","N380"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"(i) Fixtures account  (ii) Machinery account <br>\r\n(iii) Wages accounts (iv) Rent account.<br>\r\nWhich of the above are nominal account?","options":["iii and iv","i and ii","i and iii","ii and iii"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"NAFARA AND SONS Balance Sheet items as at 31st December, 1987.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital N74480<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCreditors N15875<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPrepaid expenses N580<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMotor vehicles N34750<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFurniture N35850<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAccrued expenses N645<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock N8100<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCash balances N9911<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDebtors N1809<br>\r\nCompute the value of current assets?","options":["N20400","N20465","N35695","N19820"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe Assets and liabilities of Udo Co.ltd. as at 31st December, 2000.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCreditors N50,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDebtors  N46,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLoan     N100,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock    N20,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMotor vehicle N120,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBuilding N70,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAccrued wages 30,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBank N25 ,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe value of capital invested by the owners is?","options":["N110,000","N105,000","N101,000","N100,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 9 and 10.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe Assets and liabilities of Udo Co.ltd. as at 31st December, 2000.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCreditors N50,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDebtors N46,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLoan N100,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock N20,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMotor vehicle N120,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBuilding N70,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAccrued wages 30,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBank N25 ,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe liabilities of Udo Co. Ltd is?","options":["N180,000","N181,000","N177,000","N110,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The normal accounting entry to record the dishonor of a businessman is to?","options":["debit cash book and credit suspense account","debit cash book and credit drawer","credit caah book and debit suspense account","credit cash book and debit drawer"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question . Statement of assets and liabilities as at 31st December, 2001. Shareholders' interest N240 Current liabilities N20 Current assets N110 Fixed assets N140 <br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the value of the trade investment?","options":["N8m","N10m","N15m","N20m"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStatement of assets and liabilities as at 31st December, 2001.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nShareholders' interest  N240 <br>\r\n<br>\r\nCurrent liabilities N20 <br>\r\n<br>\r\nCurrent assets N110<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFixed assets   N140<br>\r\nWhat is the networking capital?","options":["N90m","N70m","N100m","N80m"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The concise statement used to explain entries in the general journal is known as?","options":["narration","summary","information","commentary"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"In a departmental accounting system, which of the following expenses will most likely be apportioned on the basis of turnover?","options":["carriage outwards","carriage inwards","discounts received","returns outwards"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The gross profit on manufactured goods is the difference between the cost of goods manufactured and the?","options":["market value of goods produced","prime cost of production","indirect cost of production","goods produced"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock of raw materials (1st January) N3000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDirect wages N2500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDirect expenses N1000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFactory overheads N2000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCost of raw materials used N5500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock of finished goods (31st December) N2000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the prime cost?","options":["N7500","N6500","N9000","N8000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Stock or raw materials(1st January)   3000<br>\r\nDirect wages                          2500<br>\r\nDirect expenses                       1000<br>\r\nFactory overheads                     2000<br>\r\nCost of raw materials used            5500<br>\r\nStock of finished goods (31st December) 2000<br>\r\nThe cost of goods manufactured is?","options":["N11000","N12000","N14000","N9000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"(i)Orientation (ii) Entity (iii)Legal status<br>\r\n(iv)Finance.<br>\r\nWhich of the characteristics above distinguishes a profit-making from a not-for-profit-making organizations?","options":["i, ii, iii and iv","i, ii, and iii","ii, and iii","i and ii"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nAdex Ltd. issues stock to its retail branches at cost price. The following particulars relate to Ede branch.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStock at branch 1st January at cost............N400<br>\r\nGoods sent to branch at cost...................N8000<br>\r\nReturns to head ...............................N340<br>\r\nCash sales ....................................N9160<br>\r\nStock at branch 31st December at cost..........N720<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the gross profit carried to the profit and loss account?","options":["N1820","N1640","N1530","N1870"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions Adex Ltd. issues stock to its retail branches at cost price. The following particulars relate to Ede branch. Stock at branch 1st January at cost............N400 Goods sent to branch at cost...................N8000 Returns to head ...............................N340 Cash sales ....................................N9160 Stock at branch 31st December at cost..........N720 <br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the cost of goods credited to the head office trading account?","options":["N7660","N7500","N7460","N7200"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Nasara Manufacturing Plc has three direct labour employees that work 40 hours each a week for 50 weeks a year. Factory overhead costs of N60,000 is distributed on the basis of direct labour hours.<br>\r\nCompute the overhead rate?","options":["N12 per hour","N16 per hour","N10 per hour","N15 per hour"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Given that 1\/3 of the N6000 stock held by a branch is purchased from outsiders. If goods are invoiced to branch at 25% on cost, the provision for unrealized profit is?","options":["N1000.00","N333.33","N666.66","N800.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Costs that vary in proportion to the level of production in a manufacturing environment are known as?","options":["control costs","overheads","direct costs","indirect costs"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"A company operating a chain of retail provision stores invoices goods to the branches at cost plus a mark-up of 25%. What is the mark-up percentage on selling price?","options":["35%","30%","20%","15%"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCash purchases ..............................N25000<br>\r\nTrading creditors............................N45000<br>\r\nOpening balance of trade creditors...........N35000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the purchases for the period?","options":["N80,000","N35,000","N105,000","N70,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Which method of pricing can be used satisfactorily in either a rising or falling price situation?","options":["Standard price","Marketing price","FIFO","Average method"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Given:<br><br>\r\nCapital at start.......................N3250<br><br>\r\nCapital at close ......................N6250<br><br>\r\nAdditional capital during the period...N1000<br><br>\r\n<br><br>\r\nCalculate the profit or loss?","options":["N8500 profit","N2000 loss","N2000 profit","N8500 loss"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"In a control account, discount received is found on the?","options":["debit side of the purchase ledger control account","debit side of the sales ledger control account","credit side of the purchase ledger control account","credit side of the sales ledger control account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"In an incomplete record system a trading account cannot be prepared until the?","options":["day book has been balanced","amount of personal drawings has been established","cash book has been balanced","amount os sales and purchases has been established"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Given an incomplete record without sufficient information to determine profit, the necessary thing to do is to?","options":["draw up the statement of affairs","draw up a T-account to establish the amount","compare the journal entries with the cash book","cross-check the cash book for further information"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"keeping records under the single entry system has the advantage of?","options":["quality in terms of records","completeness in terms of records","accuracy in terms of operation","simplicity in terms of operation"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Control accounts help to verify the arithmetic accuracy of the postings from the?","options":["subsidiary books into the trial balance","ledger into the trial balance","journals into the ledgers","subsidiary books into the ledgers"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSales ............................N195,200<br>\r\nStock 1st January.................N34,000<br>\r\nPurchases ........................N126,000<br>\r\nSales returns ....................N1,200<br>\r\nPurchases returns ................N2,000<br>\r\nIf the gross profit is N66,000, what is the value of stock at 31st December?","options":["N30,000","N40,000","50,000","N20,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Given:<br><br>\r\n<br><br>\r\nBalance at 31st December ............N14,744m<br><br>\r\nTreasury Bills issued Jan-Dec........N7124m<br><br>\r\nRevenue for the year ................N6387m<br><br>\r\nExpenditure .........................N8767m<br><br>\r\n<br><br>\r\nWhat is the opening balance on the consolidated revenue fund account?","options":["N10,000m","N12,000m","N90,000m","N11,000m"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Upon the dissolution of a partnership, the Partnership Act provides that the amount realized should be?","options":["used to pay all taxes due to government","used to start a new partnership business by members who are willing","shared equally by the existing partners","used in paying the debts and liabilities of the firm to persons who are not partners"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"In the public sector, the method of accounting that reports revenues and expenditures in the period in which they are received and paid is called?","options":["fund accounting","commitment accounting","cash accounting","accrual accounting"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nDate.............QTY. .....RATE........TOTAL<br>\r\n...............(Units).....N...........N<br>\r\nJanuary 2nd.....500........25..........12500<br>\r\nMarch 7th.......250........28..........7000<br>\r\nIssues were made as follows:<br>\r\nDate............QTY. (uNITS)<br>\r\nJanuary 9th .....200<br>\r\nFebruary 14th ...200<br>\r\nMarch 11th ......200<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe closing stock on March 11th by LIFO valuation is","options":["N4200","N2700","N4500","N3900"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nDate.............QTY. .....RATE........TOTAL<br>\r\n...............(Units).....N...........N<br>\r\nJanuary 2nd.....500........25..........12500<br>\r\nMarch 7th.......250........28..........7000<br>\r\nIssues were made as follows:<br>\r\nDate............QTY. (uNITS)<br>\r\nJanuary 9th .....200<br>\r\nFebruary 14th ...200<br>\r\nMarch 11th ......200<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe value of closing stock as at February 14th by simple average method is","options":["N3900","N2500","N4100","N2700"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe partnership agreement between Abba, Baba and Kaka contains the following provision:<br>\r\n(i) 5% interest to be paid on capital and no interest to be charged on drawings<br>\r\n(ii) Profits and losses to be shared in the ratio 3:2:1 respectively<br>\r\n(iii) net profit as at 31\/12\/95 N 2,250.<br>\r\n.................Abba......Baba.......Kake<br>\r\nCapital..........5000......4000......3000<br>\r\nCurrent account...250......100.......175<br>\r\nSalary............300......300.......---<br>\r\nDrawings..........600......500........250<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAbba's capital balance at the end of the year will be","options":["N5475","N5725","N4400","N5000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe partnership agreement between Abba, Baba and Kaka contains the following provision:<br>\r\n(i) 5% interest to be paid on capital and no interest to be charged on drawings<br>\r\n(ii) Profits and losses to be shared in the ratio 3:2:1 respectively<br>\r\n(iii) net profit as at 31\/12\/95 N 2,250.<br>\r\n.................Abba......Baba.......Kake<br>\r\nCapital..........5000......4000......3000<br>\r\nCurrent account...250......100.......175<br>\r\nSalary............300......300.......---<br>\r\nDrawings..........600......500........250<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCurrent account balance of Kaka at the end of the year will be","options":["N250","N350","N175","N325"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The gross profit on manufactured goods is the difference between the cost of goods manufactured and the","options":["market value of goods produced","prime cost of production","indirect cost of production","goods produced."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.............Total.........  Dept.P.............Dept.Q<br>\r\n...............N...............N.................N<br>\r\nSales.........10000............6000..............4000<br>\r\nPurchases......4000............1000..............3000<br>\r\nDiscount received.1000..........?..................<br>\r\nDiscounts allowed..2000...........................?.<br>\r\nDiscount (allowed and received) are apportioned to the two departments on the basis of departmental sales and purchases.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDepartment P's share of discount received is","options":["N750","N1000","N250","N500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.............Total.........  Dept.P.............Dept.Q<br>\r\n...............N...............N.................N<br>\r\nSales.........10000............6000..............4000<br>\r\nPurchases......4000............1000..............3000<br>\r\nDiscount received.1000..........?..................<br>\r\nDiscounts allowed..2000...........................?.<br>\r\nDiscount (allowed and received) are apportioned to the two departments on the basis of departmental sales and purchases.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is department Q's share of discount allowed?","options":["N2000","N1500","N800","N1200"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The working capital of the club is","options":["N5000","N4000","N3000","N7000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"It is the tradition of the club to write off an amount equal to 25% of the subscriptions received as other expenses.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the amount to be written off as  other expenses?","options":["N4500","N6000","N4000","N5000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"It is the tradition of the club to write off an amount equal to 25% of the subscriptions received as other expenses.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the club's excess of income over expenditure","options":["N12000","N15000","N10000","N14500"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Miscellaneous expense is 10% of revenue Calculate the net income.","options":["N583,000","N563,000","N483,000","N583,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Subscriptions received are always put at 125% of the total donations received and refreshment sales.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the closing cash balance ?","options":["N11500","N12000","N13000","N13500"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Subscriptions received are always put at 125% of the total donations received and refreshment sales.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCompute the subscriptions received.","options":["N30000","N28000","N24000","N20000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The current growth in the volume of trading and financial dealings in Nigeria is helped by?","options":["increased financial activities","government intervention","credit as a factor in business","payment for goods in cash"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Cost accounting entails the provision of information?","options":["for investment purposes","for descision making","to shareholders","to stockholders"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The main objective of accounting report is to provide information about?","options":["a company's shareholding","an entity's  management","the efficacy of assets","a company's economic resources"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If liabilities amounted to N12,045, other assets N36,800and equity N26,896, the cash at hand would be?","options":["N2,241","N2,214","N2,141","N2,114"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question.<br>\r\nGiven:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFixed assets       N85,600<br>\r\nSales              N197,000<br>\r\nStock              N34,300<br>\r\nSalaries           N37,000<br>\r\nPurchases          N127,700<br>\r\nShare capital      N120,000<br>\r\nCreditors          N16, 050<br>\r\nMotor expenses     N10,500<br>\r\nDebtors            N25,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the cash balance?","options":["N12,095","N12,590","N12,905","N12,950"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question.<br>\r\nGiven:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFixed assets N85,600<br>\r\nSales N197,000<br>\r\nStock N34,300<br>\r\nSalaries N37,000<br>\r\nPurchases N127,700<br>\r\nShare capital N120,000<br>\r\nCreditors N16, 050<br>\r\nMotor expenses N10,500<br>\r\nDebtors N25,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the total of the trial balance?","options":["N335,050","N333,050","N323,050","N230,550"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The accuracy of journalist is checked by?","options":["ensuring that debit totals equal credit totals","posting all journal entries to ledger accounts","adding all figures in the debit column","comparing accounts in the ledger against the journals"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Hauwa Ltd bought 10bags of rice for N500 each.<br>\r\nThe company was given 5% AND 12% trade and cash discounts respectively. What will be recorded as discount received in the company's book?","options":["N250","N570","N600","N850"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A cash book had opening balance of N15,200 closing balance N18,400 and total cash received during the period N36,000. What was the amount of cash paid out during the same period?","options":["N17,800","N19,600","N29,200","N32,800"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"In a petty cash book, the closing balance was N235, imprest N1,250, while the stationery expenses were N655. How much was paid for other general expenses?","options":["N360","N355","N350","N305"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"When a bill is negotiated to a bank, it is said be?","options":["surrendered","cashed","discounted","accepted"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Given that the balance as per cash book after necessary adjustment was N4,315, unpresented cheques were N1,688 and the bank statement balance was N4,791, what was the balance of uncredited cheques?","options":["N1,223","N1,212","N1,202","N1,115"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If a property developing company sells a completed building to an interested third party, this sale can be treated in the books of the company as?","options":["capital receipt","revenue receipt","windfall receipt","miscellaneous receipt"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\nPalaju Enterprises had fixed assets costing N900,000 with provision for depreciation of N150,000 were disposed of during the period. Fixed assets of N100,000 were added during the year. Provision for depreciation was N350,000 at the beginning of the year and N300,000 at the end of the year.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat was the value of fixed assets at the beginning of the year?","options":["N2,900,000","N3,800,000","N3,900,000","N4,000,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\nPalaju Enterprises had fixed assets costing N900,000 with provision for depreciation of N150,000 were disposed of during the period. Fixed assets of N100,000 were added during the year. Provision for depreciation was N350,000 at the beginning of the year and N300,000 at the end of the year.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe depreciation expenses charged for the year is?","options":["N450,000","N250,000","N150,000","N100,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A reduction in the catalogue price of an article given by a wholesaler to a retailer is called a?","options":["bad debt","trade discount","premium","cash discount"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question .<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPurchases ledger opening balances N4,000<br>\r\nSales ledger opening balances     N6,000<br>\r\nCredit purchases during the year  N25,000<br>\r\nDiscounts allowed                 N1,000<br>\r\nReturns inwards                   N2,000<br>\r\nCredit sales during the year      N10,000<br>\r\nReturns outwards                  N6,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the sales ledger balance?","options":["N3,000","N6,000","N10,000","N13,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question . Purchases ledger opening balances N4,000 Sales ledger opening balances N6,000 Credit purchases during the year N25,000 Discounts allowed N1,000 Returns inwards N2,000 Credit sales during the year N10,000 Returns outwards N6,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the purchases ledger balance?","options":["N4,000","N23,000","N24,000","N29,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"For an incomplete record to provide necessary information, it must be converted to?","options":["complete records","double entry records","statement of affairs","single entry"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\nGiven:                    31\/12\/98      31\/12\/99<br>\r\nAssets:      Plant and Mach. N1,500          N1,200<br>\r\n             Fixtures        N700            N520<br>\r\n             Stock           N500            N600<br>\r\n             Debtors         N900            N400<br>\r\n             Cash            N200            N300<br>\r\nLiabilities: Creditor        N500            N600<br>\r\n             Loan            N600            N400<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the total fixed assets from the opening balance sheet?","options":["N2,200","N2,020","N1,720","N2,070"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nDirect material  N2,500<br>\r\nDirect labour    N5,000<br>\r\nDirect expenses  N1,000<br>\r\nOverhead expenses N1,500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the data above, compute the prime cost?","options":["N8,500","N7,500","N6,500","6,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question 25 and 26.<br>\r\nBar opening stock N10,000<br>\r\nAmount owed to bar suppliers at <br>\r\nthe end the beginning of the year N10,000<br>\r\nBar sales  N50,000<br>\r\nBar credit purchases N40,000<br>\r\nPayment to suppliers N30,000<br>\r\nBar expenses         N1,000<br>\r\nBar closing stock    N15,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the bar profits?","options":["N20,000","N15,000","N14,000","N10,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question 25 and 26.<br>\r\nBar opening stock N10,000<br>\r\nAmount owed to bar suppliers at<br>\r\nthe end the beginning of the year N10,000<br>\r\nBar sales N50,000<br>\r\nBar credit purchases N40,000<br>\r\nPayment to suppliers N30,000<br>\r\nBar expenses N1,000<br>\r\nBar closing stock N15,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow much is owed to suppliers?","options":["N50,000","N40,000","N30,000","20,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Lubricating oil and spare parts of machinery are examples of?","options":["direct materials","indirect materials","indirect expenses","direct expenses"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nSubscription received during the year N30,000<br>\r\nSubscription owed last year N4,000<br>\r\nSubscription received for next year N6,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe N6,000 subscription received is?","options":["current asset","current liability","fixed asset","capital"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions Subscription received during the year N30,000 Subscription owed last year N4,000 Subscription received for next year N6,000 <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the subscription to be charged to income and expenditure account?","options":["N36,000","N34,000","N30,000","N20,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Given:<br><br>\r\nClub trading profit N12,000<br><br>\r\n<br><br>\r\nMembers'' subscription N15,000<br><br>\r\n<br><br>\r\nProfit on sale of fixed assets N2,500<br><br>\r\n<br><br>\r\nLoss on sale of investments N1,000<br><br>\r\n<br><br>\r\nWages N16,500 <br><br>\r\n<br><br>\r\nOther expenses N10,000<br><br>\r\n<br><br>\r\nDetermine the club''s excess of income over expenditure?","options":["N500","N1,500","N2,000","N2,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The excess of income over expenditure is usually transferred to the?","options":["accumulated fund","profit and loss account","current assets in the balance sheet","current liabilities in the balance sheet"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Partners' salaries and drawings are usually posted to the?","options":["trading account","current  account","capital account","partners' account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Marhumu and Yusuf are in partnership sharing profits and losses in the ratio of 2:1. On 31\/3\/2000, the partnership decided to admit Idris who is to take 1\/4 of future profits without changing the ratio of Marhumu and Yusuf.<br>\r\nWhat is the new profit-sharing ratio of Marhumu and Yusuf?","options":["50% : 25%","50% : 20%","25% : 50%","25% :25%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If a partner pays a premium of N500 for 1\/5 share of profit, then the total value of goodwill is?","options":["N500","N2,000","N2,500","N3,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"On the dissolution of a partnership business,the net book value of the assets is transferred to?","options":["debit of realization account","credit of realization account","credit of bank account","debit of bank account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Bala Ltd acquired the business of Bello Ltd and caused the separate existence of the latter company to terminate. This situation is best described as?","options":["absorption","merger","conversion","dissolution"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Where a company acquires controlling shares of another and the consideration is paid in cash, the entries in the books of the purchases are debit?`","options":["investment and credit cash","investment and credit shares","purchases and credit cash","purchases and credit shares"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The main difference between the ordinary and preference shareholders is that?","options":["the former receive dividends while the latter do not","the latter are not members of the company while the former are","in the case of winding up, the former are paid first before the latter","the former have voting rights while the latter do not"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The law that currently regulates the registration of companies in Nigeria is the?","options":["Constitution of the Federal Republic of Nigeria, 1999","Nigeria Enterprises Promotion Decree, 1972","Companies and Allied Matters Decree, 1990","Companies Decree, 1968"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"X and Y are two departments that are to share 50% of all joint costs equally and the balance in ratio 2:1. If a sum of N150,000 is incurred jointly, what will be the portion attributable to X?","options":["N37,500","N62,500","N87,500","N100,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Department F transferred some goods to department G at a selling price. The goods were not sold at the end of the accounting period. Which account is affected at the time of preparing a combined balance sheet?","options":["creditors","debtors","stock","suspense"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"To account for expenses paid by head office on behalf of the branch, the branch should?","options":["debit head office account and credit cash","debit profit and loss account and credit headoffice account","credit cash and debit profitand loss account","credit profit and loss account and debit head office account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The correct entry to reflect the receipt of cash sent by a branch to a head office is?","options":["debit cash and credit branch current account","debit branch, current account and credit cash","credit branch, debtors and debit cash","credit branch current account and debit branch debtors"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The officer responsible for ascertaining whether all public expenditure and appropriation are in line with approved guidelines is the?","options":["Acountant General","Auditor General","Finance Minister","Permanent Secretary"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question<br>\r\nGiven: 31\/12\/98 31\/12\/99<br>\r\nAssets: Plant and Mach. N1,500 N1,200<br>\r\nFixtures N700 N520<br>\r\nStock N500 N600<br>\r\nDebtors N900 N400<br>\r\nCash N200 N300<br>\r\nLiabilities: Creditor N500 N600<br>\r\nLoan N600 N400<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the capital from the opening balance sheet?","options":["N3,600","N 2,700","N2,070","N1,520"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAuthorized Capital:                      N<br>\r\n100,000 ordinary shares of N 1 eash<br>\r\nIssued and fully paid:<br>\r\n50,000 ordinary shares of N 1 each 50,000<br>\r\n10, 000 8% perference shares<br>\r\nof N 1 each <br>\r\nReserves                   10,000<br>\r\nCreditors                  25,000<br>\r\nDebtors                    13 000<br>\r\nCash in hand                 5000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the net current assets","options":["N 43,000","N 28,000","N13,000","N3,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"\u00bb Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAuthorized Capital: N<br>\r\n100,000 ordinary shares of N 1 eash<br>\r\nIssued and fully paid:<br>\r\n50,000 ordinary shares of N 1 each 50,000<br>\r\n10, 000 8% perference shares<br>\r\nof N 1 each<br>\r\nReserves 10,000<br>\r\nCreditors 25,000<br>\r\nDebtors 13 000<br>\r\nCash in hand 5000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the shareholders fund","options":["N 60,000","N75,000","N85,000","N185,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Given: <br>\r\nPTF Trial Balance [Extract] as at 31 December, 1999<br>\r\nDr                           Cr<br>\r\n           N'000    N '000<br>\r\nCash       2,000<br>\r\nInvestments 3,000<br>\r\nAccounts receivable 6,000      11,000<br>\r\nFund balance     11,000        11,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAssuming all the investments realized N4m, what will be the endig fund balance?","options":["N8m","N 11M","N12M","N15M"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"\u00bb Given:<br>\r\nPTF Trial Balance [Extract] as at 31 December, 1999<br>\r\nDr Cr<br>\r\nN'000 N '000<br>\r\nCash 2,000<br>\r\nInvestments 3,000<br>\r\nAccounts receivable 6,000 11,000<br>\r\nFund balance 11,000 11,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf only 1\/2 of the investments is sold for N2m and N5m realized from the accounts receivable what will be the balance of the fund?","options":["N9M","N11M","N13M","N16M"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nN                N<br>\r\nCapital        200,000    total assets  210,000<br>\r\nLiabilities    10,000<br>\r\n               210,000                  210,000<br>\r\nIf the business is purchased at a price including a goodwill of N 20,000, what must have been the  purchas price?","options":["N190,000","N210,000","N220,000","N230,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"WHAT IS THE STOCK VALUATION METHOD USED?","options":["LAST IN FIRST OUT","FIRST IN FIRST OUT","AVERAGE COST","WEIGHTED AVERAGE"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The value of x is","options":["N4.00","N5.00","N5.50","N6.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"On November 1, 199 8, Zaria Holdings owed N13,600 in respect of a creditor. On November 15, it purchase goods worth N69,000 and paid a cheque of N51,600. On November 29, one of the Holdings' cheques worth N3,000 was returned while the creditor granted N1,500 discount. The amount owed by Zaria Holdings as at November 29 is?","options":["N32,500","N32,000","N31,000","N29,500"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"To write off bad debt, debt?","options":["debtor's account and credit provision for bad debt","bad debt account and credit debtor's account","debtor's account credit bad debt","provision for bad debt account and credit debtor's account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"In order to make the cash book balance equal to the bank statement, it is usual to add?","options":["uncredited cheques","direct payments by bank","bank charges","unpresented cheques"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question 4 and 5.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSales                          N20,000<br>\r\nCost sales                     N10,000<br>\r\nOperating expenses             N2,500<br>\r\nExpenses prepaid included <br>\r\nin operating expenses          N500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the net profit?","options":["N12,500","N10,000","N8,000","N7,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"what is the gross profit margin?","options":["N100%","N50%","N40%","N30%"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The main objective of bookkeeping is to record economic?","options":["transactions systematically for routine managerial decision-making","events clearly to ensure adequate checks and balances","events clearly to facilitate strategic managerial desicion-making","transaction systematically to ascertain the financial position of a business"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Which of the following is an example of intangible assets?","options":["trade debtors","stock of goods","trade creditors","motor vehicles"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A source document that aids the ascertainment of amount paid out of current account is the?","options":["teller","cheque stub","cheque","teller stub"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The most convenient cash book used by a petty trader operating in an area where there is no banking facility is?","options":["four column","three column","single column","two column"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A general journal contains?","options":["date, narration, folio, debit, and purchases","date, narration, folio, debit and purchase","folio, credit, date, debit and sales","debit, credit, narration, date and discount"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Which of the following errors will affect the trial balance total?","options":["posting disscount allowed to the debit side of the discount allowed account","omision of one account from the list when extracting from the ledger","failure to post sales of N2,000 and purchases of N2,000 from the subsidiiary ledger","omission of sales of N3,000 and purchases of N2,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"An expenses account is closed by a debit to?","options":["an asset account and a credit to the expenses account","the expenses account and a credit to an asset account","profit and loss account and a creit to the expenses account","the expenses account and a credit to profit and loss account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"In a manufacturing company, the total cost of goods produced is equivalent to?","options":["purchases","sales","cost of goods sold","cost of materials used"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nSales Ledger Control  Account (Extracts)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBalance b\/f                     N10,600<br>\r\nTotal cash payments by debtors  N32,275<br>\r\nTotal credit sales              N59,193<br>\r\nDiscount received               N9,700<br>\r\nBalance c\/f                     N20,751<br>\r\nDiscount allowed                N2,890<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the sales returns?","options":["N24,577","N13,877","N7,067","N2,890"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The simplest form of single entry procedure consists fo keeping a?","options":["day book  or general journal","cash book and ledger accounts showing debtors and creditors balances","cash journal, sales journal and purchases journal","day book in which transactions are described in chronological order"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A fixed cost is fixed only in relation to?","options":["the quality of goods produced","the quantity of goods sold","a given period of time and a range of activities","a given period of time and the nature of activity"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"One of the advantage of the shortcomings of single entry procedures is that?","options":["a trial balance is not available","profits are overestimated","there are no subsidiary books","there are no control accounts"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"When a customer's cheque is returned unpaid in a debtor's control accounting system, the treatment will be?","options":["debit bank, credit custmer and credit conyrol account","credit bank, debit customer, and credit control account","debit customer, debit control accountand credit bank","credit control account, debit bank and debit customer"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Didi Ltd offered 10,000 ordinary shares of N1.50 each at a discount of 2% which were fully subscribed. With regard to the offer above?","options":["shares are never offered at a discount; the offer is invalid","the value of shares in the capital account will be lowered by 2%","the company incurs a loss to the tune of 2% of the offer","each of the subscribers loses 2% of investment"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions <br>\r\n<br>\r\nMaro Merchant Bank plc is to issue N500,000 ordinary shares of 50k  each at N 3.00 per share.<br>\r\nApplications were received for N1,550,000 shares fully paid, N1,250,000 shares are to be issued on a pro rata basis and excess subscriptions were dishonored  and refunds made?<br>\r\nThe refund due to an application for N25,000 shares is?","options":["N45,000","N30,000","7,500","N5,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions Maro Merchant Bank plc is to issue N500,000 ordinary shares of 50k each at N 3.00 per share. Applications were received for N1,550,000 shares fully paid, N1,250,000 shares are to be issued on a pro rata basis and excess subscriptions were dishonored and refunds made? <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat will be the number of shares to be issued to a subscriber who applied for N30,000 shares?","options":["N20,000","N18,000","N15,000","N12,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Which of the following items does not feature in the balance sheet of a club?","options":["Arrears of current year's subscription","Salary arrears paid in the current year","Rental income received in advance","Advances subscription in respect of a coming year"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"An outright sale of a partnership amounts to the?","options":["compensation of vendors by the purchase","admission of a new partner","purchase of rights of a dead partner","change of sharing ratio of vendors"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nOpening cash balance           N20,000<br>\r\nSales of match tickets         N15,000<br>\r\nClearing of pitch              N1,200<br>\r\nRefreshments                   N3,500<br>\r\nReferees' allowance            N1,000<br>\r\nCost of petrol                 N1,120<br>\r\nDonation from local government N3,800            <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe club's balance is?","options":["N39,180","N34,830","N34,380","N31,980"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nMaimalari Ltd had (i) Earning per share 47k<br>\r\n(ii) Dividend per share 30k <br>\r\n(iii) Par value of each share N1.20<br>\r\n(iv) Market price per share N1.50<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe company's earning yield is?","options":["20.00%","25.00%","31.33%","39.17%"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question Maimalari Ltd had (i) Earning per share 47k (ii) Dividend per share 30k (iii) Par value of each share N1.20 (iv) Market price per share N1.50<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat will be the price earnings ratio of the company?","options":["3.91","3.19","2.95","2.55"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The Partnership Deed normally specifies?","options":["how profit or losses are to be shared","the capital  to be contributed annually","how salaries are paid to employees","the profit that should be earned annually"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The accumulation fund of a non-trading concern can equally be referred to as?","options":["members'  equity","share capital","general fund","surplus fund"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"When a purchase business is revalued, the effect is that?","options":["a decrease in the value of asset has no effect on value of goodwill","an increase in the value of asset is treated as an increase in the value of goodwill","a decrease in the value of asset is treated as an decrease in the value of goodwil","an increase in the value of asset is treated as an decrease in the value of goodwill"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"An item of appropriation in partnership profit and loss account is?","options":["interest on partners'  capital","interest on partners'  loan","employees'  salaries","partners'  drawings"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nRakiya and Joy are in partnership and agreed that 5% interest per annul is to be charged on drawings. The drawing made by both partners in one year were: Rakiya, N200 on March 31 and N300 on September 30. Joy, N100 on April 1 and N240 on July 1.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe interest on joy's drawing is?","options":["N6.00","N7.25","N9.00","N9.75"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRakiya and Joy are in partnership and agreed that 5% interest per annul is to be charged on drawings. The drawing made by both partners in one year were: Rakiya, N200 on March 31 and N300 on September 30. Joy, N100 on April 1 and N240 on July 1.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAssuming that Rakiya was not credited with any income during the period, what is her closing current account  balance?","options":["N340,000 credit","N349,75 debit","N500.00 credit","N 511.25 debit"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A business is required at par when the?","options":["purchase consideration equals goodwill","purchase consideration equals net value","purchase consideration is greater than the net value","net assets is greater than the liabilitties"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\ncash book item:<br>\r\nPaid to suppliers N10,800<br>\r\nExpenses paid N6,900<br>\r\nDrawings made N900<br>\r\nBalances at start N15,750<br>\r\nBalances at end N3,870<br>\r\nDrawings from bank to shop N1,720<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the receipt from debtors?","options":["N22,470","N17,470","N8,440","N5,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDepreciation of plant and machinery N1,600<br>\r\nFactory rent N650<br>\r\nIndirect wages N695<br>\r\nGeneral indirect expenses N726<br>\r\nlubricants N1235<br>\r\nCarriage inwards  N829<br>\r\nFactory power N350<br>\r\nBank charges N612<br>\r\nCarriage outwards N2,900<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the total factory overhead cost?","options":["N4,485","N5,256","N6,085","N6,556"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Yola Social Club <br>\r\nStatement of Account 1998 financial year<br>\r\n31\/12\/98:<br>\r\nSubscription in arrears N21,000<br>\r\nSubscription in advance N12,000<br>\r\nReceipt during 1999: <br>\r\n<br>\r\nArrears 1998 N21,000<br>\r\nDues 1999    N48,000<br>\r\nAdvance 2000 N11,000 <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe subscription transferable to the income and expenditure account is?","options":["N48,000","N59,000","N60,000","N69,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The most appropriate basis for apportioning inventory holding cost among departments is to use the value of?","options":["purchases","opening stock","closing stock","average stock"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The body constitutionally charged with the responsibility of examining the audited accounts of the Federation and other reports as referred by the National Assembly is the?","options":["Public Accounts Committee","Public Audit Committee","Internal Audit Committee","External Audit Committee"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"(i) Meet growth and diversification need.<br>\r\n(ii) Reach out to particular customers or markets <br>\r\n(iii) Comply with some regulatory directives<br>\r\n(iv) Increase employees' income. <br>\r\nWhich of the reasons above do companies consider in establishing branches?","options":["i and ii","i, ii and iii","ii, iii and iv","iii and iv"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The channel through which all government borrowing and domestic lending transactions pass is called?","options":["special trust fund","agency fund","national loan fund","contingency fund"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Recurrent expenditure are expenses for the period not exceeding?","options":["10 years","5 years","2 years","1 year"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A major benefit derived from the reconciliation of branch and head office books is to?","options":["determine accurate returns by the branch","ascertian the correct profit or loss on branch activities","enable the branch to keep control over stock","enable the branch to ascertain debtor's balance"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Halal Limited with three departments has a total of N7,200,000 as net debtors for the year ended 31\/12\/97. <br>\r\nThe company's policy provides for 15% bad debt annually.  Which of the following represents the total balance of debtors before adjustment?","options":["N6,120,000","N6,120,300","N8,280,000","8,820,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Yahuza Enterpises<br>\r\nTrial Balance (Extracts) as at Dec. 31, 1998.<br>\r\nCapital<br>\r\nPremises            90,000     21,000<br>\r\nDebtors             35,000<br>\r\nProvisions 1\/1\/98:<br>\r\nDepreciation        9,000<br>\r\nBad and doubtful    1,500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf premises is to be depreciated at 10% on cost and a 5% provision is to be allowed on debtors, the total asset in the balance sheet is","options":["N 125, 000","N114,500","N105,500","N105,250"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The accounting convention which stipulates that money or goods taken from the business by the owner for personal use should be treated as deductions from capital is","options":["cost","prudence","consistency","entity"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Use the information below to this question <br>\r\nCost of raw materials consumed     300,600<br>\r\nCarriage inwards                    6,700<br>\r\nReturns of raw materials            10,800<br>\r\nClosing stock of raw materials      100,250<br>\r\nManufacturing wages                 27,000<br>\r\nLighting, power, insurance and rent <br>\r\nrelation to the factory are <br>\r\napportioned 1\/3,2\/5, 1\/6 and 17<br>\r\nwith totals N30,000; N 75,000; N36,000 and N 56,000 respectively.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the cost of the opening raw materials?","options":["N 418,350","N404,950","N400,250","N398,250"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Use the information below to this question Cost of raw materials consumed 300,600 Carriage inwards 6,700 Returns of raw materials 10,800 Closing stock of raw materials 100,250 Manufacturing wages 27,000 Lighting, power, insurance and rent relation to the factory are apportioned 1\/3,2\/5, 1\/6 and 17 with totals N30,000; N 75,000; N36,000 and N 56,000 respectively. <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe production cost of finished goods is","options":["N 524,600","n408,600","n381,600","n327,600"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Amin Ltd. Creditor Ledger Control Account (Extracts)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBeginning control account <br>\r\nBalance:  Debit               32,000<br>\r\n          Credit              61,000<br>\r\nPurchases during the year: <br>\r\n          Cash                30,000<br>\r\n          Credit              60,000<br>\r\nPayment to suppliers:<br>\r\n           Cash               13,000<br>\r\n           Cheque             29,000<br>\r\nDebtor's contra               6,000<br>\r\nThe closing control account balance is","options":["N 41,000","N65,000","N71,000","N77,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The items entered in an opening statement of affairs of an enterprise that keeps incomplete record are","options":["sales income","receipt from debtors","fixtures and fittings","rent paid"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Given<br>\r\n<br>\r\n                   Dept A            Dept B<br>\r\nFloor space         40m<sup>2<\/sup>   60m<sup>2<\/sup><br>\r\nMachine hours       1200              1400<br>\r\nTurnover            N36 million       N64 million<br>\r\nLabour hours        1000              1400<br>\r\nA joint cost of N 72 million incurred by the two departments was apportioned N30 million to A and N42 million to B. the basis used for apportionment must have been","options":["labour hours","floor space","turnover","machine hours"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Accrual concept stipulates that?","options":["revenue should be recognized when  it is earned","costs should be recognized when the expenditure is paid","revenue should be recognized only when cash is paid","costs should be recognized when the are incurred"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The basic role of accounting is to?","options":["detect fraud","attest to finacial statements","measure performance","protect sharehlders"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The need for changes in accounting theory in Nigeria was influenced by the?","options":["dynamics of commercialization and privatization policies","growh in size of business units","introduction of the structural adjustment programme","inconvertibility of the nation's currency"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A bookkeeping error occurs when there is?","options":["a deliberate manipulation of records","unintentional correct posting in the ledger","intentional failure to record transactions completely","incorrect records and oversights that are  not intended"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"When a proprietor withdraws cash from the business for private use, he?","options":["debits cash account and credits drawings account","credits cash account and debits bank account","debits bank account and credits drawings account","credits cash account and debits drawings account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A basic unifying concept in accounting implies that?","options":["where creditors'account is zero, the assets are equal to the owners' equity","there should be a balance in the creditors' account  in order to measure total assets","revenues  should be supported by invested and owners'capital","total assets can be less than liabilities and equity"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A source document for the sales day book is?","options":["a requisition form","an invoice","a customer advice","a credit advice"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"In a cash book, the opening balance was N7,600, closing balance N9,200 and the total cash received during the period was N18,000. What was the amount of cash paid out during the period?","options":["N8,900","N9,800","N14,600","N16,400"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"If the total discount allowed in a cash book was N230 and the total discount received was N255, which of the following is true concerning the two discounts?","options":["They must be balanced in the cash book and the difference taken to the debtors ledger","They must be balanced in the cash book and the difference taken to the trial balance","They should not be balanced in the cash book before being taking  to the  trial balance","They should not appear in the trial balance as they were already either received or paid out"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Which of the following bank reconciliation items should not be added or subtracted from the bank statement balance to determine the adjusted cash balance?","options":["Outstanding cheques","Bank service charges","Deposit in the mail not yet received by the bank","Bank error, charging a company for another company's cheque"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The fixed amount of money given to a petty cashier at the beginning of a period is called?","options":["imprest","petty cash","float","cash advance"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A provision for bad debt account had N3,800 at the beginning of the year and N4,220 at the close of the year. If bad debts are calculated at the rate of 1\/2% of annual sales, what was the credit sales for the period?","options":["N2,100,000","N844,400","N840,000","N500,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Asa Company bought a vehicle worth N20,000 and the vehicle is to be depreciated at 5%. Using the reducing balance method of depreciation, what would be the value of the asset after 3 years?","options":["N19,000.00","N18,050.50","N17,147.50","16,290.13"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Chibuike bought 36 notebooks at N10 each from John and was given a trade discount of 5%. In addition, he was offered 1% cash discount which he took advantage of. How much did Chibuike pay?","options":["N338.58","N342.00","N345.42","N360,00"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Depreciation on a particular piece of machinery was N2,700 during the fifth year of its service life and N4,050 during the sixth year. The logical explanation for this is that?","options":["an addition was made to the asset during the sixth year","the estimate of salvage value on this equipment  was decreased","a unit-of-output method of depreciation was used during the sixth year","the estimate remaining service life of the assets was increased at the beginning of the sixth year"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The main features of the single system are that?","options":["books of accounts are not maintained and business relies only on bank statement","the journal records are absent and only the main ledger is kept 7","there are incomplete classifications and recording procedures","only credit sales transactions and credit purchase are recorded"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The principal function of a sales ledger control account is to?","options":["serve as internal check and provide quick information for the preparation of interim financial statements","serve as external check and provide quick information for the preparation of interim financial statements","provide quick information for the preparation of customers' statement","provide information for the control of salesmen's activities"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"In dealing with incomplete records, fixed assets are posted to?","options":["opening profit and loss as  brought forward figures","closing balance sheet as  carried forward figures","closing balance sheets as brought forward figures","closing profit and loss as brought forward figures"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"When the factory  cost of production has been ascertained, manufactured goods are transferred to trading account by?","options":["debting manufacturing account and crediting trading acccount","crditing  sales account and debtiting trading account","debiting sales account and crediting trading account","crediting manufacturing account and debiting trading account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Lawal and co makes blocks and sell to builders.<br>\r\nIn computing prime cost, which of the following costs would be considered appropriate?","options":["Cement, sand and carriage outwards","Water carriage inwards and cement","Sales boys'wages, cement and sand","Carriage outwards,carriage inwards and cement"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Manufacturing costs can be classified based on?","options":["timing of charges degree of averaging and size of capital","degree of averaging, ease of traceability and timing of charges","degree of averaging, size of floor space occupied and cost accounts","number of employees, timing of charges and management style"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The difference between the factory cost of production and the prime cost of production is?","options":["direct materials","direct labour","selling expenses","overhead"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Receipt and payments account of a non-profit making organization is principally a summary of the?","options":["bak entries","cash bok entries","expenditure entries","balance sheet entries"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nClub                        N150<br>\r\nCash sales                  N4,850<br>\r\nClub debtors at close       N900<br>\r\nCash received from debtors  N550<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the amount of club sales?","options":["N6,150","N4,850","N4,650","N1,300"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A credit balance on a receipt and payments account indicates that the non-profit making organization?","options":["had more revenues than expenses during the period","did not owe much liabilities during the period","received more cash than it paid out during the period","made more cash payments than it received during the period"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Goodwill can be valued in partnership when?","options":["a partners make profits","large losses are made","a partner retires","a new branch is opened"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"As part of the initial investment, a partner contributes office equipment that originally cost N20,000 and on which provision for depreciation of N12,500 had been recorded. If the partners agree on a valuation of N9,000 for the equipment, what amount should be debited to the office equipment account?","options":["N7,500","N9,000","N12,500","N20,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"When a partner makes a drawing of stock items from a partnership, the accounting impact of the drawing is to increase the partner's?","options":["goodwill account balance","current account credit balance","current account debit balance","profit and loss credit balance"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Dele and Seun who are in partnership, have decided to covert their business into a limited liability company where both become directors. To convert the business?","options":["they will simply continue since there are no new members","the partnership is formally ended and new company books opened","the shares and all other items will be shared  equally and not in their former ratios","computation of goodwill must be done as it is legally required"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"If a sole proprietorship is purchased for cash, then?","options":["the purchaser debits his business purchase account with the consideration he pays","all assets and liabilities must be bought","goodwill results where value of assets","the vendor debits his business purchase account with the considerstion he receives"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The market price per ordinary share of a corporation listed on the stock exchange is most closely related to its?","options":["earning per share","redemption price per share","book value per share","call price per share"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Which of the following events increases a corporation's shareholders equity?","options":["Donation of shares out of the corporation's own stock to the corporation","The corporation's purchase of treasury stock","Shares of previously subscribed stock issue to subscribing stockholders","A municipality donation of land to the corporation"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"If a promoter pays a lawyer N5,000 for services rendered in preparing a Memorandum of Incorporation, the journal entry is to debit?","options":["preliminary expenses, credit cash accounts","promoter, credit creditors' accounts","lawyer's credit cash accounts","cash , credit incorporation accounts"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Calls in advance are treated in the balance sheet as?","options":["current asset","current liability","fixed assets","fixed liability"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Shares issued to a vendor in payment of business purchased would require a debit to?","options":["cash account and credit to share capital account","share capital account and credit to vendor's account","vendor's account and credit to share capital account","share capital account and credit to cash account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The best method of allocating expenses among departments is to?","options":["allocate expenses to each department  in proportion  to the sales of that department","charge against each department those costs which are within its control","charge expenses against each department in proportion to the purchases of that department","allocate expenses to each section of the department in relation to the number of people"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"To record the transfer of stock from one department to another, the correct entry would be to debit?","options":["goods outwards and credit goods inwards","merchandise account and credit department stock account","department transfering and credit department receivving","department receiving and credit department transfering"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Use the information  below to Answer questions 46 and 47.<br>\r\nAmong Limited invoiced goods at a cost of N10,000 to its Ikeja branch at a marginal of 20%. The branch later returned goods worth N1,200 at invoice price to the head office.<br>\r\nThe profit marginal should be?","options":["debit to goods sent to branch account","debit to branch stock adjustment account","credit to branch adjustment account","credit to branch stock adjustment account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"What is the correct entry in the head office books at the point of initial transfer of the goods?","options":["Branch stock account would be credited with","Branch  stock account would be debited with N12,000","Goods sent to branch account would be debited with N10,800","Goods sent to branch account would be credited with N12,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Capital and revenue expenditures of government are usually accounted for under funds which include?","options":["A personal advances, technical, special trust and","technical, special trusth and commercial funds","personal advances, treasury clearance and special trusth funds","commercial loans and treasury clearance funds"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Which of the following account is kept by local governments in Nigeria?","options":["Balance sheet","Advances account","Debtors account","Profit account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The conventional sources of public revenue includes?","options":["loans,taxation, foreign reserves and dividends","interest, royalties, taxation and loans","crude oil, interest, posted price and taxation","taxtion, deficit budgeting, royalties and loans"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Appropriation Account<br>\r\n<br>\r\n                    Kudu            Wale <br>\r\nInterest on capital  750             550<br>\r\nSalaries              800             600<br>\r\nShare of profits      3,300           3,300<br>\r\nDetermine the net profit of the partnership.","options":["N 9,300","N 6,600","N4,850","N 4,450"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Use the information to answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nAminu and Sons credit purchases (Extract] as at February 1996.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFeb         1Credit balances             40, 000<br>\r\n             Debit balances              1, 000<br>\r\nFeb          28 Purchases journal totals  500,000<br>\r\n             Returns outwards journal totals 50,000<br>\r\n             Cheques paid to suppliers      400,000<br>\r\n           Promissory notes sent to suppliers 30,000<br>\r\n              Credit balance in the purchases ledger set off against debit balances in the sales ledger  2000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe Total for the purchases ledger control account is","options":["N 480,000","N490000","N 500,000","N540,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Use the information to answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAminu and Sons credit purchases (Extract] as at February 1996.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFeb 1Credit balances 40, 000<br>\r\nDebit balances 1, 000<br>\r\nFeb 28 Purchases journal totals 500,000<br>\r\nReturns outwards journal totals 50,000<br>\r\nCheques paid to suppliers 400,000<br>\r\nPromissory notes sent to suppliers 30,000<br>\r\nCredit balance in the purchases ledger set off against debit balances in the sales ledger 2000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the balance c\/d in the purchases ledger control account?","options":["N 2,000","N 8, 000","N 40, 000","N49,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTotal cash received from debtors       30,000<br>\r\nTotal purchases for the period         21,000<br>\r\nAmount owed by debtors at the beginning of the period  4,000<br>\r\nEquipment bought                         2,500<br>\r\nAmount owed by debtors at the end of the period 3,000<br>\r\nDetermine the value of sales for the period","options":["N29,000","N 31,500","N46,500","N50,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Use information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital: opening balance        307,000<br>\r\nclosing balance                 342,000<br>\r\nNet profit for the period       121,600<br>\r\nOpening stock                   98,800<br>\r\nPurchases                        706,000<br>\r\nCarriage inwards                 17,500<br>\r\nCost of goods sold               740,700<br>\r\nTotal selling , general and <br>\r\nadministration expenses          526,000<br>\r\nDiscount received                9, 650<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the closing stock for the period?","options":["N 69,300","N81,300","N81,600","N106,400"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Use information below to answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCapital: opening balance 307,000<br>\r\nclosing balance 342,000<br>\r\nNet profit for the period 121,600<br>\r\nOpening stock 98,800<br>\r\nPurchases 706,000<br>\r\nCarriage inwards 17,500<br>\r\nCost of goods sold 740,700<br>\r\nTotal selling , general and<br>\r\nadministration expenses 526,000<br>\r\nDiscount received 9, 650<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the gross profit for the period?","options":["N 535,650","N628,300","N637,950","N647,600"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe quick ratio is","options":["0. 82: 1","0. 91:1","0.95:1","1:53:1"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Determine the owners equity","options":["N200,000","N 215,000","N275,000","N755,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The Act establishing the institute of Chartered Accountants of Nigeria (ICAN) came into force on?","options":["Ist September, 1960","Ist October, 1960","Ist October,1963","Ist ,  September,1965"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Cost reports for the intention of management should reflect?","options":["as much details as possible","summary figures only","details of non-controllable expenses","cost and comparable data useful in decision-making"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Responsibility accounting is particularly concerned with?","options":["histoical accounting","controllable costs","storekeeping","valuation of stock"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"An advantage of the use of the voucher system is that it?","options":["reduces the number of cheques that will be writen during any given period","provides a highly flexible system for handling unusual transactions","provides a comprehensive record of business done with particular suppliers","ensure that every expenditure is reviewed and verified before payment is made"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A business transaction is recorded in the books of account when the?","options":["owner of the business invests his N10,000 in another company","business retains part of ofits profits for future expansion purposes","business invest applies for overdraft facilities from its bankers","owner of the business collects N5,000 from the accountant"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"When a transaction causes an assets account to increase, there is?","options":["a decrease of equal amount inthe owner's  equity account","an increase in a liability account","an increase of equal amonut in another assets account","a decrease of equal amount in a liability account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"N<br>\r\nBank account             59,410<br>\r\nCapital account          50,000<br>\r\nPurchase account         20,000<br>\r\nRent                      2,500<br>\r\nStationery                   90<br>\r\ntypewriter                6,500<br>\r\nSales                    38,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn preparing a trial from the list of balances given above, what is the total in debit and credit columns?","options":["N147,910","N138,500","N88,500","N85,800"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The purchase of two generators by Hassan Electronics Enterprises should be recorded as?","options":["an acquistion of fixed assets","an expenses in its general office expenses account","an acquistion of stock","a part of capital in the capital account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"If the inventory at the end of the current year is understated and the error is not caught during the following year, the effect is to?","options":["overstate income this year and understate in next year","understate income this year and overstate in next year","understate this year's income with no effect on the next year's","overstate the income for the two-year period"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The total of the  discounts received column in the cash book is posted to the?","options":["credit of the discounts received account","debit of the discounts allowed account","credit of the discounts allowed accoun","debit of the discounts received  account"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer questions 11 and 12.<br>\r\nThe initial imprest as at July Ist was N500. Petty cash vouchers with the custodian by July 15th added up to N394. An IOU slip received from a co-worker was N65 and there was a shortage of N5 cash. The co-worker made refund on July 18th just before the imprest was replenished.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat was the actual cash in the till as at 15th July?","options":["N106","N101","N70","N36"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The amount required to replenish the payments made from the imprest was?","options":["N399","N394","N358","N101"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"State Bank collected a note for A-Makura Company. This collection, not yet recorded in AL-Makura's  books, appears on the bank reconciliation as?","options":["an addition to balance per book","a deduction from balance per bank statement","an addition to balance per bank statement","a deduction from balance per books"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Mayana Corporation uses special journals to record its transactions. If one of Mayana's customers returns merchandize purchased with cash (for a refund), it makes an entry in the?","options":["cash receipts journal","sales journal","general journal","cash disbursement  journal."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Sobande Incorporation acquired a machine that involved the following expenditures and related factors.<br>\r\n                                     <br>\r\n                                         N<br>\r\nGross invoice price                     15,000<br>\r\nSales tax                                  900<br>\r\nPurchases discount taken                   300<br>\r\nFreight                                    750<br>\r\nAssembly of machine                        500<br>\r\nInstallation of machine                    800<br>\r\nAssorted spare parts for future use       1200<br>\r\nTuring and adjusting machine               700<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the initial accounting cost of the machine?","options":["N19,550","N18,950","N18,350","N17,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A pottery company had sales of N176,000 during the current period and a gross profit rate of 40%.<br>\r\nThe company's cost of merchandize available for sale during the period was N128,000. The company's ending inventory is?","options":["N22,400","N32,000","N51,200","N76,800"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"On Ist January, 1993, lobo Company purchased equipment for N18,000. it uses straight-line depreciation and estimates an eight-year useful life and a N2,000 salvage value. On 31st December, 1996, it sells the equipment for N80,0000. In recording this sales, it should reflect?","options":["N10,000 loss","N2,000 loss","N6,000 gain","N8,000 gain"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The balance on a purchase ledger control account represents the?","options":["present amount that a business owes its suppliers at date","total credit avaiable to the end of the year to be utilized in future","total credit the business enjoyed for the particular year from its suppliers","total credit owd the business by its customers"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A powerful instrument of control over both the sales ledger and the clek whose duty is to post the ledger is the?","options":["total debtors account","purchase day book","sales day book","cash book"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Mini Enterprises Sales Ledger as at 31\/12\/94<br>\r\nread:<br>\r\n                                  N <br>\r\n    Balance b\/f                  12750<br>\r\n    Total credit  sales          28185 <br>\r\n    Payments by debtors          12112<br>\r\n    Discount allowed             638<br>\r\n    Sales returns                1500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPrepare the sales ledger control account and determine the balance due from debtors.","options":["N40,935","N27,961","N26,685","N1,185"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Determine the year''s purchase from the following information relating to a firm.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n                                         <br>\r\nTotal creditor''s b\/f                    N  7,200<br>\r\nTotal cash payment to suppliers          N  98,800<br>\r\nTotal creditors c\/f                      N   8,400","options":["N7,200","N98,800","N100,000","N105,800"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Derive the total sales figure from the following information extracted from a firm's cash book and other relevant records.<br>\r\n                                      <br>\r\n Total debtors b\/f                       N  5,600<br>\r\n Total cash receipts from debtors <br>\r\n and cash sales                          N  153,000  <br>\r\n Total debtors c\/f                       N   6,800","options":["N6,800","N153,000","N154,200","N159,800"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The statement of affairs prepared from incomplete records can be described as?","options":["the summary of all the business transactions of the trader ascertained by the accountant","a balance sheet at a particular date showing the assets and liabilities of the business","a schedule of all the business ventures entered into for the period to which the records relates","the statement that shows the profit or loss made during the period"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The contribution marginal on a job is the?","options":["gross profit","net profit","excess of sales revnue over variable costs","difference between fixed and variable costs"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The objective of allocating all costs to producer is to?","options":["produce a scientifically accurate cost","avoid unallocated overhead and compute total accounts","co-odinate the cost and financial accounts","compute the contribution of the product to the final profit"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question 28 and 29.<br>\r\nRaw materials inventory at the beginning of a period was N 46,800 and at the close of the period there was a balance of N38,600. From the purchases made during the period, defective materials costing N9,200 were returned. Cost of materials consumed during the period was N448,500.<br>\r\nWhat was the total purchases made during the period?","options":["N497,100","N457,700","N449,500","N440,300"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"What was the cost of materials available for use during the period?","options":["N487,100","N449,500","N448,500","N440,300"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The limitations of the receipts and payments account arise mainly because of the reliance on?","options":["cash movement as evidence of transaction","the acconuting officer to report","the capital account of the organization","the transaction papers as evidence of transaction"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The trading account is to a sole trader what income and expenditure account is to a?","options":["partnership","public limited organization","manufacturing organization","non-profit making organization"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A non-profit-making organization differs from a profit-making one in that?","options":["it does not earn income","proceeds from sale of shares form part of its income","all its income is committed","annual subscriptions and levies form part of its income"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Which of the following indicate that a partnership business is in place? <br>\r\n(i) There is a business<br>\r\n(ii)It is run commonly by partners <br>\r\n(iii)It has profit-making in view<br>\r\n(iv) Partners' liability is limited","options":["i and  ii only","i, ii and iii only","i, iii and iv only","ii, iii and iv only"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"When forming a partnership, new partners should record non-monetary assets on the new partnership's books at?","options":["their current fair market values","their historical costs  when first use","their historical costs when first purchase by each new partner","the highest values practical so that future income tax deductions are maximized"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Umar and Ahemed share profit and losses equally and have capital balances of N40,000 and N60,000 respectively. If bdullahi purchases one-third interest with no bonus, how much will he have to contribute to the partnership?","options":["N33,333","N40,000","N44,444","N50,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Which of the following is an intangible asset and a measure of a firm's superior earning power?","options":["Patent","Goodwill","Trademark","Right issue"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The price paid by an acquiring company is the?","options":["premium","purchase consideration","sales consideration","conversion fee"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Use the information below to answer question 38 and 39.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDan and Baker are in partnership with capital of N50,000 and N30,000 each. The partnership agreement provides that:(i) profits be shared in the ratio of capital. (ii) Baker be paid a salary of N8,000.<br>\r\n(iii) both partners earn interest on capital at 6% p.a.<br>\r\n(iv) both partners pay interest on drawing at 6% p.a. <br>\r\n At the end of the year, Dan drew N15,000 while Baker drew N14,000 in four installment on 31\/3,30\/6,30\/9 and 31\/12. The net profit for the year was N48,000. N5,000 is to be written off the Goodwill account.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the interest on the drawing by Baker?","options":["N210","N315","N450","N840"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Dan and Baker are in partnership with capitals of N50,000 and N30,000 each. The partnership agreement provides that: (i) profits be shared in the ratio of capital (ii) both partners earn interest on capital at 6% p.a (iv) both parents pay interest on drawings at 6% p.a. At the end of the year, Dan drew N15,000 while baker drew N14,000 in four installments on 31\/3, 30\\6, 30\\9 and 30\\12. The net profit for the year was N48,000. N5000 is to be written off the goodwill account.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDetermine the total interest on capital due to the partners?","options":["N1200","N1800","N3000","N4800"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The ordinary shareholders enjoy the following rights except the right to?","options":["vote at annual general meetings","elect the board of directors","participate in additional issues of shares","receive dividends at a preddetermined rate"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Granada Corporation has net assets of N600,000 and contributed capital of N180,000. The corporation has 30,000 shares of common stock outstanding with no preferred stock. This suggest that the corporation has?","options":["a book value of N14 per share","a book value of N20 per share","a deficit of N420,000","retained earnings of N600,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Under which of these conditions can a company issue shares at discount? (i)A resolution must be passed at a general meeting (ii) The amount of discount must be stated in the resolution (iii) The share must have existed for at least six years (iv) On the order of a court.","options":["i, ii and iii only","i, ii and iv only","i, iii, and iv only","ii, iii and iv only"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The part of equity which is payable on winding up is called?","options":["general reserve","revenue  reserve","capital reserve","normal reserve"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"To compute gearing ratio, divide?","options":["profit by capital employed","current assets by current liability","profit by total assets","long-term debts  by equity capital"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Which of the following entries is effected by a department when goods are charged to it at selling prices?","options":["stock account is debited","purchases  account is debited","stock account is credited","mark-up account is debited"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The difference between the closure of the books of a branch and those of a separate company is that?","options":["there is retained earnings account on the branch books","the revenue and expenses account is closed to branch current account","there is no retained earnings account on the branch","the revenue and expenses account is not closed to the home office current account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The term fiscal compliance means?","options":["al financial and related laws and regulations are adhered to","only the  budget fir the current period is complied with and no deficits allowed","all physical assets requirements have been met","fiscal planning is necessary for proper accountabilit in the public sector"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"In a public corporation, the capital expenditure incurred in a financial period is?","options":["spread over the useful life of the assets through depreciation","apportioned at a pre-determined rate stipulated by law","written off in the year in which they occur","merged with recurrent  expenditure and reported in one required lump sum"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Money not required to meet chargeable  expenditure in any fiscal year under cash accounting, should be?","options":["surrendered to the consolidated revenue fund","carried forward to the next financial year","reserved to meetany deficits or contingencies","returned to the taxpayer"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"If a monthly insurance premium is remitted to a company by the state government, the initial deductions from employees are recorded in?","options":["the general fund","agency fund","special fund","general long-term fund"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The most important reason for studying accounting is that","options":["the information provided by accounting is  useful in making decision","Accounting plays  an important role in the society","the study of Accounting leads to challeging career","Accounting provides gross profit information"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"In preparing accounting records, the owner of a business and the business are treated as","options":["the same person","having business relationship","separate legal entities","partners"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Creditors use Accounting information for the purpose of","options":["planning sales to a company","controlling a company's affairs","investing in a company","assessing a company's liquidity"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The instrument that are generated when firms enter into business transactions with others are called","options":["purchase document","journals","source documents","invoices"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The document that is used to acknowledge the acceptance of the return of goods by the seller from the buyer is known as","options":["credit note","debit note","invoice","voucher"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The effect of the payment of liability is that it","options":["increase both assets and liabilities","increase assets and decrease liabilities","decrease assets and increase liabilities","decrease both assets and liabilities"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Books of original entry are used for","options":["recording business transactions","the adjustment of accounts","reminding the book keeping to post transactions  in the ledger","informing the bookkeeper about the state of affairs"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The term 'posting' in Accounting refers to","options":["recording entries in the journal","transferring the balance in the ledger to the trial balance","tracing amounts from the journal to the ledger to find errors","transferring entries to the ledger from the journal"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Erroneous rearrangement of financial figures such as writing N624 as N 264 is called","options":["transposition","principle","commission","omission"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Which of the following demonstrates the imprest system?","options":["Float \u2192 expenses paid \u2192 cash in bank \u2192 float","Float \u2192 cash from bank \u2192 expenses paid \u2192 float","Float \u2192 expenses paid\u2192 cash from bank \u2192 float","Float \u2192 cash in bank \u2192 expenses paid \u2192 float"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"When the sum of money appears on the credit side of the cash book, but not on the debit side of the bank statement, the sum is regarded as","options":["uncredited cheques","dishonoured cheques","direct remittance to the bank","unpresented cheques"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"An examination of the cash book on 3rd August 1993 showed a different balance from the bank statement of 31st July, 1993 which read N722. Uncredited cheques were Bimpe N40; Wale N60 while unpresented cheques were; Usman N20, Kalu N32 and Musa N70. What is the cash book balance after the reconciliation?","options":["N700","N770","N800","N822"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"On the 30\/5\/93 Tolu & Co. paid 2 years rent of N50,000 which was debited to the rent account. <br>\r\nAt 31\/12\/93, what portion of that amount was prepaid?","options":["N14,583","N25,000","N35,417","N37,415"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"On the 30\/5\/93 Tolu & Co. paid 2 years rent of N50,000 which was debited to the rent account. <br>\r\nThe adjustment needed as at 31st December 1993 is?","options":["debit rent account and credited adjustment account","debit prepayment account and credit rent account","debit rent account and credit prepayment account","debit adjustment account and credit prepayment account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The receipt of cash from a customer who bought goods with N800 list price, 25% trade discount and 2\/10, n\/30 terms would, if paid within the discount period, amount to","options":["N576","N588","N600","N624"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"At the end of a financial period, the trading profit and loss account of a company showed a profit of N120,000. It was however discovered that revenue of N12,000 was recorded as expenses while expenses of N4,000 had been recorded as revenue. What should be the correct profit for the period?","options":["N104,000","N128,000","N136,000","N144,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nNet profit-----------------------N25,000<br>\r\nCost of sale---------------------N25,000<br>\r\nSales----------------------------N85,000<br>\r\nDetermine the total expenses.","options":["N45,000","N35,000","N25,000","N15,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Given: capital N13,000; office machinery, N9,000; creditors N900, stock of goods N1,550; debtors, N275; cash at bank, N5,075 and loan from Jumbo, N2,000. What is the balance sheet total?","options":["N19,500","N18,500","N17,900","N15,900"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The records of wages due but not yet paid is an example of an adjustment for","options":["apportionment of revenue between two periods","recognizing accrued expenses","recognizing unaccounted revenue","recognizing prepaid expenses"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The process of allocating the cost of an intangible assets over its useful life is known as","options":["depreciation","extraction","depletion","amortization"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The principle use of control accounts is to","options":["localize error within the ledger","prevent fraud","increase sales","record assets and liabilities"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"In the absence of a sales day book or sales account the credit for sales can be computed from","options":["creditors control account","debtors control account","opening figures of the balance sheet","closing figures of the balance sheet"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"which of the following conditions best represents the net effect of discount allowed on credit sales on the accounts of the business?","options":["decrease in the closing balance of sales ledger control accout","increase in net profit","increase in the value of sales","decrease in the value of purchases in the trading account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The total of the creditors at the beginning of the year was N4,600 and at the end of the year N5,250. During the year, N26,500 was paid to suppliers and N130 was received in discounts from these suppliers. The purchases for the year would be","options":["N26,630","N27,038","N27,150","N27,280"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nCapital at the beginning...............N20 000<br>\r\nDrawings...............................N3  000<br>\r\nCapital................................N30 000<br>\r\nNew capital introduced.................N8  000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the profit for the period?","options":["N4 000","N5 000","N6 000","N8 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Which of the following stock valuation methods is suitable under inflationary conditions?","options":["FIFO","LIFO","Simple average","Weighted average"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The understatement of closing value of work-in-process would have the effect of?","options":["understating cost of goods manufactured","overstating prime cost of manufactured","overstating cost of goods manufactured","undersating prime cost of goods manufactured"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Emeka Manufacturing Company (Extract) Manufacturing Account.<br>\r\nDirect material.....................N5 000<br>\r\nDirect labour.......................N4 500<br>\r\nDirect expenses.....................N3 000<br>\r\nFactory overhead....................N2 500<br>\r\nSelling distribution................N1 500<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculating the production cost?","options":["N16 500","N15 000","N14 000","N12 500"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Adamu, Babaji and Chukwu are in partnership and they share profit and losses on ratio 3:2:1. Their respective capitals are N20 000, N15 000 and  N5 000 on which on which they are entitle to interest at 5% per annum. The profit for the year before charging interest on capital amounted to N5 500.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCalculate the profit for Adamu?","options":["N583","N1 000","N1 167","N1 750"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Faruk and Osawe are in partnership sharing profits and losses in the ratio of 3:7. Faruk is to receive a salary of N9 000. In one accounting period, the business recorded a loss of N1 500 (before deduction of Faruk's salary). The appropriate distribution of the net loss would be?","options":["Faruk, (N450); Osawe,  (N1 050)","Faruk, (N3 150); Osawe, (N7350)","Faruk, (2 250); Osawe,  (N7 350)","Faruk, (N450); Osawe,  (N1 050)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Share premium can be used to?<br>\r\ni.  write off discount on shares <br>\r\nii. give loans to directors<br>\r\niii.pay dividends<br>\r\niv. pay company's formation expenses.","options":["i and iv only","i and iii only","ii and iii only","iii and iv only"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Alabede (NIG) limited issued 50 000 ordinary shares of N1 each at a market value of N2.50 each. the share premium is?","options":["N125 000","N500 000","N50 000","N25 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"What is the balance of the bank account shown above?","options":["N88 500 debit","N 88 500 credit","N 59 410 credit","N 59 410 debit"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"In analyzing incomplete records, which of the following should be investigated?","options":["the general ledger","the purchases day book and sales day book","the nature of trading activities and the basis on which goods are sold","the asset register together with the  depreciation schedule"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Given:                 N<br>\r\nDirect material    -   10 000<br>\r\nDirect labour      -   5000<br>\r\nDirect expenses    -   2000<br>\r\nFactory overhead   -   4000<br>\r\nWhat is the prime cost?","options":["N21 000","N 17 000","N 15 000","N 6 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The difference between a trading account and a manufacturing account is that while the manufacturing account","options":["has no particular period, the trading account has","does not consider the cost of goods involved, the trading account does","is concerned with the cost of production, the trading account is not","is not concerned with the stock of raw materials the rading account is"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"An income and expenditure account is a summary of","options":["all income and expenditure during a period","revenue income and expenditure during a period","receipts and payments during a period","the trading income a period"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Additional information :<br>\r\n1: 1: 93  31 : 12  : 93<br>\r\n                            N      N<br>\r\nSubscription in arrears     300    450<br>\r\nFurniture                   7000<br>\r\nSubscription received<br>\r\nin advance                   500    400<br>\r\nRate owing                    50     60<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSubscription relating to the accounting year 1993 in the income and expenditure account is","options":["N 15 050","N 14 550","N14 300","N 13 400"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Accumulated fund on 1st January 1993 is","options":["N 8 570","N8 470","N 850","N7 520"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"On partnership dissolution, if a partner's capital account has a debit balance and the partnr is insolvent, the deficiency will, in accordance with the decision of the case of Garner v Murray, be","options":["borne by all the partners","borne by the insolvent partner","written off","borne by the solvent partners"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"A company has 5% debentures worth N500 000 ordinary share capital N 2 000 000, and preference shares N1500 000. if the company made a profit of N 1 000 000, the debenture interest would amount to","options":["N 1 000 000","N 500 000","N 50 000","N 25 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"A dividend of 10% in a company on 500 000 ordinary shares of N 1 nominal value has been declared, How much will a shareholder receive if he has 200 shares?","options":["N 500 000","N 50 000","N200","N 20"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"What is the working capital?","options":["N12 000","N 11 000","N 8 000","N4 000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The acid test ratio in the company is","options":["1:1","1:2","2:3","3:2"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"If goods are invoiced to the branch at cost and the invoice par value is N 2 000 with 5%discount rate, can remitted to the head office is","options":["N2 100","N 200","N 1 900","N 100"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Which of the following are advantages of departmental accounts?<br>\r\nI. The department making the highest profit can be easily determined<br>\r\n<br>\r\nII. The capital of the business can be calculated easily<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIII. Easy knowledge of the sources of funding <br>\r\n<br>\r\nIV. Encouragement of healthy rivalry among the various departments","options":["I and IV only","II and III only","II and IV only","III and IV only"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Public sector accounting is based on","options":["cash","accrual","budget","consolidated fund"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The end result of governmental accounting procedure is to","options":["keep proper records of government expenditures","give financial information to the public and investors","produce timely and accurate financial reports for legislators and the public","give information on the performance of public enterprises"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The Current account above had some errors in the arrangement of the accounts for Musa, Kalu and Lawal<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe Correct closing balance for Musa's current account is","options":["N36 000 Credit","N16 600 credit","N16 600 debit","N1 800 credit"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The Current account above had some errors in the arrangement of the accounts for Musa, Kalu and Lawal]<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe correct closing balance for lawal's current account is","options":["N21 100 debit","N14 740 debit","N14 740 credit","N540 credit"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"which of the following factors has aided the development of accounting?","options":["The emergence of nation states","The discovery of mineral resources in commercial quantity","the growth in size of businesses and separation of ownership and management","the development  and management of sophisticated monetary system"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Which of the following concept stipulates that accounting profit is the difference between revenue and expenses?","options":["Accrual concept","Conservatism concept","Prudence concept","Materiality concept"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"An effective accounting system should provide information","options":["on new product and methods","for cutomer feed back and requirement","on internal and external reporting for managers and third parties","for promoters, directors, labour union and distributors"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Which of the following accounting records are source documents?","options":["Journal and ledgers","Sales invoice and cash book","Cash book and debit note","sales invoice and debit note"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Given: Motor van, N3,600, Premises, N5,000; Loan from R. Nwaeke, N1,000; Cash at bank; N1,650; stock of goods N4,800; Creditors, N2,560; Cash in hand, N250 and debtors N6,910. calculate the capital figure.","options":["N19,650","N18,650","N17,850","NN16,850"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Which of the following transaction is BEST recorded in the general journal?","options":["Payment of rent with cheque","Purchase of stock with cash","Purchase of an asset on credit terms","Transfer of cash from head office branch"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Diamond Ringo business was started when Mr. Diamond brought in a cheque of N500,000, which was paid into the bank account. Which of the following entries properly records the transaction?","options":["Cash account was credited with N500,000 and capital account was debited with N500,000","Bank account was debited with N500,000 and capital account was credited with N500,000","Bank account was accredited with N500,000","Mr. diamond acount was debited with N500,000 and the cheque account was credited with N500,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"One major advantage of ledger is that it","options":["is a book of original entry","is only accessible to share holders during liquidation","removes the need for preparing a balance sheet after each transaction","can be used by any type of business"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"A trail balance is usually prepared by an accountant from account balances in the ledger for the purpose of","options":["classifying accounts in the ledger","testing arithmetical accuracies of the ledger account balances","identifying the balance sheet items","providing a basis for establishing  the accountant's competence"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"What are the advantages of an imprest petty cash book?<br>\r\nI   cheques can be drawn easily<br>\r\nII  A cheque on the use of cash<br>\r\nIII Liability of the petty cashier is limited to the value of petty cash<br>\r\nIV  Loses through the petty cashier can be minimized","options":["I, II and III only","I, II and IV only","I, III and IV only","II, III and IV only"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Bola, UTC's regular customer, owed N1,00 on account of a radio bought. If he sent in a cheque for N1,500, UTC would send him a","options":["credit note","debit note","journal voucher","way bill"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"A payment of cash of N20 to John was entered on the receipt side of the cash book in error and credited to John's account. Which of the following journal entry can be used to correct the error?","options":["John: N40 Dr, cash: N40 Cr","Cash: N40 Dr, John: N40 Cr","John: N20 Dr, cash: N20 Cr","Cash: N20 Dr, John: N20 Cr"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The following represent extracts from the trading account of a retail outlet for a given month:<br>\r\nOpening stock  N2,400<br>\r\nClosing stock  N6,400<br>\r\nOther expenses N2,000<br>\r\nSales          N11,000<br>\r\nProfit         N900<br>\r\nWhat is the purchase figure for the month?","options":["N13,000","N12,100","N12,000","N11,200"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Adama's bank account showed an overdraft of N600 on 31st march. On going through the account, it was discovered that the N1,080 paid into the account on 29th March had not been credited. what should be the balance in Adama's cash accounts?","options":["N1,680 Dr","N1,080 Cr","N600 Dr","N480 Cr"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Why are adjustments in the profit and loss account necessary?","options":["To cover some expenses of the following year","To ascertain the actual expenses incurred and income earned during the year","To show the provision made during the year","To show the total expenses paid and income received during the year"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Sales ledger control account contains the total amount in respect of","options":["creditors","debtors","investors","shareholders"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The purchase ledger control account of a company had an opening balance of N45,600 credit and closing balance of N72,600 credit. The company made payments of 437,000 to credit suppliers during the period: and had discount received of N18,600 on this account. What were the credit purchase  for the period?","options":["N509,600","N482,600","N428,600","N418,400"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The starting point for the production of accounts from incomplete records is to","options":["ascertain the total sales","compute the opening stock of goods sold","verify the total purchase","prepare an opening statement of affairs"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"I.   A retailer when fixing his selling price adds one-quarter to the cost of the article<br>\r\nII.  The expenses of the retailer is 10% of his sales<br>\r\nIII. The total sales is N23,000<br>\r\nIV.  he turned over his stock five times in the year.<br>\r\nCompute the average amount of stock in hand at cost price","options":["N3,860","N3,806","N3,680","N3,086"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"I.   A retailer when fixing his selling price adds one-quarter to the cost of the article<br>\r\nII.  The expenses of the retailer is 10% of his sales<br>\r\nIII. The total sales is N23,000<br>\r\nIV.  he turned over his stock five times in the year.<br>\r\nThe net profit for the year is","options":["N5,750","N5,650","N3,200","N2,300"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Given:<br>\r\nPrime cost                      N220,000<br>\r\nFactory cost                    N32,000<br>\r\nwork in progress at beginning   N25,000<br>\r\nwork in progress at close       N19,000<br>\r\nAdministrative expenses         N21,000<br>\r\nDetermine the production cost","options":["N296,000","N277,000","N258,000","N246,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The factory cost of producing goods is made up of","options":["prime cost and factory overhead","prime cost and office overhead","raw materials consumed and fixed cost","Raw materials and administrative overhead"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The following information is provided for amusa company limited , a manufacturer <br><br>\r\nPrime cost                                     N999,000<br><br>\r\nManufacturing overhead                         N132,000<br><br>\r\nClosing work in progress                       N75,000<br><br>\r\nvalues of finished goods transferred to the<br><br>\r\ntrading account                             N1,116,000<br><br>\r\nIf including in the manufacturing overhead were rents of N5,000 paid in advance, what is the opening work in progress for the period?","options":["N85,000","N80,000","N70,000","N65,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Subscription in arrears are","options":["Credited to the income and expenditure account and shown as a liability in the balance sheet","debited to the income and expenditure account and shown as an asset in the balance sheet","credited to the income and expenditure account and shown as a liability in the balance sheet","debited to the income and expenditure account and shown as a liability in the balance sheet"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Where a non-profit making organization prepares the account using accruals basis of reporting, the statement showing how well the organization is doing is the","options":["appropriation account","balance sheet","income and expenditure account","receipts and payment account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"A member of a club paid N1,000 as is subscription for 1993 and N1,200 as subscription for 1992. If the financial year of the society ended on 31st December 1993, the N1,200 subscription will be treated in the balance sheet as","options":["current asset","current liability","capital","profit"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Which of the following is a strong feature of partnership?","options":["The life of the partnership is generally assumed to be indefinite","The owners are liable personally for all debts of the business","The transfer of ownership interest is frequent and easy to accomplish","The partnership is complex to form because of many legal and reporting requirements"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Interest on a partner's drawings is debited to the","options":["Partners current account and credited to the profit and loss appropriation account","profit and loss appropriation account and credited to the partner's current account","profit and loss account and credited to the partner's current account","Partner's current account and credited to the profit and loss account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"A partnership on admitting a new member, revalued the business' land and building from N30,000 to N70,00. The difference of N40,000 should be","options":["credited to land and building account","debited to asset revaluation account","credited to asset revaluation account","credited to profit and loss appropriation account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Halidu and Hamed are business partners with N30,000 and N20,000 capital respectively. At the end of the financial year, a profit of N12,000, which included Halidu's salary of N3,000 was made.<br>\r\nHalidu's share of the profit is","options":["N7,500","N6,000","N5,400","N4,500"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Halidu and Hamed are business partners with N30,000 and N20,000 capital respectively. At the end of the financial year, a profit of N12,000, which included Halidu's salary of N3,000 was made.<br>\r\nHamed's share of the profit should be","options":["credited to partners' capital account","credited to partners' current account","credited to appropriation account","debited to partners' drawing account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The conversion of a partners business into a limited liability company affords the","options":["general partners the chance of enjoying the limited laibility protection","limited liability partners the  chance of enjoying the limited liability protecction","Creditors the chance of enjoying the limited liabiity protection","debtors the chance of enjoying the limited liability protection"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Which of the following ratios gives an idea of the liquidity of a firm?","options":["Turnover ratio","Quick ratio","Debit ratio","Dividend yield"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"A total of 400,000 shares of N1 each are to be issued by Sariki company Ltd at a price of N1.20 per share. Application were received for 600,000 shares out of which 100,000 were dishonored. If the available share were distributed pro-rata, what refund will be due a subscriber who applied for 5,000 shares?","options":["N1,000","N1,200","N4,800","N6,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The measure of a company's ability to pays its debts quickly is called","options":["Current ratio","turnover ratio","acid test ratio","return of investment"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Departmental accounts re maintained to ascertain the","options":["profits of   the entire organization","contribution of each department","expenses of each department","sales of each department"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The Asa branch of Emene company Ltd, made a sales of N549,000 from the goods sent from the head office during the period ended 31\/12\/94. These sales were based on a 22% mark up. If branch expenses were N34,400 and there were no discrepancies, what should be the profit of the branch for the period?","options":["N6,500","N64,600","N85,380","N514,600"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Which of the following statement is correct about the head office current account and the branch current account?","options":["Both always have debit balances","both always have credit balances","the head office current account has a credit balance while the branch current account has a debit balance","the head office current account has a debit balance while the branch current account has a credit balance"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Which of the following are sources of revenue to state government in Nigeria?<br>\r\nI   Statutory allocation<br>\r\nII  Fines from customary courts<br>\r\nIII Petroleum tax<br>\r\nIV  Income tax<br>\r\nIV","options":["I and II only","II and III","I and IV","III and IV"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Eko Local Government expenditure<br>\r\nHospital building ---------------------- N200,000<br>\r\nDrugs ---------------------------------- N180,000<br>\r\nHospital beds and mattresses ------------ N40,000<br>\r\nDoctors' and nurses' salaries ---------- N120,000<br>\r\nAdministrative expenses ----------------- N50,000<br>\r\nCapital expenditure is","options":["N420,000","N380,000","N240,000","N200,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Eko Local Government expenditure<br>\r\nHospital building ---------------------- N200,000<br>\r\nDrugs ---------------------------------- N180,000<br>\r\nHospital beds and mattresses ------------ N40,000<br>\r\nDoctors' and nurses' salaries ---------- N120,000<br>\r\nAdministrative expenses ----------------- N50,000<br>\r\nRecurrent expenditure is","options":["N390,000","N360,000","N350,000","N170,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"A government accounting systems must make sure that","options":["revenue exceeds expenditure","all applicable legal provisions are complied with","capital expenditure is equal to revenue","capital project fund is tied to recurrent expenditure"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Equity shareholders' fund is","options":["N133 000","N 120 000","N113 000","N 100 000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"If a 10% dividend is approved, what is the dividend payable to ordinary shareholders?","options":["N 13 000","N 11 300","N 10 000","N 8 000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"A charitable club has the following figures:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n                                    N<br>\r\nSubscriptions received in 1991    2 800<br>\r\nSubscriptions unpaid in 1990        300<br>\r\nSubscriptions paid for 1992         150<br>\r\nSubscriptions due 1991              180<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow much should be charged to the income and expenditure of this club as subscription for 1991?","options":["N 2 530","N 2 680","N 2 830","N 2 980"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Accumulated depreciation on the asset as at 31\/12\/81 was","options":["N 2 487 500 .00","N 2 736 250 . 00","N 4 511 192.00","N 4 975 000 .00"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"THE BOOK VALUE OF THE ASSET AS AT 31\/12\/86 WAS","options":["N 3 731 250.00","N 2 487 500.00","N 1 268 750.00","N1 020 000. 00"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Trade creditors account was maintained at 25% of the capital.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat was the balance in the trade creditors account as at 31\/12\/92?","options":["N 29 800","N 29 500","N29 400","N 29 000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"What was the balance showed wages, N2 500 and a note stated that N 500 wages were due but unpaid when preparing final accounts and loss account with","options":["N 3 000 and show wages accrued N 500 in the balance sheet","N2 000 and show wages accrued N500 in the balance sheet","N 3 000 and show wages perpaid N 500 in the balance sheet","N 2000 and show wages paid in advance N500 in the balace sheet"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The trial balance showed wages, N2 500 and a note stated that N500 wages,  were due but unpaid when preparing final accounts and loss account with","options":["N 3000 and show wages accrued N 500 in the balance sheet in the balance sheet","N 2 000 and show wages accured N500 in the balance sheet","N 3000 and show wages prepaid N 500 in the balance sheet","N 2000 and show wages paid in advance N 500 in the balance sheet"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The term \"accounting period\" is used to refer to the","options":["time span during which taxes are paid to the inland revenue board","budget period, usually one year, relied on by the accountant","time span, usually one year, covered by financial statement","period within which debtors are expected to settle accounts"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Assigning revenues to the accounting period in which goods were sold or services rendered and expenses incurred is known as","options":["passing of entries","consistency convention","matching concept","adjusting for revenue"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The accounting convention which states that profit must not be recognized until realized while all losses should be adequately provided for it termed","options":["materiality","objectivity","consistency","conservatism"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Accounting information is used by investors and creditors of a company to predict","options":["future cash flows of the company","future tax payments of the company","potential merger candidates for the company","appropriate remunerations for the company's staff"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Antics Electronic Company recently bought six generators. Which of the following is the correct method of recording this transaction?","options":["Debit generator account and credit cash account","Debit purchases account and credit cash account","Debit cash accounts and credit purchases account","Debit cash account and credit generator account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"When a business incurs labour cost in installing a fixed asset, the cost is treated as","options":["additional cost to the asset","business wages and salaries","installation cost of the asset","business cost of the asset"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"What is the cardinal rule of the double entry system?","options":["Debit the increasing account and credit the decreasing account","Debit the receiving account and credit the giving account","Debit the asset account and credit the liability account","Debit the revenue account and credit the expenditure account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Mallam Gambo bought a freezer for his shop costing N10,500. In recording, he debited office expenses account and credited the bank account. What book-keeping error has he committed?","options":["Error of commission","Error of reversal of entries","Error of principle","Compensating error"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The use of the folio in the ledger is for","options":["referencing purposes","particulars of the transaction","the account titles","only credit items"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The suspense account is used to correct book-keeping error where the","options":["amount involved is quite significant","item involved is not material","item involved is unknown","error does not affect the agreement of the trial balance"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The discount column of a three column cashbook is not balanced off but periodically transferred to the discount account because discounts","options":["are not important in cashbooks","are cash items only","do not form part of double entry","are used for bank reconciliation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"When is a petty cash account debited?","options":["When the fund is established and every time money is spent","When the fund is established and every time it is replenished","When the fund is established and when the size of the float is decreased","Every time money is drawn from the petty cash"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"When preparing a bank reconciliation statement, which of the following is deducted from the balance per bank statement?","options":["Bank charges","Uncleared cheques","Returned cheques","unpresented cheques"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The financial position of an organization at a particular time can be ascertained from the","options":["statement of sources and application of funds","statement of retained earnings","balance sheet","profit and loss account"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Given;<br>\r\nPurchases = N20,000<br>\r\nSales = N40,000<br>\r\nCarriage inwards = N5,000<br>\r\nCarriage outwards = N5,000<br>\r\nOpening stock = N10,000<br>\r\nClosing stock = N5,000<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is the cost of goods sold?","options":["N30,000","N25,000","N20,000","N15,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The net profit or loss for the year is determined in profit and loss account after","options":["deducting purchases from sales","deducting cost of goods sold from sales and adding administrative expenses","adding commissions received to gross profit","eliminating all expenses from gross profit and adding any other income"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"If a bad debt previously written off is subsequently repaid, the amount collected is recorded as an","options":["income in the profit and loss account","income in the balance sheet","additional cash in the profit and loss account","expense in the balance sheet"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Beginning and ending accounts receivable balances were N8,000 and N15,000 respectively. If collections from customers during the period were N36,000, then total sales on account would be","options":["N23,000","N29,000","N36,000","N43,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"From which of the following sources are creditors control account most likely to be posted?","options":["supplier's invoices","cash disbursements journal","subsidiary debtors ledger","purchases journal"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Which of the following categories of labour cost will be classified as direct?","options":["accountant's salary","factory workers' salary","managing director's salary","cashier's salary"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The major difference between the receipt and payment account and the income and expenditure account is that while the former","options":["is kept by the treasurer, the latter is not","deals with all receipts and payments in the year regardless of the time it relates to, the latter is for just that year","is a T-account, the latter is not","is not in the ledger, the latter is"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The net profit from a trading account of a non-profit making organization would be treated as income in the","options":["income and expenditure account","receipt and payment account","balance sheet","statement of affairs"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The major distinguishing element between the final accounts of a partnership and a sole trader is the","options":["drawings account","appropriation account","capital account","creditors account"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Goodwill appears in the books of a business only if it has been","options":["purchased at a certain price","raised in connection with the admission of a new partner","raised to account for the true value of a business on the death of a partner","raised in order to prevent the balance sheet showing that the business is insolvent"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Kayode, Akpan and Kachalla are in partnership. Their respective capital accounts had the following balances: N40,000, N50,000 and N70,000. The partners agree to admit Wamo as a new partner with a one-fifth interest in the partnership capital in exchange for N50,000 cash. Wamo's equity in the resulting partnership is","options":["N32,000","N40,000","N42,000","N50,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Under which of the following conditions is a partnership dissolved?","options":["Change of partnership's head office","admission of a new partner","Purchase of a large quantity  of fixed asset","Retirement of a manager who is not a partner"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"when shares issued are paid for, accounting entry required is","options":["debit bank or cash account and credit share capital and\/or premium account","credit bank or cash account and debit share capital and\/or premium account","debit shares account and credit capital account","credit shares account and debit capital account"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"A limited liability company has an authorized share capital of N50 million split into 100 million shares 80 million share was offered for subscription at 60k per share payable in full on application. These have been fully subscribed and issued <br>\r\nWhat is the nominal value of each share?","options":["N2","N0.80","N0.60","N0.50"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"A limited liability company has an authorized share capital of N50 million split into 100 million shares 80 million share was offered for subscription at 60k per share payable in full on application. These have been fully subscribed and issued <br>\r\nWhat is the issued capital","options":["N40","N48","N50","N80"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The document setting out the regulations regarding shares, meetings and internal organization of a company is known as","options":["memorandum of association","article of association","prospectus","company law"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"An advantage of using accounting ratios is that they","options":["can be easily calculated","facilitate decision making","are stipulated by law","shows error and fraud"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The expenditure on a good or services which is consumed either immediately or within a current accounting period is called","options":["fixed expenditure","capital expenditure","annual expenditure","recurrent expenditure"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The receipt from a special tax levy to pay maturing interest obligation are recorded in","options":["capital fund project","Debt Service Fund","Tax Assessment Fund","Special Revenue Fund"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The cash bass of accounting requires the recognition of revenue only when they are","options":["due","earned","paid","received"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The amount of individual items on a government budget is called","options":["vote","deposit","loan","grant"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"}]